[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50，这是第五周。
This CS50 and this is week five.
回想一下，在第四周的上周，我们引入了一些新的构建基块，
Recall that last week in week four, we introduced a few new building blocks,
即指针和非常详细的讲话
namely pointers and spoke in great detail
关于如何现在可以操纵计算机的内存
about how you can now manipulate a computer's memory
并开始用它做较低层次的事情。
and begin to do things at a lower level with it.
好吧，今天，我们将使用这些基本构建块
Well today, we'll sort of use those basic building blocks
开始在计算机内存中创建称为数据结构的事物。
to start creating things called data structures in the computer's memory.
事实证明，一旦您具备了这种能力
It turns out that once you have this ability
引用计算机内存中的不同位置，
to refer to different locations in the computer's memory,
您可以将自己的自定义形状拼接在一起，
you can stitch together your own custom shapes,
您自己的自定义数据结构，即所谓的数据结构。
your own custom data structures, as they're called.
实际上，我们将通过回滚来开始
And indeed, we'll start doing that by rolling back
在第二周我们第一次看到数据结构的那一刻。
for just a moment to where we first saw a data structure in week two.
所以回想一下第二周，那是我们玩C的第二周，
So recall in week two which was our second week of playing with C,
我们向您介绍了数组的概念。
we introduced you to the notion of an array.
数组只是连续的内存序列
And an array is just a contiguous sequence of memory
您可以在其中背靠背存储一大堆整数，
in which you can store a whole bunch of integers back to back to back,
或整串字符背靠背。
or maybe a whole bunch of chars back to back to back.
这些数组可能已通过图形方式表示。
And those arrays might have been represented pictorially like this.
因此，这将是大小为3的数组。
So this would be an array of size 3.
并假设这确实是一个整数数组。
And suppose that this were an array indeed of integers.
我们里面可能有一，二，三。
We might have one, two, three inside of it.
但是现在就假设-这是我们将开始遇到问题的地方，
But suppose now-- and here's where we'll start to bump up against a problem,
而且今天也解决了一个问题。
but also solve a problem today.
假设您要向该数组添加另一个数字，
Suppose that you want to add another number to this array,
但是您只有预见性才能创建大小为3的数组。
but you've only had the forethought to create an array of size 3.
C语言中的数组存在一个难点，就是它们实际上并不容易调整大小。
The catch with arrays in C is that they're not really easily resizable.
同样，你们都知道您必须预先决定阵列的大小
Again, you all know that you have to decide in advance how big the array is
将。
going to be.
因此，如果您以后改变主意或您的程序
So if you change your mind later or your program's
运行足够长的时间，您需要在其中存储更多值，
running long enough where you need to store more values in it,
你陷入困境。
you're in a bind.
直观上来说，如果您想将数字4插入此数组，
Like intuitively, if you wanted to insert the number 4 into this array,
您最好将其放在数组末尾的此处
you would ideally just plop it right here at the end of the array
并继续您的业务。
and continue about your business.
但是数组带来的问题是那块内存不是-
But the catch with an array is that that chunk of memory is not--
它不存在于真空中。
it doesn't exist in a vacuum.
回想一下，如果我们缩小并查看您计算机的所有内存，
Recall if we zoom out and look at all of your computer's memory,
这个字节，这个字节和其他所有字节
this byte, this byte and a whole bunch of other bytes
可能很好地被其他变量使用
might very well be in use by other variables
或程序的其他方面。
or other aspects of your program.
因此，例如，为了讨论起见，
So for instance for the sake of discussion,
假设所讨论的程序具有一个大小为3的数组，其中包含
suppose that the program in question has one array of size 3 containing
整数1、2、3
the integers 1, 2 3.
然后假设您的同一程序在代码中的某个位置有一个字符串
And then suppose that your same program has a string somewhere in the code
您已经写过并且该字符串正在存储您好，世界。
that you've written and that string is storing hello, world.
恰好在内存中这个数组的旁边，
Well next to this array in memory just by chance,
可能是HELLO逗号空间WORLD反斜杠0。
may very well be an H-E-L-L-O comma space W-O-R-L-D backslash 0.
可以这么说，那里可能有空闲的内存。
And there might be free memory, so to speak.
您可以使用的内存充满了垃圾值，垃圾也不错。
Memory you could use that's filled with garbage values and garbage isn't bad.
这只是意味着您不知道。
It just means that you don't know.
您并不真正在乎什么价值或曾经存在过什么价值。
You don't really care what values are or were there.
因此，可以说有自由空间。
So there is free space, so to speak.
这些奥斯卡都代表了有效的自由空间
Each of these Oscars represents effectively free space
那里有一些垃圾价值。
with some garbage value there.
也许是过去执行过的遗留物。
Remnants, maybe, of some execution past.
但是这里的问题是你没有空间
But the problem here is that you don't have room
将这四个正确放置在您可能想要放置的位置。
to plop this four right where you might want to put it.
那么解决方案是什么呢？
So what's the solution?
如果我们有一个大小为3的数组，其中包含三个整数，
If we have this array of size 3 containing three integers--
1，2 3--但是它被涂在一个角落里，地狱等
1, 2 3-- but it's been painted into a corner whereby H-E-L-L and so forth are
已经就在它旁边，我们不能只把四个放在那里
already immediately next to it, we can't just put the four there without
牺牲H。那真的感觉不像是一个解决方案。
sacrificing the H. And that doesn't really feel like a solution.
那么，关于如何解决这个问题的任何想法？
So any thoughts on how we can solve this problem?
我们完全没有运气吗？
Are we completely out of luck?
在这样的情况下，您可以不只将数字添加到数组中吗？
Can you just not add a number to an array in a situation like this?
还是有可能想到的解决方案？
Or is there a solution perhaps that comes to mind?
即使您以前从未编程过，即使在屏幕上-
Even if you've never programmed before, if on the screen there--
土地的位置。
the lay of the land.
圣地亚哥，你怎么看？
Santiago, what do you think?
听众：我会说也许你可以
AUDIENCE: I would say that maybe you could
复制原始数组中的元素并创建一个新数组，
copy the elements in the original array and create a new array,
但这是一个大一号或一个大一号的元素。
but that's one size bigger or one element bigger.
然后，添加该新元素。
And then, add that new element.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
这真是直觉。
That's really good intuition.
毕竟，屏幕上有所有这些奥斯卡奖
After all, there's all these Oscars on the screen
现在，它再次表示垃圾值。
right now, which again represent garbage values.
或依次释放可用空间。
Or in turn, free space.
所以我可以在这里放1、2、3、4。
So I could put 1, 2, 3, 4 up here.
我可以在这里放1、2、3、4。
I could put 1, 2, 3, 4 over here.
我可以在这里放下1、2、3、4。
I could put 1, 2, 3, 4 down here.
所以我们有一定的灵活性，但圣地亚哥是完全正确的。
So we some flexibility, but Santiago is exactly right.
凭直觉，我们真正需要做的就是只集中精力
Intuitively, all we really need to do is let's focus only
在四个可用位置上。
on four of the available spots.
大小为4的新数组（如果可以），最初
A new array of size four, if you will, which initially
具有这四个垃圾值。
has these four garbage values.
但是没关系。
But that's OK.
正如圣地亚哥也指出的那样，现在就足够了
Because as Santiago also notes, it suffices now
只是复制旧的阵列-
to just copy the old array--
1、2、3--进入新数组。
1, 2, 3-- into the new array.
哎呀，也许我们现在甚至可以释放原始阵列中的内存，
And heck, maybe we can now even free the memory from the original array,
就像我们使用malloc一样。
much like we could if we used malloc.
当然，那只剩下我们一个大小的数组
And that leaves us then, of course, with just an array of size
具有第四个垃圾值的4。
4 with that fourth garbage value.
但是现在，我们确实有足够的空间，例如数字4本身。
But now, we do have room for, like the number 4 itself.
因此，似乎有解决该问题的方法
So it would seem that there is a solution to this problem that doesn't
违反数组的定义。
violate the definition of an array.
同样，数组的唯一定义确实
Again, the only definition of an array really
是内存必须是连续的。
is that the memory must be contiguous.
您不能只将4放入计算机内存中的任何位置。
You can't just plop the 4 anywhere in the computer's memory.
它必须在您现有的内存之后变为
It has to become right after your existing memory
如果整个事情，整个结构，
if this whole thing, this whole structure,
确实仍将是一个数组。
is indeed going to still be an array.
但是我担心这可能会花费我们一些时间。
But I worry that might have cost us a bit of time.
实际上，让我继续在此处打开屏幕
And in fact, let me go ahead and open up on the screen here
片刻之内，欢迎大家提出一个问题。
in just a moment a question that you're all welcome to buzz in for.
插入数组的运行时间是多少？
What would be the running time of inserting into an array?
让我继续在这里透露民意调查问题。
Let me go ahead and reveal the poll question here.
随意转到通常的URL。
Feel free to go to the usual URL.
如果您不介意照常复制和粘贴，请选择Brian。
Which Brian, if you wouldn't mind copying and pasting as usual.
您认为插入数组的运行时间如何？
What do you think the running time is of inserting into an array?
插入数组。
Inserting into an array.
回想过去，我们在搜索方面讨论了数组。
Recall in the past, we talked about arrays in terms of searching.
但是今天，这是我们第一次真正
But today, this is the first time we're really
谈论插入其中。
talking about inserting into them.
如果我们看看结果，您中的80％
And if we take a look at the results coming in, it looks like 80% of you
感觉到它是线性时间，n的大O，因此
feel that it's linear time, big O of n, whereby
可能需要多达n个步骤才能实际插入到数组中。
it might take as many as n steps to actually insert into an array.
5％的人建议n log n。
5% of you propose n log n.
你们的7％，n平方。
7% of you, n squared.
然后，其他值也分别为2％和5％。
And then, 2% and 5% respectively for the other values as well.
所以这是一种有趣的混合，因为当
So this is kind of an interesting mix because when
我们过去讨论过数组，也谈到过搜索，
we talked about arrays in the past and we talked about searching,
回想一下，我们通常获得log n的大O。
recall that we typically achieve big O of log n.
这非常好。
That's really good.
不幸的是如果我们要与圣地亚哥建议
Unfortunately if we have to do with Santiago proposed
并实际上将所有元素从旧数组复制到新数组中，
and actually copy all of the elements from the old array into the new array,
这将花我们多达n步，因为我们有
it's going to take us as many as n steps because we have
复制每个原始元素-
to copy each of the original elements--
1、2、3到新数组中，其大小将为n加1。
1, 2, 3-- over into the new array, which is going to be of size n plus 1.
因此，总共约为n个步骤。
So it's on the order of n steps in total.
因此，插入数组的运行时间
So the running time then of inserting into an array, in terms
至少是一个上限，实际上将是n的大O
of an upper bound at least, is going to be indeed big O of n
因为您可能已经复制了所有这些元素。
because you've got a copy potentially all of those elements over.
但是也许，如果我们考虑降低
But perhaps, we might feel differently if we consider a lower
限制插入的运行时间。
bound on the running time of insert.
当涉及到数组时，insert的下限可能是多少？
What might the lower bound of insert be when it comes to an array?
同样，我们可以在这里使用omega表示法。
Again, omega notation is what we can use here.
在最佳情况下，可能需要执行几个步骤
How many steps maybe in the best case might it
带我将值插入数组吗？
take me to insert a value into an array?
我们不会对此进行民意调查。
We won't do a poll for this one.
布莱恩，为什么我们不继续呼吁这一点。
Brian, why don't we go ahead and call on a hand for this.
插入运行时间的下限是多少？
What's a lower bound on the running time of insert?
瑞安，你怎么看？
Ryan, what do you think?
听众：最好的情况是
AUDIENCE: Well, the best case scenario would
如果数组中只有一个元素。
be if there's only one element in the array.
所以你只有一个，或者只是
So you would just have a one or it would just
是数组中的一个元素。
be one element right into the array.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，如果您有一个阵列，
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so if you've got an array--
我要强调的是，这已经是空的-
and let me emphasize that's already empty--
这样，您就可以为新元素留出空间。
whereby you have room for the new element, then indeed.
只要您需要，欧米茄1恒定的时间就是您所需要的
Omega of 1, constant time, is all you need so long as you
在数组中有可用空间。
have space available in the array.
数组有多大无关紧要。
And it doesn't matter how large the array is.
也许是4号，但您只输入了一个数字。
Maybe it's a size 4, but you've only put one number in it.
可以，因为您可以立即将新号码放到位。
That's OK because you can immediately put the new number in place.
回想一下，数组支持随机访问。
Recall that array support random access.
您可以使用方括号表示法
You can use the square bracket notation and just
仅一步之遥即可在所谓的恒定时间内跳到任意位置。
jump to any location in so-called constant time in just one step.
因此，如果您的阵列足够大且未满，则可以。
So if your array is of sufficient size and it's not full, then yes.
插入数组的下限
The lower bound on the insertion into an array
将是恒定的时间，Ω为1。
is going to be constant time, omega of 1.
但正如我们在圣地亚哥的情况中所见，
But as we saw in Santiago's situation whereby
你有一个已经充满了元素的数组
you have an array that's already filled with elements
并且您想添加另一个，在这种情况下，
and you want to add another, well in that case,
那么上限确实将是n的大O
then upper bound is indeed going to be big O of n
因为您必须做额外的工作来将值复制到
because you have to do the additional labor of copying the values over
从一个到另一个。
from one to the other.
现在，您之前已经编程过，也许您已经使用过Java。
Now those of you have programmed before, maybe you've use Java.
您可能对短语向量很熟悉。
You might be familiar with the phrase vector.
向量就像可以调整大小，可以增长和收缩的数组。
A vector is like an array that can be resized, can grow and shrink.
那不是C中的数组。C中的数组只是连续的内存块
That's not what arrays in C. Arrays in C are just contiguous blocks of memory
值背对背。
with values back to back to back.
但是，一旦您决定了它们的大小，就可以了。
But once you decide on their size, that is it.
您将不得不调整它的大小，本质上是您自己。
You're going to have to resize it, essentially yourself.
他们不会为您自动成长。
They're not going to automatically grow for you.
因此，数组是数据中的第一个，而且实际上是最简单的
So an array was the first and really the simplest of the data
我们将看到的结构。
structures we'll see.
但这还不如什么强大
But it's also not nearly as powerful as what
现在我们可以访问计算机的内存了。
we can do now that we have access to a computers memory.
今天，我们将开始利用这些称为
Today, we're going to start to leverage these things called
指针，即我们可以用来引用内存中位置的地址。
pointers, the addresses via which we can refer to locations in memory.
我们将开始将一些更高级的数据结构结合在一起-
And we're going to start to stitch together some fancier data structures--
首先，在某种意义上是一维的。
first, one dimensional in some sense.
然后，从某种意义上讲是二维的-通过使用一些非常基本的构建块。
Then, two dimensional in some sense-- by using some very basic building blocks.
回顾过去几周的这三段语法。
Recall these three pieces of syntax from the past weeks.
结构，回想是这种机制，C语言中的这个关键字，
Struct, recall, is this mechanism, this keyword in C,
借此我们可以在内存中定义自己的结构。
whereby we can define our own structures in memory.
我们为一个人看到了一个，其中一个人可能既有名字又有数字
We saw one for a person whereby a person might have both a name and a number
在电话簿之类的东西中。
in something like a phone book.
您已经看到了点运算符。
And you've seen the dot operator The dot operator was
我们如何进入这种结构并获得点名称或点编号。
how we go inside of such a structure and get at dot name or dot number.
结构内部的特定变量。
The specific variables inside of the struct.
然后上周，回想一下，我们看到了明星运营商
And then last week, recall we saw the star operator
因此，解引用运算符，通俗地表示
whereby the dereference operator, which colloquially means
转到这个特定的地址。
go to this particular address.
因此，仅通过使用这三种成分就可以
So just by using these three ingredients are
我们现在将能够建立自己的自定义数据结构
we going to be able to now build up our own custom data structures
甚至比阵列更出色，最终可以帮助我们解决问题
that are even fancier than arrays and can ultimately help us solve problems
更有效率。
more efficiently.
实际上，这是C语言编程中的一种常见技术
And in fact, this is such a common technique in programming in C
点和星这两个运算符，
that these two operators, the dot and the star,
通常被组合成一个故意看起来像箭头的箭头。
are often combined into one that intentionally looks like an arrow.
因此，我们将在短时间内看到其用法。
So we'll see its usage in just a little bit.
因此，从语法上讲，今天几乎是构建基块
So syntactically today, it's pretty much building blocks
过去，但我们现在将以新方式使用这些构建基块
past but we're going to use these building blocks now in new ways
开始以不同的方式解决问题。
to start solving problems differently.
首先，我们将通过称为链接列表的方式进行此操作。
And we'll first do this by way of something called linked lists.
因此，例如，一个链表将是一个可以解决以下问题的数据结构：
So for instance, a linked list is going to be a data structure that solves
数组的一些问题。
some of the problems with an array.
那可以说是什么问题呢？
And what's a problem arguably?
好吧，如果将n个步骤中的大O插入到数组中，
Well if it takes big O of n steps to insert into an array,
坦白说，这很烦人。
frankly that's kind of annoying.
那有点贵。
That's kind of expensive.
因为随着时间的流逝，如果您要编写一个包含大量数据的大型程序，
Because over time if you're writing a really big program with lots of data--
您是世界上的Google，世界上的Twitter-很好
you're the Googles of the world, the Twitters of the world-- it's fine
如果您想将所有数据存储在一个大数组中
if you want to store all of your data in a big array
为了有效的搜索。
for the sake of efficient searching.
如果我们使用类似二进制的搜索方式，那回想起来是log n的大O
Which recall, was big O of log n if we use something like binary search
并保持一切排序。
and keep everything sorted.
但是，如果每次您
But it's going to be pretty painful if every time you
想要向该阵列添加另一条推文，或向该阵列添加其他网页。
want to add another tweet to the array, or some other web page to the array.
根据您要解决的问题，
Depending on what the problem is that you're solving,
正如圣地亚哥指出的那样，您可能会
you might potentially-- as Santiago notes--
必须复制原始较小数组的所有内容
have to copy all of the contents of your original smaller array
添加到更大的新数组中，只是添加更多推文或更多网页等。
into a new bigger array just to add more tweets or more web pages or the like.
因此，链表将是一个数据结构，
So a linked list is going to be a data structure that's
更动态，从而您可以扩大和缩小数据
more dynamic, whereby you can grow and shrink the data
结构，而无需触及所有原始数据
structure without having to touch all of the original data
并将其从旧位置移动到新位置。
and move it from old location to new.
那么这看起来像什么呢？
So what might this look like?
好吧，让我们再次考虑一下我们的计算机内存
Well let's consider again our computers memory
并建议我要再次存储这些相同的值。
and let's propose that I want to store those same values again.
就像第一名-只是为了讨论，
So like the number one-- and just for the sake of discussion,
假设它在我计算机的内存中，地址为0x123。
suppose that it's in my computer's memory at address 0x123.
0x只是表示它是一个十六进制数。
0x just means it's a hexadecimal number.
1-2-3-是完全任意的。
1-2-3- is completely arbitrary.
我只是为了讨论而编造的。
I made it up just for the sake of discussion.
所以让我规定那就是数字1发生的地方
So let me stipulate that that's where the number 1 happens
在这个新解决方案中存储在计算机的内存中
to be in the computer's memory in this new solution
存储大量数据的问题。
to the problem of storing lots of data.
假设我要存储2号。
Suppose I want to store number 2.
也许是在地址0x456。
Maybe it's at address 0x456.
然后，假设我要存储数字3。
And then, suppose I want to store number 3.
假设它位于地址0x789。
Suppose it's at address 0x789.
因此，请注意，这些数字分散了
So notice deliberately, these numbers are spread out
在计算机的内存中。
in the computer's memory.
因为毕竟，我们在不久前就遇到了数组问题
Because after all, the problem we ran into a moment ago with arrays
是您可能拥有来自其他部分的问候，世界或其他价值
is that you might have hello, world or other values from other parts
您的程序的方式。
of your program in the way.
所以，如果我提议，如果你想
So if I'm proposing instead that if you want
存储一个，然后两个，然后三个，就可以了。
to store one, and then two, and then three, that's fine.
将它们放到您想要的任何地方，而无需
Plop them anywhere you want and you don't
不得不担心在哪里已经存在价值。
have to worry about where there is already existing values.
相反，您可以将这些值放在有空间的地方。
Instead, you can just put these values where there is room.
但是，问题在于，如果您只是开始处理诸如一，二之类的值，
The problem, though, is that if you just start plopping values like one, two,
您想要在计算机内存中的任意三个位置，
three anywhere you want in the computer's memory,
您不能再轻易地找到这些值了，对吧？
you can no longer very easily find those values, right?
您可能知道一个人在哪里，但是不再
You might know where one is, but it no longer
只需在右侧寻找一个位置即可找到下一个值
suffices to just look one location to the right to find the next value
或加两个，然后找到下一个值。
or add two find the next value after that.
在数组中，所有内容都是连续的。
In an array, everything is contiguous.
但是如果我们改为开始处理计算机的内存
But if we instead start to treat the computer's memory
就像一个画布，我们可以在任何地方绘制数字
as just a canvas where we can just draw numbers anywhere
我们想要，那很好，只要我们能以某种方式
we want, that's fine so long as we can somehow
帮助自己从第一，第二，
help ourselves get from the first, to the second,
到第三，不管其他所有东西是什么
to the third irrespective of all the other stuff that's
弄乱了计算机的内存。
cluttering up the computer's memory.
所以事实上，让我建议我们可以通过窃取来做到这一点
So in fact, let me propose that we do this by maybe stealing
电脑上还有更多空间。
a bit more space from the computer.
因此，与其使用足够的内存来存储一，二和三，
So rather than use just enough memory to store one, two, and three,
让我存储两倍的信息。
let me store twice as much information.
除了我真正关心的每个数字-一，二，三，
In addition to every number that I actually care about-- one, two, three,
我的数据
my data--
我可以存储一些元数据，可以这么说。
let me store a little metadata, so to speak.
我根本不关心的价值观
The values that I don't fundamentally care about,
但这将有助于我跟踪实际数据。
but that are going to help me keep track of my actual data.
让我在这里的方框中提出这个建议，
And let me propose that in this box here,
我从字面上存储值0x456。
I literally store the value 0x456.
同样，它以十六进制编写，但这只是数字。
Again, it's written in hexadecimal, but that's just the number.
那是内存中其他地方的地址。
That's the address of somewhere else in memory.
在此框中，让我建议存储0x789。
In this box, let me propose that I store 0x789.
在此框中，让我任意说0x0，它全都是零位。
And in this box, let me arbitrarily say 0x0, which is just all zero bits.
现在为什么要这样做？
Now why have I done this?
即使您从未见过这种结构，
Even if you've never seen this structure that's
演变成所谓的链表，
evolving to be what's called a linked list,
为什么我刚刚完成了自己的工作？
why have I just done what I've done?
除了分别存储一，二和三之外，
In addition to storing one, two, and three respectively,
我现在还存储0x456和额外的内存块以及0x789
I'm also now storing 0x456 and an additional chunk of memory and 0x789
和一个额外的内存块。
and an additional chunk of memory.
但为什么？
But why?
苏菲亚。
Sofia.
听众：这样我们就知道第一个元素与第二个元素有何关系
AUDIENCE: So that we know how the first element relates to the second
或它们如何链接在一起。
or how they're linked together.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确-
DAVID MALAN: That's exactly--
听众：-在第一和第二之间。
AUDIENCE: --between the first and second.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
所以现在，我使用的空间实际上是每个数据的两倍。
So now, I'm using essentially twice as much space to store each piece of data.
一，二和三。
One, two, and three respectively.
但是在第二块空间中，我现在
But in the second chunk of space, I'm now
在我现在将其视为列表的事物中存储指向下一个元素的指针。
storing a pointer to the next element in the thing I'll now think of as a list.
所以这是0x456，因为第二个
So this is 0x456 because the number two, which
是我关心的列表中的下一个数字，位于0x456。
is the next number in the list I care about, lives at 0x456.
这个数字是0x789，因为我关心的是下一个数字
This number is 0x789 because the next number after that I care about
位于地址0x789。
is at address 0x789.
所以这只是离开的一种有用方法
So it's just a helpful way now of leaving
我自己的面包屑，这样我就可以把一个，两个，三个放在任何地方
myself breadcrumbs so that I can plop the one, the two, the three anywhere
只要有可用空间，我都希望在计算机的内存中
I want in the computer's memory wherever there's available space
并仍然想出如何从一个到达另一个的方法。
and still figure out how to get from one to the other to the other.
实际上，我们之前已经看过其中一些语法。
And we've actually seen some of this syntax before.
事实证明，0x0全为零，这只是技术上的问题-
It turns out that 0x0, which is all zero bits, that's just the technical--
这就是我们称为null的数值等效项。
that's the numeric equivalent of what we've called null.
上周介绍的NULL是一个特殊符号，表示
N-U-L-L, which we introduced last week, is a special symbol indicating that
内存出现问题或空间不足。
something has gone wrong with memory or you're out of space.
有点没有地址。
It's sort of the absence of an address.
C保证如果您使用0x0，AKA为null，
C guarantees that if you use 0x0, AKA null,
那只是表明那里没有任何有用的地址。
that just indicates the absence of any useful address there.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
就像上周一样，这已经进入了杂草丛生。
Again like last week, this is of getting way into the weeds.
我不太在乎0x123456789。
I don't really care about 0x123456789.
因此，让我们将其抽象一下，然后开始真正地考虑一下
So let's just kind of abstract this away and start thinking about this really
作为以某种方式链接在一起的数字的列表。
as a list of numbers that are somehow linked together.
引擎盖下的链接是通过地址实现的，
Underneath the hood, the links are implemented by way of addresses,
或指针，例如0x123456789的那些低级数字。
or pointers, those low level numbers like 0x123456789.
但是从图片上来说，我们只要开始就足够了
But pictorially, it suffices for us to just start
考虑到此数据结构（以下称为链表），
thinking of this data structure, hereafter known as a linked list,
作为节点的集合，可以说-
as being a collection of nodes, so to speak--
NODE-通过指针连接。
N-O-D-E-- that are connected via pointers.
因此，节点只是一门通用的计算机科学
So a node is just a generic computer science
指某种结构的术语
term that refers to some kind of structure
存放您关心的东西。
that store stuff you care about.
我在这里关心的是一个数字和一个指向另一个这样的结构的指针。
What I care about here is a number and a pointer to another such structure.
所以这是一个链表，每个矩形代表一个节点。
So this is a linked list and each of these rectangles represents a node.
在代码中，我们将最终实现这些节点
And in code, we'll implement those nodes ultimately
通过C中的那个东西称为struct。
by way of that thing in C called a struct.
但让我停在这里先看看是否有
But let me pause here to see first if there
对我们建立的结构有任何疑问。
are any questions about the structure we have built up.
有关此问题的任何问题都称为链接列表
Any questions about this thing called a linked list
在某些代码中看到它之前？
before we see it in some code?
布莱恩？
Brian?
布莱恩：是的，聊天中出现了一个问题，
BRIAN: Yeah, a question came in in the chat asking,
这不是浪费内存，我们现在正在使用所有这些单元格
isn't this kind of a waste of memory that we're now using all of these cells
存储地址呢？
to store addresses too?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，非常好的观察。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good observation.
难道这不是在浪费记忆吗？
Isn't this kind of a waste of memory in that we're
另外存储所有这些地址
storing all of these addresses in addition
到我们关心的数字1、2、3？
to the numbers 1, 2, 3 that we care about?
是的，事实上，这正是我们要付出的代价，
Yes, and in fact, that is exactly the price we are paying,
这将是主题。
and this is going to be thematic.
这个星期，上周以及此后的每个星期，
This week, last week and really every week thereafter,
每当我们解决CS和编程方面的问题时，
any time we solve a problem in CS and programming in particular,
总会有一些付出的代价。
there's always going to be some price paid.
会有一些成本，实际上，有
There's going to be some cost and really, there's
会有所取舍。
going to be some trade-off.
因此，如果片刻之前插入到数组中是不可接受的
So if a moment ago, it was unacceptable that inserting into an array
在n的大O中，因为人，这将需要很多步骤来复制所有
is in big O of n because man, that's going to take so many steps to copy all
从旧数组到新数组的值，
of the values from the old array into the new array,
如果由于性能原因您不可接受
if that is unacceptable to you for performance reasons
或您正在解决的问题是什么，都很好。
or whatever the problem is that you're solving, well, that's fine.
您可以解决该问题，现在有了更多的动力
You can solve that problem and now have much more dynamism
借此您可以将数字放入内存中的任何位置
whereby you can plop your numbers anywhere in memory
无需将现有数字移动到其他任何地方，从而节省了
without having to move the existing numbers anywhere else, thereby saving
自己的时间，但是您要付出的代价确实是更多的空间。
yourself time, but the price you're going to pay indeed is more space.
所以在那一点上，这取决于什么
So at that point, it kind of depends what's
对您而言更重要的是计算机的时间，
more important to you, the computer's time,
您的人的时间，或者空间或空间成本，更多的内存
your human time, or maybe the space or the cost of the space, the more memory
您可能真的需要为该计算机购买。
that you might really need to literally buy for that computer.
所以这将是主题。
So this is going to be thematic.
实际上，在编程中，时空之间的这种折衷是无所不在的。
This trade-off between space and time is omnipresent, really, in programming.
好吧，让我们考虑如何将其立即转换为实际代码。
Well, let's consider how we might translate this now into actual code.
回想一下，当我们上次在C中看到结构时，
Recall that when we last saw structs in C,
我们做了这样的事情来定义一个人有两个相关联的东西
we did something like this to define a person as having two things associated
和他们一起，一个名字和一个数字。
with them, a name and a number.
所以今天，我们不在乎人，名字和数字。
So today, we don't care about persons and names and numbers.
我们关心这些事情，我们将开始调用节点，
We care about these things we're going to start calling nodes,
所以让我继续前进。
so let me go ahead and rewind from that.
擦除它，让我们说这个结构中的每个节点，
Erase that and let's instead say that every node in this structure,
也将人重命名为节点
renaming person as well to node, is going
有一个数字，在我们这里是整数
to have a number, which will be an int in our case here,
我为其他价值留出了空间，因为我们最终
and I've left room for one other value because we ultimately
需要能够存储第二条数据。
need to be able to store that second piece of data.
第二部分数据将是一个指针。
That second piece of data is going to be a pointer.
这将是某物的地址，但是怎么可能
It's going to be an address of something, but how might
我表达这个吗？
I express this?
这将不太明显
This is going to be a little less obvious
但是我们上周为指针打下了基础。
but we laid the foundation last week with pointers.
我怎么能形容这种结构
How could I describe this structure as having
指向另一个这样的结构的指针？
a pointer to another such structure?
关于所使用语法的口头思考，
Any thoughts on verbally the syntax to use,
甚至即使您不确定确切的咒语，确切的符号
or even if you're not sure of exactly the incantation, exactly what symbols
我们应该用来表达和寻址到另一个这样的节点吗？
we should use to express and address to another such node?
布莱恩：有人建议我们使用节点*作为指向节点的指针。
BRIAN: Someone is suggesting we use a node * as a pointer to a node.
DAVID MALAN：节点*？
DAVID MALAN: Node *?
好的。
All right.
所以*我绝对记得上周
So * I definitely remember from last week,
表示如果您有int *，则为int的地址。
indicating that if you have int *, this is the address of an int.
如果您有char *，则这是char的地址。
If you have char *, this is the address of a char.
因此，如果所有这些箭头确实只是代表节点的地址，
So if all of these arrows really just represent addresses of nodes,
有理由认为语法可能是
it stands to reason that syntax is probably
将类似于节点*。
going to be something akin to node *.
现在，我可以将其命名为任何所需的指针。
Now I can call this pointer anything I want.
按照惯例，我将其称为“下一步”。
By convention, I'll call it next.
因为从字面上看，它的人生目的是
Because literally, its purpose in life is
指向数据结构中的下一个节点。
to point to the next node in the data structure.
这将是我将建议的int被叫号码的补充
And that's going to be in addition to the int called number that I'll propose
描述了该单个数据结构的顶部。
describes the top of that individual data structure.
但是，C语言中存在一个细微的问题。
But there's a subtle problem here in C. Recall
在C语言中，这是一种简单的语言，
that in C, it's kind of a simplistic language, complicated
尽管它似乎经常出现，但它什么都不懂
though it might often seem, in that it doesn't understand anything
它从未见过。
that it hasn't seen before.
因此，目前，请注意
So at the moment, notice that the very first time
到目前为止，我已经提到过节点
I have mentioned node up until now was on the very
此代码段的最后一行。
last line of this snippet of code.
问题在于，本质上是typedef的工作方式，
The problem is that by nature of how typedef works,
所谓的节点实际上并没有
the thing called a node does not actually
一直存在，直到编译器完成读取最后一行代码为止
exist until the compiler is done reading that last line of code
和分号，也就是说，实际上
and the semicolon, which is to say that it would actually
使用或引用不正确，请取消引用
be incorrect to use or refer to quote, unquote
该结构内部的“节点”。
"node" inside of this structure.
因为从字面上看，根据typedef的工作原理的定义，
Because literally, by definition of how typedef works,
直到最后一行代码和分号为止，节点才存在
a node does not exist until, again, that last line of code and the semicolon
被执行。
are executed.
值得庆幸的是，有一种解决方法。
Thankfully, there's a workaround.
看起来有点奇怪。
It's a little weird to look at.
但是您可以在C语言中执行此操作。
But what you can do in C is this.
实际上，您实际上可以在关键字struct之后添加一个附加词。
You can actually add an additional word after, literally, the keyword struct.
我们将使其保持简单。
And we'll keep it simple.
我们将使用完全相同的词，尽管从技术上讲这不是必需的。
We'll use the exact same word, though technically that's not necessary.
现在，我将更改结构的内部以替代此说法。
And now, I'm going to change the inside of the structure to say this instead.
因此感觉有些冗长。
So it feels a little verbose.
而且感觉有点复制粘贴。
And it feels a little bit of copy paste.
但这是在C中完成的方式。Typedef结构节点本质上是
But this is the way it is done in C. Typedef struct node is essentially
暗示，与原型在精神上相似
a hint, similar in spirit to the prototypes
我们已经讨论过有关为编译器提供线索的函数，
we've talked about for functions that gives the compiler a clue that,
好了，一个叫做struct节点的东西将会存在。
OK, something called a struct node is going to exist.
然后，您可以在该数据结构中使用它
You can then use it inside of that data structure
并将其称为struct node *。
and refer to it as struct node *.
这周比较令人满口。
It's more of a mouthful this week.
我们还没有看到像这样的多个单词。
We've not seen multiple words like this.
但这类似于char *或int *，就像上周一样。
But it's similar to char * or int *, like last week.
接下来，我将随意拨打该电话。
And I'm going to call that arbitrarily next.
在这里，与过去的人一样，发生了同样的事情。
And down here, the same thing happens as in the past with persons.
通过在代码的最后一行调用此节点，可以
By calling this node at the very last line of the code, that
只是告诉编译器，您知道吗？
just tells the compiler, you know what?
您不必在各处都将其称为struct节点。
You don't have to refer to it as struct node all over the place.
您可以仅将此事物节点称为。
You can just call this thing node.
因此，在这种情况下，它有点冗长。
So it's a little verbose in this case.
但是，所有这些工作都是在计算机中为我创建的，
But all this is done is create for me, in the computer,
我们以图片形式描绘的节点定义
the definition of a node as we have depicted it pictorially
那个矩形。
with that rectangle.
好吧，现在我们如何将其转换为更有用的代码，而不是
All right, so how can we now translate this into more useful code, not
只是定义这些结构是什么，但是如何
just defining what these structures are, but how
我们如何开始建立链表？
do we begin building up linked lists?
好吧，让我建议一个链接列表实际上仅从一个指针开始。
Well, let me propose that a linked list really begins with just a pointer.
实际上，这里有了剧院的道具店，
And in fact, here we have, thanks to the theatre's prop shop,
如果可以的话，只是一个空指针。
just kind of a null pointer, if you will.
我将这个变量称为“列表”。
I'm going to call this variable "list."
和列表目前什么都没有指向。
And list is currently pointing to nothing.
我们将要说的箭头只是指向地板，这意味着它为空。
The arrow, we'll say, is just pointing at the floor, which means it's null.
它实际上并没有指向任何有用的东西。
It's not actually pointing at anything useful.
假设我现在想开始分配链接
Suppose I now want to start to begin to allocate a linked
列出三个数字1、2和3。
list with three numbers, 1, 2, and 3.
好吧，我该怎么做？
Well, how am I going to do this?
好吧，目前，我的程序中存在的唯一内容
Well, at the moment, the only thing that exists in my program
将被称为list的变量。
is going to be this variable called list.
这个故事没有任何意义。
There's no array in this story.
那是在第二周。
That was in Week 2.
今天是关于链表的全部。
Today is all about linked lists.
那么我如何让自己成为一个木块，
So how do I get myself a wooden block that
代表1，另一个代表2的木块
represents 1, another wooden block that represents 2,
第三个代表3？
and a third that represents 3?
好吧，我们需要使用上周的新朋友malloc。
Well, we need to use our new friend from last week, malloc.
回想一下malloc允许您分配内存，
Recall that malloc allows you to allocate memory,
只要您告诉它就可以拥有尽可能多的内存
as much memory as you might want, so long as you tell it
那东西的大小。
the size of that thing.
坦率地说，我认为我们今天最终能做些什么
So frankly, I think what we could do ultimately today
使用malloc动态分配一个结构并将数字1放入其中，
is use malloc to allocate dynamically one struct and put the number 1 in it,
另一个结构将数字2放在上面，另一个结构将数字3放在上面。
another struct put the number 2 on it, another struct put the number 3 in it.
然后，使用此处的这些俏皮箭头将它们实际缝合在一起，
And then, use these playful arrows here to actually stitch them together,
指向另一点。
having one point to the other.
因此，值得庆幸的是，道具商店
So thankfully, the prop shop has wonderfully
为我们创造了一大堆这些。
created a whole bunch of these for us.
让我继续，并分配一个非常重的节点，该节点可以容纳两个值。
Let me go ahead and malloc a very heavy node that has room for two values.
而且您会看到它有空间容纳数字和下一个指针。
And you'll see it has room for a number and a next pointer.
所以我要首先在这里安装的号码
So the number I'm going to first install here
例如，将是数字1。
is going to be the number 1, for instance.
我将其指针指向地面，
And I'm going to leave its pointer as just pointing at the ground,
指示这是一个空指针。
indicating that this is a null pointer.
它实际上并没有指向其他任何东西。
It's not actually pointing at anything else.
但是现在我开始实例化，
But now that I'm starting to instantiate,
那就是创建这个列表，现在我要做这样的事情
that is create this list, now I'm going to do something like this
并说，好的，我的变量称为“列表”，其生命目的
and say that, all right, my variable called "list," whose purpose in life
是为了跟踪此列表在内存中的位置，
is to keep track of where this list is in memory,
我将通过实际将彼此连接起来
I'm going to connect one to the other by actually having
此变量指向此节点。
this variable point at this node.
然后，要分配另一个节点，
When it comes time, then, to allocate another node,
我想插入此链接列表。
I want to insert into this linked list.
回到数组世界，我可能不得不分配一个新的内存块，
Back in the world of arrays, I might have to allocate a new chunk of memory,
将此值复制到新值中。
copy this value over into the new values.
我不必那样做。
I don't have to do that.
在链接列表的世界中，我第二次调用malloc
In the world of linked lists, I just call malloc for a second time
再说一遍，再给我一块足够大的内存，足以容纳一个节点。
and say, give me another chunk of memory big enough to fit a node.
值得庆幸的是，在道具商店里，我们还有另一个。
Thankfully, from the prop shop, we have another one of these.
我继续在这里分配另一个节点。
Let me go ahead and malloc another node here.
目前，其中没有任何内容。
At the moment, there's nothing in it.
它只是占位符。
It's just the placeholder.
因此，如果可以的话，这是垃圾值。
So it's garbage values, if you will.
我不知道那里到底有什么
I don't know what's there until I actually
说数字应该是2。
say that the number shall be number 2.
然后转到链接列表，其变量名称为“列表”，
And then I go over to my linked list whose variable name is "list,"
我想插入这个东西。
and I want to insert this thing.
所以我跟随箭头。
So I follow the arrow.
然后，我将此节点的下一个字段指向此节点。
I then point the next field of this node at this node here.
所以现在我有了一个尺寸为2的链表。
So now I have a linked list of size 2.
图片中有三件事，但这只是一个简单的变量。
There's three things in the picture, but this is just a simple variable.
这是一个指向实际节点的指针，该节点依次是
This is a pointer that's pointing at the actual node which, in turn, is
指向实际的另一个节点。
pointing at an actual other node.
现在，假设我要将数字3插入此链表中。
Now suppose I want to insert the number 3 into this linked list.
回想一下malloc是强大的，并且它
Recall that malloc is powerful and that it
从可用的地方获取内存，
takes memory from wherever it's available,
您计算机上的所谓“堆”。
the so-called "heap" from your computer.
根据定义，这意味着它可能不是连续的。
And that means, by definition, that it might not be contiguous.
下一个数字可能实际上不是隐喻在这里
The next number might not actually be here metaphorically
在计算机的内存中。
in the computer's memory.
可能在那边。
It might be way over there.
因此，这确实有可能发生。
So that might indeed happen.
现在第三次调用malloc并分配第三个节点，
The third time I call malloc now and allocate a third node,
它可能在计算机内存中的任何地方都不可用，除了，
it might not be available anywhere in the computer's memory except for,
就像，在这边。
like, way over here.
很好。
And that's fine.
它不必像在数组世界中那样是连续的。
It doesn't have to be contiguous as it did in the world of our arrays.
我现在可以将数字3放在它的位置。
I can now put the number 3 in its place.
但是，如果我想保留指向该节点的指针，以便所有这些事情
But if I want to keep a pointer to that node, so that all of these things
缝合在一起，我可以从头开始。
are stitched together, I can start at the beginning.
我跟随箭头。
I follow the arrows.
现在，如果我想记住那个地方，
And now, if I want to remember where that one is,
我将不得不连接这些东西。
I'm going to have to connect these things.
因此，现在，该指针需要指向此处的该块。
And so now, that pointer needs to point at this block here.
而且这种视觉效果是有意为之的。
And this visual is very much deliberate.
这些节点可以在计算机内存中的任何位置。
These nodes can be anywhere in the computer's memory.
它们不一定是连续的。
They're not necessarily going to be contiguous.
缺点是您不能依赖二进制搜索，
The downside of that is that you cannot rely on binary search,
我们从第0周开始的朋友。
our friend from Week 0 onward.
二进制搜索是惊人的，因为它是log n的BigO。
Binary search was amazing in that it's Big O of log n.
您可以比n的Big O更快地找到东西。
You can find stuff way faster than Big O of n.
这就是电话簿的重点
That was the whole point of even the phonebook
在第一周的例子。
example in the very first week.
但是这种方法的好处是
But the upside of this approach is that you
不必实际继续分配和复制更多的内存
don't have to actually keep allocating and copying more memory
并在需要调整大小时随时使用所有值。
and all of your values any time you want to resize this thing.
我有些尴尬地承认我出于某种原因而气喘吁吁，
And I'm a little embarrassed to admit that I'm out of breath for some reason,
只是在这里分配节点。
just mallocing nodes here.
但是重点是使用malloc并进行构建
But the point is using malloc and building out
结构确实要付出一些代价。
the structure does come at some price.
坦白说，这太累了。
It's exhausting, frankly.
但这也将在内存中扩展内容。
But it's also going to spread things out in memory.
但是你有这种活力。
But you have this dynamism.
老实说，如果您是全世界的推特，那么Google
And honestly, if you are the Twitters of the world, the Googles
在世界上，那里有很多数据，
of the world, where you have lots and lots of data,
必须复制所有数据，这会扼杀您的性能
it's going to kill you performance wise to have to copy all of your data
从一个地方到另一个地方，就像圣地亚哥一样
from one location into another as Santiago originally
建议作为阵列的解决方案。
proposed as a solution to the array.
因此，使用这些动态数据结构（例如链表）时，
So using these dynamic data structures, like a linked list, where
您在可用的地方分配更多的空间，
you allocate more space wherever it's available,
而且您以某种方式还记得缝合的位置[？团队？]东西
and you somehow remember where that is by stitching [? team ?] things
就像这些物理指针一样
together, as with these physical pointers,
确实是您最新的技术水平
is really the state of the art in how you
如果对您来说更重要，则可以创建这些更动态的结构
can create these more dynamic structures if it's more important to you
具有那种活力。
to have that dynamism.
好吧，我们现在翻译这些物理块之前的任何问题
All right, any questions before we now translate these physical blocks
一些代码示例？
to some samples of code?
布莱恩：聊天中出现了一个问题。
BRIAN: A question came in in the chat.
在链接列表的整个过程中，什么时候我们实际上在使用malloc？
When in this whole process of linked lists are we actually using malloc?
而malloc的作用是什么？
And what is malloc being used for?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
那么我们在哪里使用malloc？
So where are we using malloc?
每次我走下舞台，抓住一个
Every time I went off stage and grabbed one
在这些大块中，这是我执行分配节点的过程。
of these big blocks, that was my acting out the process of mallocing a node.
因此，当您调用malloc时，它将返回给您，
So when you call malloc, that returns to you,
每上周，这是一块内存的第一个字节的地址。
per last week, the address of the first byte of a chunk of memory.
而且，如果您调用malloc的1，则将为您提供1个字节的地址。
And if you call malloc of one, that gives you the address of one byte.
如果您将malloc调用为100，则将为您提供第一个地址
If you call malloc of 100, that gives you the first address
100个连续字节。
of 100 bytes that are contiguous.
因此，这些节点中的每一个都代表返回值，如果您愿意的话，
So each of these nodes, then, represents the return value, if you will,
对malloc的单个调用。
of a single call to malloc.
实际上，也许布莱恩是最好的方法
And in fact, perhaps, Brian, the best way
要更详细地回答该问题，请立即翻译
to answer that question in more detail is to translate this now
一些实际的代码。
to some actual code.
因此，让我们不时进行此操作，然后再进行访问。
So let's do that now and then revisit.
例如，这是一行代码，
So here is, for instance, a line of code that
代表我们故事的开始，我们只
represents the beginning of our story, where we only
有一个名为“列表”的变量，该变量最初初始化为空。
had a variable called "list" that was initialized to nothing initially.
这个箭头没有指向任何东西。
This arrow was not pointing at anything.
实际上，如果它只是指向上，下，左
And in fact, if it was just pointing up, down, left,
或正确，它将被视为垃圾值。
or right, it would be considered a garbage value.
这只是内存，这意味着其中包含值
This is just memory, which means there are values inside of it
在我实际输入实际值之前。
before I actually put actual values in it.
所以，如果我不给它赋值，谁知道它指向的是什么？
So if I don't assign it a value, who knows what it's pointing to?
但是，让我继续更改代码。
But let me go ahead and change the code.
默认情况下，此列表变量具有一些垃圾值，除非我对其进行初始化
This list variable, by default, has some garbage value unless I initialize it
到null之类的东西
to something like null.
因此，我仅通过指向地面来形象地表示这一点。
So I'll represent that here figuratively by just pointing at the ground.
现在表示为空。
That now represents null.
这将是相应的代码行
This would be the corresponding line of code that just
为您创建一个空的链表。
creates for you an empty linked list.
那是故事的开始。
That was the beginning of the story.
现在回想一下，我接下来要做的就是离开舞台
Now recall that the next thing I did was I went off stage
我打电话给malloc来带回这些大箱子之一。
and I called malloc to bring back one of these big boxes.
该代码可能看起来像这样。
That code might instead look like this.
节点* n。
Node *n.
因此，我可以将变量命名为malloc，节点大小。
So I could call the variable anything I want, malloc, size of node.
因此，我们的规模可能已经简短地看到了
So size of we might have seen briefly in that it's just
C语言中的运算符，它告诉您任何数据类型的字节数为多少。
an operator in C that tells you how many bytes large any data type is.
所以我可以进行数学计算，然后在Mac或PC或CS50 IDE中弄清楚
So I could do the math and figure out in my Mac or PC or CS50 IDE just how
这些节点应该占用很多字节。
many bytes these nodes are supposed to take up.
大小只是为我回答了这个问题。
Size of just answers that question for me.
因此，malloc再次接受一个参数，即数字
So malloc, again, takes one argument, the number
您要动态分配的字节数，
of bytes you want to allocate dynamically,
然后返回到这些字节中第一个字节的地址。
and it returns to the address of the first of those bytes.
因此，如果您将其视为我以前的黄色幻灯片之一，
So if you think of this as one of my earlier slides in yellow,
它返回给您，例如顶部的地址
it returns to you, like, the address of the top
如果可以的话，此内存块的左字节。
left byte of this chunk of memory, if you will.
我将继续将其分配给变量
And I'm going to go ahead and assign that to a variable
我将调用n表示一个节点。
I'll call n to represent a node.
以及它的节点*，因为malloc同样总是返回一个地址。
And its node * because, again, malloc returns always an address.
以及上周我们看到的用于存储地址的语法
And the syntax we saw last week for storing addresses
是在这里使用这种新的*语法。
is to use this new * syntax here.
因此，这给了我一个最初只有垃圾值的块。
So this gave me a block that initially just had garbage values.
因此没有适当的数字，谁知道箭头所指的位置？
So there was no number in place and who knows where the arrow was pointing at?
因此，如果我现在将其绘制在屏幕上，它看起来像这样。
So it looked a little something like this, if I draw it now on the screen.
列表初始化为空。
List is initialized to null.
现在没有指向任何东西。
It's not pointing at anything right now.
但是我刚刚声明的变量n指向一个节点。
But n, the variable I just declared, is pointing at a node.
但是在那个节点内部，还是谁知道呢？
But inside of that node, or who knows what?
这是垃圾值。
It's garbage values.
Number和next只是垃圾值。
Number and next are just garbage values.
因为默认情况下就是过去的残局。
Because that's what's there by default, remnants of the past.
但是现在，让我建议我们执行此代码。
But now, let me propose that we do this code.
只要n不为空，
So long as n is not null--
这是您现在想要养成的习惯，总是检查一下，
which is something you want to get into the habit always now of checking,
在C中的任何时候，当您调用返回给您指针的函数时，
any time in C, when you call a function that returns to you a pointer,
您几乎应该始终检查它是否为null。
you should almost always check is it null or is it not null.
因为如果它确实为null，则不希望尝试对其进行触摸。
Because you do not want to try touching it if it is indeed null.
因为这意味着这里没有有效的地址。
Because that means there is no valid address here.
这是使用指针时的惯例。
That's the human convention when using pointers.
但是，如果n不等于null，那是一件好事。
But if n does not equal null, that's a good thing.
这意味着它是计算机内存中某个地方的有效地址。
That means it's a valid address somewhere in the computer's memory.
现在让我继续前往该地址，其语法为* n，
Let me go ahead now and go to that address, the syntax for which is *n,
就像上周一样。
just like last week.
然后，运算符意味着进入那里的结构内部
And then the operator means go inside of the structure that's there
然后进入其中的变量（在这种情况下称为数字）。
and go into the variable inside of it, called number in this case.
所以当我继续做这样的事情时，
So when I go ahead and do something like this,
当我有一个最初大小为1的列表时
when I have a list that's initially of size 1,
该变量指向当前唯一的一个节点，
where this variable is pointing at the one and only node at the moment,
一旦执行此行代码，它将立即将数字1包含在其中。
it's going to have the number 1 in it as soon as I execute this line of code.
* n表示从此处包含的地址开始，转到该地址，
*n means start at the address embodied here, go to it,
然后将数字（在这种情况下为1）放置到位。
and then put the number, 1 in this case, in place.
但是我也需要做另一件事。
But I need to do one other thing as well.
我也想去替换垃圾
I want to go ahead, too, and replace the garbage
表示该结构中下一个指针的值
value that represents the next pointer in that structure
并将其替换为null。
and replace it with null.
空[音频不清晰]发现这是列表的末尾。
Null [INAUDIBLE] find that this is the end of the list.
那里什么都没有。
There's nothing there.
我不希望它成为垃圾值。
I don't want it to be garbage value.
因为垃圾值是任意数字
Because a garbage value is an arbitrary number
这可能是这种方式，这种方式的指向。
that could be pointing this way, this way, this way.
隐喻地，我想实际上将其更改为null
Metaphorically, I want to actually change that to be null
所以我可以使用相同的语法
and so I can use the same syntax.
但是现在有一种聪明的方法。
But there's this clever approach now.
如前所述，我不必先用星号然后在该位置上点一下。
I don't have to use star and then dot over the place, as mentioned earlier.
星点带有一些语法糖。
Star and dot comes with some syntactic sugar.
您可以替换星号，括号和点
You can replace the star and the parentheses and the dot
我们刚刚看到的箭头符号表示跟随箭头。
that we just saw with an arrow notation, which means follow the arrow.
然后将其设置为null，即
And then set this thing equal to null, which
我将再次用箭头逐字地表示
I'll represent again by just having the arrow literally points
为了清楚起见，在地板上。
at the floor for clarity.
因此，再次从我们开始的地方倒带* n.number，
So, again, rewinding from where we started, *n.number,
括号中的第一个是与此相同的东西。
with the first of those in parentheses, is the same thing as this.
可以这么说，也是大多数人更喜欢使用箭头符号的原因，
And the reason that most people prefer using the arrow notation, so to speak,
是它确实捕获了这种物理状态。
is that it really does capture this physicality.
您从地址开始，然后去那里，然后
You start at the address, you go there, and then
您分别查看字段，数字或下一个。
you look at the field, number or next, respectively.
但这等同于我们刚才看到的开头和句点的语法
But it's equivalent to the syntax we saw a moment ago with the start and the dot
像之前一样。
as before.
这两个步骤之后，我们是否已初始化
So after these two steps, have we initialized
此节点包含数字1，内部包含null。
this node to containing the number 1 and null inside of it.
但是接下来呢？
But what comes next?
接下来是什么？
What comes next?
好吧，在故事中，在这段代码中，
Well, at point in the story, in this code,
我这里还有其他未显示的变量。
I have some other variable here that's not pictured.
因为我们现在正在从木工世界过渡到实际代码。
Because we're now transitioning from the world of woodwork to actual code.
因此，还有另一个变量n，我也可以代表我自己。
So there's another variable n, which I might as well be representing myself.
如果我是这个临时变量n，我也将指向该值。
If I am this temporary variable n, I, too, am pointing at this value.
直到我实际执行这一行代码list = n ;，
It's not until I actually execute this line of code, list = n;,
我记得该节点在计算机内存中的位置。
that I remember where this node is in the computer's memory.
因此，到目前为止，n确实只是一个临时变量。
So n, up until now, has really just been a temporary variable.
这是我可以用来实际保留的变量
It's a variable that I can use to actually keep
在内存中跟踪此事物。
track of this thing in memory.
但是，如果我想将此节点最终添加到我的链表中，
But if I want to add this node ultimately to my linked list,
列表以null开头，请记住该指针指向
list started out as null, recall that this pointer was pointing
在地面上，表示null。
at the ground, representing null.
但是，当我现在想记住此链表中有一个节点时，
But when I now want to remember that this linked list has a node in it,
我实际上需要执行这样的代码，list = null。
I need to actually execute a line of code like this, list = null.
好吧，我们接下来要做什么？
All right, what did we next do?
让我们再迈出一步。
Let's take one more step further.
所以在故事的这一点上，如果我代表n，
So at this point in the story, if I was representing n,
我也指着同一街区。 n是临时的，
I'm also pointing at the same block. n is temporary,
因此它最终可以消失。
so it can eventually go away.
但是在故事的这一点上，我们有一个大小为1的链表。
But at this point in the story, we have a linked list of size 1.
让我们继续前进。
Let's go ahead and take this further.
假设现在执行这些代码行。
Suppose now I execute these lines of code.
而且我们会更快一点，一次全部完成
And we'll do it a little faster and all at once so
您可以在上下文中看到更多。
that you can see it more in context.
代码的第一行与以前相同。
The first line of code is the same as before.
嘿，malloc，给我一块内存
Hey, malloc, give me a chunk of memory that's
大到足以容纳一个节点的大小。
big enough for the size of a node.
再次，让我们使用这个临时变量n指向该变量。
And, again, let's use this temporary variable n to point to that.
假设这意味着如果我代表这个临时变量，
And suppose that means that I, if I'm representing this temporary variable,
我在这里指向这个新的内存块。
I'm pointing at this new chunk of memory here.
然后我检查，如果n不等于null，那么
I then check, if n does not equal null, then
只有这样我才能继续安装
and only then do I go ahead and install the number
2就像我之前所做的一样，并且我最初初始化了指针
2 as I did physically earlier and do I initialize the pointer originally
指向不是指向尚不存在的其他节点，而是指向
to pointing not at some other node which doesn't yet exist, but pointing at,
让我们将其称为地板，从而代表null。
let's just call it the floor, thereby representing null.
就是这样。
And that's it.
现在已经分配了第二个节点。
That has now allocated the second node.
但是请注意，从字面上看，这是断开的。
But notice, literally, this disconnect.
只是因为我分配了一个新节点并放入
Just because I've allocated a new node and put
我关心的数字，并将其下一个指针初始化为null，
the number I care about and initialized its next pointer to null,
这并不意味着它是数据结构的一部分。
that doesn't mean it's part of the data structure.
链表仍然缺少从旧到新的指针。
The linked list is still missing a pointer from old to new.
所以我们需要执行另一行代码
So we need to execute one other line of code
现在，以便我们可以最终从这张图片到最后一张。
now so that we can get from this picture ultimately to the final one.
在这里，我们可以使用与以前相同的语法。
And here's where we can use the same kind of syntax as before.
如果我从列表变量开始，则按照该代码跟随箭头。
If I start at my list variable, I follow the arrow as per that code.
然后我更新下一个字段以指向
And then I update the next field to point
到n，这是我新分配的节点。
to n, which is my newly allocated node.
现在，在最后一行代码之后，我是否有一个大小为2的链表。
Now, after that final line of code, do I have a linked list of size 2.
因为我不仅分配了节点，还初始化了它的两个
Because I've not only allocated the node, initialized its two
变量，分别是数字和下一个，
variables, a number and next respectively,
我还将其与链表上的现有节点链接在一起。
I've also chained it together with the existing node on the linked list.
让我更快速地执行此操作，
And let me do this one even slightly more quickly,
只是因为这是同一件事，所以我们才能一次看到所有内容。
only because it's the same thing, just so we can see it all together at once.
现在我们有了这张图片，让我们再次执行相同类型的代码。
Now that we have this picture, let's execute the same kind of code again.
此代码块中的唯一区别
The only difference in this chunk of code
我正在将数字初始化为3。
is that I'm initializing number to 3.
那么这对我做了什么呢？
So what has this done for me?
那段代码已经分配了第三个也是最后一个节点。
That chunk of code has malloced a third and final node.
我已经将顶部初始化为数字3。
I've initialized the top to the number 3.
我将底部初始化为null，因为
I've initialized the bottom to null, as I'll
只需将箭头指向地面即可表示。
represent by just pointing the arrow at the ground.
然后，有最后一步。
There's one final step, then.
如果我要继续并将该第三个节点插入此链接列表，
If I want to go ahead and insert that third node into this linked list,
我现在必须继续前进，而不仅仅是指着自己，
I've got to go ahead now and not just point it at myself,
我再次代表临时变量n，我现在需要这样做。
me representing, again, the temporary variable n, I need to now do this.
这是您不会经常使用的语法。
And this is syntax you won't do often.
我们将在稍后的实际程序中看到它。
We'll see it in an actual program in just a moment.
但这仅说明了我们正在处理的基本构建块。
But it just speaks to the basic building blocks we're manipulating.
如果我要继续并将2链接到3，我可以从列表开始。
If I want to go ahead and link the 2 to the 3, I can start here at list.
我可以跟随箭头一次。
I can follow the arrow once.
我可以再次跟随箭头。
I can follow the arrow again.
然后我可以将下一个字段设置为n。
And then I can set that next field equal to n.
同样，因为n是该最近分配的节点的当前地址。
Because, again, n is the current address of that most recently allocated node.
因此，即使语法有了一些新变化，我使用的两个箭头
So even though the syntax is getting a little new, the two arrows I'm using
从字面上看就像是Just的代码体现
are literally just like a code manifestation of just
跟随指针，跟随指针，动臂，为下一个分配一个值。
follow the pointer, follow the pointer, boom, assign one value to the next.
好吧，所以在故事的这一点上，图片现在看起来像这样。
All right, so at this point in the story, the picture now looks like this.
只要我，n，仍然在图片中。
So long as I, n, am still in the picture.
但是如果我摆脱自己，因为我
But if I just get rid of myself, because I'm
临时变量，瞧，我们刚刚逐步建立起来，
a temporary variable, voila, we've just built up, step by step,
大小为3的全新链接列表。
a brand new linked list of size 3.
似乎需要做很多工作，但是它使我们现在可以动态地发展这个东西。
Seems like a lot of work, but it allows us to now grow this thing dynamically.
但是，让我在这里暂停。
But let me pause here.
对链表有任何疑问或困惑吗？
Any questions or confusion on linked lists?
链表上有任何疑问或困惑吗？
Any questions or confusions on linked lists?
布莱恩：聊天中出现了一个问题。
BRIAN: One question just came in the chat.
如果我们试图列出更长的列表，例如，
If we're trying to make a list that's going to be much longer, like,
超过三个元素，难道就没有泰迪乌斯了吗？
more than three elements, wouldn't it get tedius to have,
像，下一个箭头，一遍又一遍的箭头？
like, arrow next, arrow next over and over again?
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
真的很好观察。
Really good observation.
因此，这就是我说的原因，您通常不会这样写。
And so that's why I said, you won't usually write it like this.
稍后，我们将在功能完善的程序中暂时进行此操作
We'll do it temporarily in a full-fledged program in just a moment
只是为了演示它。
just to demonstrate it.
但通常，您可能会使用类似循环的内容。
But in general, you'll probably use something like a loop.
而您要做的就是使用一个指向该变量的临时变量，
And what you'll do is use a temporary variable that points at this one,
然后再次迭代，然后再次迭代。
then iterates again, then iterates again.
现在让我规定，如果您以正确的方式使用循环，
And let me stipulate for now that if you use a loop in the right way,
最终只用一个箭头就可以写出
you can end up writing just a single arrow by just
不断更新变量。
keep updating the variable again and again.
因此，有一种方法可以避免这种情况。
So there is a way to avoid that.
您可以更加动态地进行操作。
And you do it much more dynamically.
那么，让我继续前进，在这里问您一个我自己的问题。
Let me go ahead then and ask you a question of my own here.
让我继续问这个。
Let me go ahead and ask this one.
如果您想讨论这个问题，
If you'd like to buzz in to this question,
搜索链接列表的运行时间是多少？
what is the running time of searching a linked list?
以Big O表示法搜索链接列表的运行时间是多少？
What's the running time of searching a linked list in Big O notation?
那么什么是上限，最坏的搜索情况
So what's an upper bound, worst case of searching
像这样的一个链表，它是否包含三个元素甚至更多？
a linked list like this one, whether it has three elements or even many more?
就像以前一样，该组中大约有80％
So it looks like, as before, about 80% of the group
建议它是n的大O。
is proposing that it's Big O of n.
这实际上是正确的。
And this is actually correct.
因为考虑最坏的情况。
Because consider the worst case.
假设您要寻找数字3，
Suppose you're looking for the number 3, you're
将必须查看所有三个数字，即n的大O。
going to have to look at all three numbers, Big O of n.
如果您要查找数字10，则表示
If you're looking for the number 10, you're
首先要从这里开始
going to start here at the beginning, you're
要继续寻找，寻找，寻找，寻找。
going to keep looking, looking, looking, looking.
您将最终意识到，哦，数字10甚至不在这里。
You're going to get to the end realize, oh, the number 10 is not even here.
此时，您已经查看了n个元素。
At which point, you've already looked at n elements.
但这又是链表的一种。
But here's one of the trade, again, of linked lists.
使用数组，您可以在恒定时间内跳到列表的末尾。
With arrays, you could jump to the end of the list in constant time.
您可以只使用一点算术。
You could just use a little bit of arithmetic.
您可以跳到中间元素或第一个元素，
You could jump to the middle elements, or the first element,
全部使用固定时间。
all using constant time.
不幸的是，最终显示了一个链表
A linked list, unfortunately, is represented ultimately
仅通过一个地址，即指向第一个节点的地址。
by just a single address, the address that points to the very first node.
因此，即使您在摄像机上的所有人都可以看到该节点和该节点
And so even though you all on camera can see this node and this node
而这一次像人类一样，计算机
and this one as humans all at once, the computer
只能跟随这些面包屑。
can only follow these breadcrumbs.
因此，在这种情况下，搜索链接列表将成为n的BigO。
And so searching a linked list is going to be Big O of n in that case.
但是，让我问一个后续问题。
But let me ask a follow up question.
插入链表的运行时间是多少？
What's the running time of inserting into a linked list?
因此，您有了一些新数字，例如数字4或0或100或负5，
So you've got some new number like the number 4 or 0 or 100 or negative 5,
不管是什么
whatever it may be.
将会涉及到一个malloc，但这是固定的时间。
There's going to be a malloc involved, but that's constant time.
这只是一个函数调用。
It's just one function call.
但是您将不得不将其插入某个位置。
But you're going to have to insert it somewhere.
在这里，您看来有68％的人提议1的大O
And here it looks like 68% of you are proposing Big O of 1,
有趣的是，恒定的时间。
which is interesting, constant time.
你们中有25％的人提议n的大O。
25% of you are proposing Big O of n.
任何人都可以随意在口头或聊天中进行提示
Would anyone be comfortable chiming in verbally or on the chat
至于为什么你觉得是另一种呢？
as to why you feel it's one or the other?
的确是这些答案之一。
It is indeed one of those answers.
听众：可能是n的O。
AUDIENCE: It could be O of n.
因为即使你
Because of the fact that even though you're
本质上，使用malloc创建一个新节点
using malloc to create a new node, essentially,
我认为分配计算机时，所有计算机的工作是[？去 -  ？]
I think all the computer's doing when you assign it is [? going-- ?]
当您引用这些箭头时，就像我们要从一个箭头转到下一个箭头一样
as you cite those arrows, like we're going from one arrow to the next
到下一个。
to the next to the next.
而且我认为这将是n的O。
And I would think it would be O of n.
DAVID MALAN：正如您所描述的，它是n的O。
DAVID MALAN: It is O of n as you described it.
但是您也正在做一个假设，就像其他人中的25％所做的那样。
But you, too, are making an assumption, like 25% of other people are making.
您似乎在假设，如果是一个新数字，假设它是数字4，
You seem to be assuming that if a new number, suppose it's number 4,
必须走到最后。
has to go at the end.
或者，如果它是数字5，则必须在末尾输入。
Or if it's the number 5, it has to go at the end.
我故意用这种方式进行设置。
And I kind of deliberately set things up that way.
我碰巧将它们按从左到右的顺序进行维护，即1、2、3。
I've happened to maintain them in sorted order, 1, 2, 3, from left to right.
但是到现在为止，我还没有做出条件
But up until now, I have not made the condition
甚至必须对链接列表进行排序
that the linked list has to be sorted, even
尽管到目前为止我们看到的示例都是故意的。
though the examples we've seen thus far are deliberately that way.
但是，您知道什么，如果您想花哨并且更有效率，
But you know what, if you want to get fancy and a little more efficient,
并且您想分配数字4，坦率地说，您实际上并没有
and you want to allocate the number 4, and frankly, you don't really
关心保持链表的排序顺序，
care about keeping the linked list in sorted order,
好吧，哎呀，把它拉出来，把你的新节点放到这里。
well, heck, just pull this out, put your new node here.
在这里插入。
Plug it in here.
将另一个插回这里。
Plug the other one back in here.
只需将新元素插入列表的开头即可。
And just insert the new element at the beginning of the list.
对于此后的每个数字，请像以前一样分配malloc。
And for every number thereafter, malloc as before.
但是只要继续将其插入此处，将其插入此处，将其插入此处即可。
But just keep inserting it here, inserting it here, inserting it here.
现在，无需采取任何步骤。
Now it's not going to take a single step.
因为当我口头表达出来时，就有了malloc步骤。
Because as I verbalized it, there's, like, the malloc step.
我必须拔掉它。
I have to unplug this.
我必须重新插入。
I have to plug it back in.
因此，总共需要三到四个步骤。
So it's like three or four steps total.
但是四个步骤也是不变的。
But four steps is also constant.
这是1的大O，因为它的步数是固定的。
That's big O of 1, because it's a fixed number of steps.
因此，如果您能够牺牲此列表的排序顺序，
So if you're able to sacrifice sorted order when it comes to this list,
您可以在固定时间内插入，插入，插入，插入。
you can in constant time insert, insert, insert, insert.
列表会越来越长，但是从一开始
And the list is going to get longer and longer, but from the beginning of it
而不是终点。
rather than the end.
因此，这始终是一个权衡。
So that's always a trade off.
如果您不在乎排序顺序，并且您没有算法或代码
If you don't care about sorted order, and none of your algorithms or code
要求将其排序，然后您就可以继续进行下去了
require that it be sorted, then you can go ahead and cut that corner
并实现恒定时间插入，如果您
and achieve constant time insert, which if you're
Twitter或Google之类的东西，也许实际上
a Twitter or Google or the like, maybe that's actually
净储蓄和一件好事。
a net savings and a good thing.
但是，在这种情况下，您又会牺牲排序顺序。
But, again, you sacrifice the sorted order in that case.
好吧，我想，让我们继续吧。
Well, let's go ahead, I think.
让我们将其翻译为一些实际的代码。
And let's translate this to some actual code.
让我在CS50 IDE中继续。
Let me go ahead here in CS50 IDE.
让我们继续写一些变体
And let's go ahead and write a couple of variants
现在实际上用数字做某事的程序
of a program that now actually do something with numbers
并开始操纵记忆中的事物。
and start to manipulate things in memory.
因此，我将在这里继续创建一个名为list.c的程序。
So I'm going to go ahead here and create a program called list.c.
我的第一个版本将非常简单。
And my first version is going to be very simplistic.
我要继续，包括stdio。
I'm going to go ahead and include stdio.
给自己一个int main（void）。
Give myself an int main(void).
然后在这里，让我继续前进，就像我们开始的那样，
And then inside of here, let me go ahead, like we began,
并给我自己一个大小为3的整数列表。
and give myself a list of integers of size 3.
所以这将是一个大小为3的数组。
So this is going to be an array that's of size 3.
这个大小为3的数组，我要继续努力
And this array of size 3, I'm going to go ahead and hard
向其中编码一些新值。
code some new values into it.
因此，在第一个位置，我将输入数字1。
So at the very first location, I'll put the number 1.
在第二个位置，我将输入数字2。
At the second location, I will put the number 2.
在第三个位置，我将输入数字3。
At the third location, I will put the number 3.
然后，只是为了证明这是按我想的那样工作，
And then, just to demonstrate that this is working as I think I intend,
我将快速进行循环。
I'm going to do a quick for loop.
因此，对于int，我得到0，我小于3，我++。
So for int i get 0, i less than 3, i++.
然后，在此循环中，我将继续打印％i。
And then, inside this loop, I'm going to go ahead and print out %i.
然后我将打印出i的值。
And then I'm going to print out the value of i.
现在，我已经在循环中打印了所有这些值，让
So now that I've printed out all of these values in my loop, let
我继续做清单。
me go ahead and do make list.
然后让我继续执行./list，然后按Enter。
Let me go ahead then and do ./list and hit Enter.
确实，我得到了-哎呀，不是我想要的。
And indeed, I get-- oops, not what I wanted.
诚然，这么好的可教的时刻，不是故意的。
So good teachable moment, not intended, admittedly.
但是我在这里做错了什么？
But what have I done wrong here?
我的目标是我们打印出列表。
My goal is we print out the list.
但是不知何故，我打印了0、1、2。
But somehow, I printed out 0, 1, 2.
这些确实不是此列表中的数字。
And those are indeed not the numbers in this list.
[？格雷格？ ？]
[? Greg? ?]
听众：所以你印了i。
AUDIENCE: So you printed i.
您应该已经打印了i的列表。
You should have printed list of i.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
因此，我应该已经打印了数组的内容，即list [i]。
So I should have printed the contents of the array, which is list[i].
所以这只是我在这里的新手错误。
So that was just a newbie mistake by me here.
因此，让我修复该问题。
So let me fix that.
让我继续重新编译make list，。/ list。和voila。
Let me go ahead and recompile make list, ./list., and voila.
我现在已经打印了列表。
I've now printed the list.
所以这是第2周的东西，当我们在第2周首次引入阵列时。
So this is sort of Week 2 stuff, when we first introduced arrays in Week 2.
但是，现在让我继续前进，现在过渡到更具活力的事物。
But now let me go ahead and transition now to something more dynamic.
在我不必提前承诺创建数组的情况下，
Where I don't have to commit in advance to creating an array,
我可以使用动态分配的内存块来完成此操作。
I can do this with a dynamically allocated chunk of memory.
因此，让我删除在main内部完成的所有操作。
So let me delete everything I've done inside of main.
让我继续，给我自己。
And let me go ahead and give myself this.
让我继续声明值列表
Let me go ahead and declare a list of values
现在，列表将成为按照star运算符的地址。
where list is now going to be an address as per the star operator.
我将继续进行malloc-
And I'm going to go ahead and malloc--
让我们来看看。
let's see.
我想要三个整数的空间。
I want space for three integers.
所以最简单的方法，如果我要保持简单，
So the simplest way to do this, if I'm just going to keep it simple,
我实际上可以做到这一点，是int大小的3倍。
I can actually do this, 3 times size of int.
所以我程序的这个版本本身不会使用数组。
So this version of my program isn't going to use an array per se.
它将使用malloc。
It's going to use malloc.
但是它将为我动态分配该数组。
But it's going to dynamically allocate that array for me.
我们将看到它的语法是什么。
And we'll see what the syntax for this is.
和现在一样，无论何时您使用malloc，
As always now, any time you use malloc, I
应该检查list equals是否等于null。
should check whether list equals equals null.
如果是这样，您知道吗？
And if so, you know what?
我要返回1。
I'm just going to return 1.
回想一下，您可以返回0或1或其他一些值
Recall that you can return 0 or 1 or some other value
从主要到有效地退出您的程序。
from main to effectively quit your program.
我要继续，如果list为null，则只返回1，
I'm going to go ahead and just return 1 if list is null,
只是假设某件事非常严重地出了错，例如我内存不足
just assuming that something very badly went wrong, like I'm out of memory
共。
altogether.
但是现在我有了这块内存，大小是原来的3倍
But now that I have this chunk of memory that's of size 3 times
一个int的大小，这实际上是给自己一个数组的malloc方法。
the size of an int, this is actually the malloc way to give yourself an array.
到现在为止，每次我们为自己创建数组时，
Up until now, every time we've created arrays for ourselves,
我们使用方括号表示法。
we've used square bracket notation.
你们都在方括号内放了一个数字
And you all have put a number inside the square brackets
给自己一个这样大小的数组。
to give yourself an array of that size.
但坦率地说，如果我们拥有malloc和
But frankly, if we have malloc and the ability
只是问电脑内存，
to just ask the computer for memory, well,
如果我想存储三个整数，为什么不问malloc
if I want to store three integers, why don't I ask malloc
整数大小的三倍？
for three times the size of an integer?
而malloc的工作原理是
And the way malloc works is it's actually
会返回给我这么大的连续内存，
going to return to me a contiguous chunk of memory of that size,
从而使很多字节背靠背。
so that many bytes back to back to back.
这是我们将在短时间内使用的一种技术
And that's a technique that we'll use in just a moment
分配实际节点时。
when allocating actual nodes.
因此，在故事的这一点上，只要list不等于null，
So at this point in the story, so long as list does not equal null,
现在，我的内存块足够大，可以容纳三个int的大小。
I now have a chunk of memory that's big enough to fit the size of three ints.
和以前一样，我可以继续进行初始化。
And as before, I can go ahead and initialize those.
第一个元素将是1。
The first element will be 1.
第二个元素是2。
The second element will be 2.
第三个元素是3。
The third element will be 3.
并注意现在使用数组之间的等效性
And notice the sort of equivalence now between using arrays
并使用指针。
and using pointers.
C以这种方式具有多种用途，如果您
C is kind of versatile in this way and that if you
malloc有一块内存返回给您，您可以在每个星期内，
have a chunk of memory returned to you by malloc, you can, per last week,
使用方括号表示法。
use square bracket notation.
您可以使用方括号表示法并将该内存块视为一个数组。
You can use square bracket notation and treat that chunk of memory as an array.
因为毕竟是什么数组？
Because after all, what's an array?
这是一个连续的内存块，而这正是malloc返回的内容。
It's a contiguous block of memory and that is exactly what malloc returns.
如果您想花哨的话，实际上可以说去那个地址
If you want to be fancy instead, you could actually say go to that address
并把数字1放在那里。
and put the number 1 there.
您可以说去那个地址加1，然后把下一个数字放在那里。
You could say go to that address plus 1 and put the next number there.
您可以说去那个地址加2，然后把第三个数字放在那里。
You could say go to that address plus 2 and put the third number there.
但老实说，这至少很快变得难以理解
But honestly, this just very quickly becomes unreadable, at least
对大多数人来说。
to most people.
这就是所谓的指针算术，
This is that thing called pointer arithmetic,
你在用指针做算术，
you're doing arithmetic with pointers, that
等同于使用我们已经使用了一段时间的语法，即
is equivalent to using the syntax that we've used for a while now, which
是只使用方括号。
is to just use the square brackets.
而方括号的好处是
And the nice thing about square brackets is
电脑会为您找到
that the computer will figure out for you
这些整数中的每一个相距多远，因为它知道int的大小。
how far apart each of those integers are because it knows the size of an int.
但是现在，在故事的这一点上，
But now, at this point in the story, things
变得有趣又烦人。
get interesting and also annoying.
回想一下，圣地亚哥是帮助我们更早解决这一问题的国家。
And Santiago, recall, was the one that helped us solve this earlier.
假设我没有提前计划。
Suppose I didn't plan ahead.
我只在第五行分配了三个整数。
I only allocated three integers on line five there.
但是现在，在第13行，我该死。
But now, at line 13, I'm, like, oh, dammit.
现在，我想在列表中添加第四个整数。
Now I want to add a fourth integer to the list.
我显然可以重做所有代码。
I could obviously just redo all the code.
但是，假设这里的故事的一部分是继续
But suppose that part of the story here is to go ahead
并动态分配更多内存。
and dynamically allocate more memory.
好吧，我该怎么做？
Well, how can I do this?
好吧，让我继续并临时分配另一块内存。
Well, let me go ahead and allocate another chunk of memory temporarily.
因此，按照惯例，我将其称为temp。
So I'll call it temp, by convention.
这次我将继续分配4倍int的大小。
And this time I'm going to go ahead and allocate 4 times size of int.
因为，为了这个故事，我又搞砸了
Because, again, for the sake of the story, I messed up
我现在想为该原件分配足够的空间-
and I want to allocate enough space now for that original--
我还没搞砸。
I haven't so much messed up.
现在，我决定要向该数组添加第四个数字。
I have now decided that I want to add a fourth number to this array.
和往常一样，我应该检查temp equals是否等于null。
As always, I should check if temp equals equals null.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我将继续释放已经分配的内存。
I'm going to go ahead and free the memory I already allocated.
然后我要离开这里，返回1。
And then I'm just going to get out of here, return 1.
出了些问题。
Something went wrong.
没有什么可证明的。
There's nothing to demonstrate.
因此，我将完全退出主要领域。
So I'm going to exit out of main entirely.
但是，如果malloc没有返回null，并且一切都很好，那我该怎么办？
But if malloc did not return null, and all is well, what am I going to do?
好吧，让我们先做圣地亚哥的建议
Well, let's first do what Santiago proposed
当我们第一次开始这个对话时。
when we first began this conversation.
对于int我得到0，我小于3，我++，让我们继续复制到这个新的，
For int i get 0, i less than 3, i++, let's go ahead and copy into this new,
临时内存块，无论原始内存块是什么。
temporary chunk of memory whatever is at the original chunk of memory.
因此，当圣地亚哥提议我们复制1、2
So when Santiago proposed that we copy 1, 2,
3从旧阵列到新阵列，这里是
3 from the old array into the new array, here's
第2周，我们如何使用简单的for循环在代码中做到这一点？
how we might do that in code just using a simple for loop, a la Week 2.
然后让我现在继续添加一个值tmp [3]，
And then let me go ahead now and add one more value, tmp[3],
如果您从0开始，则是第四个位置。
which is the fourth location if you're starting from 0.
我要继续把4放在那里。
I'm going to go ahead and put the number 4 there.
现在，在这一点上，我要继续记住
And now, at this point, I'm going to go ahead and remember
tmp是我的新列表。
the fact that tmp is my new list.
因此，我将继续释放原始列表。
So I'm going to go ahead and free the original list.
我将更新旧列表以指向新列表。
And I'm going to update my old list to point at the new list.
最后，我要继续使用另一个for循环
And then lastly, I'm going to go ahead and use another for loop just
证明我认为我正确地做到了，这次最多重复4次
to demonstrate that I think I did this correctly, this time iterating up to 4
而不是3。
instead of 3.
我将继续打印并打印出list [i]的内容。
I'm going to go ahead and print out with i the contents of list[i].
因此，让我们快速倒带。
So let's rewind real quick.
我们从分配三个整数数组开始了这个故事。
We began the story by allocating an array of three integers.
但是我们这次是动态进行的，以证明malloc只是
But we did it this time dynamically to demonstrate that malloc just
返回一块内存。
returns a chunk of memory.
而且，如果您要将那部分内存视为一个数组，则绝对可以。
And if you want to treat that chunk of memory as an array, you absolutely can.
这里的东西，如果list等于等于null，
This stuff here, if list equals equals null,
这只是错误检查，只是为了确保没有出错。
it's just error checking, just to make sure that nothing went wrong.
有趣的代码在这里恢复。
The interesting code resumes here.
我将数字1、2和3分别放在位置0、1和2
I'm putting the numbers 1, 2, and 3 at location 0, 1, and 2 respectively
在那块内存中，我再次将其视为数组。
in that chunk of memory which, again, I'm treating like an array.
但现在在故事的这一点上，我已规定，请稍等，
But now at this point in the story, I've stipulated that, wait a minute,
我想继续并添加第四个值。
I want to go ahead and add a fourth value.
我怎样才能做到这一点？
How can I do that?
让我们指定我想返回并更改现有程序。
And let's stipulate that I want to go back and change the existing program.
因为假设出于讨论目的，
Because suppose that for the sake of discussion,
这是一段时间以来在Google或Twitter上运行的代码
this is code that's running at Google or Twitter over time
只有在收到另一条推文之后，他们的代码才能意识到，
and it's only after receiving another tweet that their code realizes,
哦，我们需要更多空间。
oh, we need more space.
那我该怎么办呢？
So how do I do this here?
在第15行，这次我为四个整数分配了足够的空间。
On line 15, this time I allocate enough space for four integers.
然后，我再次进行一些错误检查。
And I, again, do some error checking.
如果tmp等于null，则发生了一些不好的事情。
If tmp equals null, then something bad happened.
让我们一起退出吧。
Let's just exit all together.
但是，如果没有发生任何不好的情况，让我们接受圣地亚哥的建议
But if nothing bad happened, let's take Santiago's suggestion
并将他的英语建议翻译成C。让我们使用一个从0到3的for循环
and translate his English advice into C. Let's use a for loop from 0 to 3
并复制到此新的临时内存块中
and copy into this new temporary chunk of memory
原始内存块的内容。
the contents of the original chunk of memory.
所以tmp [i] = list [i]。
So tmp[i] = list[i].
然后在这里，这就是本练习的重点，
And then here, which was the point of this exercise,
让我在tmp [3]处添加我的第四个数字，如果您在第四个位置，
let me add my fourth number at tmp[3], which is the fourth location if you
从0开始计数。
start counting from 0.
但是在故事的这一点上，就像我之前的幻灯片一样，
But at this point in the story, much like my earlier slide,
我同时拥有大小为3的数组中的1、2、3，
I have both the 1, 2, 3 in an array of size 3,
我在大小为4的数组中有1，2，3个重复项。
and I have 1, 2, 3 duplicated in the array of size 4.
让我继续并释放原始列表并退还给计算机
Let me go ahead and free the original list and give back to the computer
原始的内存块。
that original chunk of memory.
然后让我记住，用我更好的名字
Let me then remember, using my better names
变量，这个新的内存块的地址是什么。
variable, what the address of this new chunk of memory is.
然后，为了炫耀，让我继续前进，
And then, just to show off, let me go ahead,
加上另一个for循环，这次计数了四次，而不是三遍，
and with another for loop, this time counting four times, not three,
让我打印出所有这些值。
let me print out all of those values.
现在，在这里我将尽力而为，编译我的新程序。
Now here's where I'll cross my fingers, compile my new program.
它不能编译确定。
It does not compile OK.
因为看起来我那里有太多括号。
Because it looks like I have one too many parentheses there.
因此，让我们用make list重新编译程序-
So let's recompile the program with make list--
另一个错误。
another error.
所以让我向上滚动。
So let me scroll up there.
哦，很有趣，所以这是一个常见错误，隐式声明了库
And oh, interesting, so this is a common mistake, implicitly declaring library
函数malloc一些东西。
function malloc something something.
因此，每当您收到隐式声明的错误时，
So any time you get an implicitly declaring error,
很有可能这意味着您只是做了一些简单的事情，
odds are it means you just did something simple like this,
您忘记了在其中定义该功能的必需头文件。
you forgot the requisite header file in which that function is defined.
确实，回想一下上周，malloc是免费的，位于标准库中。
And indeed, recall from last week, malloc is in standard lib, as is free.
现在，让我们做一个清单。
So now let's do make list.
再次交叉手指。
Cross my fingers again.
ew
Phew.
那个时候它起作用了。
That time it worked.
./list，瞧，1，2，3，4。
./list, voila, 1, 2, 3, 4.
所以现在这是一个完全字面的翻译
So this is now a completely literal translation
所有这些代码都放入一个工作程序中
of all of that code into a working program
再一次，它使用大小为3的数组开始，
that, again, starts off by using an array of size 3,
动态分配了它。
having dynamically allocated it.
然后通过创建尺寸为4的新尺寸来调整尺寸，将旧尺寸复制为新尺寸，
And then it resizes it by creating a new one of size 4, copying old into new,
释放旧的，然后像以前一样继续进行。
freeing the old, and then proceeding as before.
而且我在这里故意两次都使用了malloc，如下所示。
And I've deliberately used malloc both times here as follows.
如果您使用方括号表示法在C中创建数组，
If you create an array in C using square bracket notation,
你已经把自己画在一个角落。
you have painted yourself into a corner.
您不能使用我们已经看到的任何代码行
You can't use any lines of code that we have seen
并调整使用方括号声明的数组的大小。
and resize an array that you have declared using square brackets.
从技术上来讲，当您使用方括号时，
More technically speaking, when you use the square brackets,
您是在堆栈上静态分配数组。
you are statically allocating the array on the stack.
您将其放入计算机内存的框架中
You're putting it into the frame of the computer's memory
根据该图，属于该计算机，属于该功能的堆栈框架
that belongs to that computer, to that function's stack frame, per the diagram
上个星期。
last week.
但是，如果您使用上周推出的新工具malloc，
If, however, you use malloc, our new tool from last week,
并说给我一块内存，它来自堆。
and say give me a chunk of memory, that comes from the heap.
而且您可以调整大小。
And that you can resize.
这样您就可以回馈并承担更多的往返费用。
That you can give back and take more of and back and forth.
实际上，相对而言，还有一种更简单的方法可以做到这一点。
And in fact, there's even a more simple way of doing this, relatively speaking.
如果您想通过重新调整数组大小来重新分配数组，则是一个大块的内存，
If you want to reallocate an array, a chunk of memory, by resizing it,
您不必做所有我以前做过的事情。
you don't have to do all of this, which I did before.
您不必两次使用malloc。
You don't have to use malloc twice.
您一开始可以使用malloc。
You can use malloc once at the beginning.
然后，您可以使用一个新功能
And then, you can use a new function that's
在这种情况下，实际上有点帮助，称为realloc。
actually kind of helpful in this case, called realloc.
您实际上可以执行此操作，将一块大小为4的内存重新分配
And you can actually do this, realloc a chunk of memory of size 4 times
int的大小。
size of int.
但具体来说，重新分配称为list的东西。
But specifically, reallocate the thing called list.
因此，realloc与malloc非常相似。
So realloc is very similar to malloc.
但这需要两个论点。
But it takes two arguments.
一个是您想要的内存大小，无论是更大还是更小。
One is the size of the memory you want, whether bigger or smaller.
但这需要第二个论点。
But it takes a second argument.
现在，它的第一个参数是一块内存的地址
Its very first argument now is the address of a chunk of memory
与malloc一样，您已经分配了。
that you have already allocated, as with malloc.
因此，同样，在同一程序的顶部，
So, again, at the top of the same program,
回想一下，我使用malloc给自己一个指向大块内存的列表
recall that I used malloc to give myself a list that points at a chunk of memory
足以容纳三个整数。
big enough for three integers.
在第16行，我现在将该地址交还给我重新分配，说，等一下，
On line 16, I'm now handing that address back to realloc, saying, wait a minute,
这是你给我的那个地址。
here is that same address you gave me.
现在，请调整大小，将其重新分配为大小4。
Please now resize it, reallocate it to be of size 4.
该功能的作用是，如果一切顺利，
And what the function does is, if all goes well,
它返回到内存中已经足够大的地址。
it returns to the address in memory that it is now of sufficient size.
否则，如果发生任何不良情况，则返回null。
Otherwise, it returns null if anything bad happened.
因此，我将不理会该代码。
So I'll leave that code alone.
但是，我不必再这样做了。
But what I don't have to do anymore is this.
Realloc实际上为您复制了旧的到新的。
Realloc actually copies the old into the new for you.
因此，再次回到今天开始的圣地亚哥的故事，
So, again, coming back to Santiago's story at the beginning of today,
重新分配不仅会给您更大的块
realloc will not only give you a bigger chunk
内存（如果您需要的话），方法是将内存的地址交还给您
of memory, if you ask for it, by handing back the address of the memory you
已经要求。
already requested.
这将使您获得新的内存块的地址
And it's going to hand you back the address of a new chunk of memory
足以容纳所有这些新价值。
that is big enough to fit all of those new values.
而且它也很聪明。
And it's smart, too.
如果恰好在现有内存块的末尾有空间，
If there happens to be room at the very end of the existing chunk of memory,
就像我们早些时候在幻灯片上看到的那样，世界没有你好
there's no hello, world, like we saw on my slide earlier,
那么您实际上将获得完全相同的地址。
then you're actually going to get back the exact same address.
但是计算机的操作系统是Windows，Mac，OS或Linux，
But the computer's operating system, Windows, Mac, OS, or Linux,
会记得，好吧，是的，我知道我原来给了你三个字节。
is going to remember, OK, yes, I know I gave you three bytes originally.
那块内存的末尾恰好有空间。
There happened to be room at the end of that chunk of memory.
所以现在我要记住，那个相同的地址有
So now I'm going to remember, instead, that that same address has
可以容纳四个整数或您传入的任何数字的空间。
room for four integers, or whatever number you pass in.
因此，再次，您不必费心复制自己。
So, again, you don't have to bother copying yourself.
您可以让计算机实际为您进行重新分配。
You can let the computer actually do the reallocation for you.
任何问题，然后是关于malloc，关于realloc，关于free或从根本上来说，
Any questions, then on malloc, on realloc, on free, or fundamentally,
在链表上？
on linked lists?
请注意，这还不是一个列表。
Notice that this isn't yet a list.
这仍然是一个数组。
This is still an array.
因此，我们仍然需要将该程序再进一步一点
So we still need to take this program one step further
并实际上从这块内存过渡
and actually transition from this chunk of memory
对这些实际节点使用数组。
using arrays to these actual nodes.
但是在我们这样做之前，有什么疑问或困惑吗？
But before we do that, any questions or confusion?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
出现了一个问题，为什么您不需要在程序结束时释放tmp？
A question came in, why do you not need to free tmp at the end of the program?
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：为什么在程序结束时不需要释放tmp？
DAVID MALAN: Why do I not need to free tmp at the end of the program?
因为我是个白痴，对关键的重要细节一无所知。
Because I'm an idiot and glossed over that key, important detail.
在这种情况下，您绝对不应该释放tmp而不是列表。
You absolutely should free not tmp in this case, but list.
因此，在这里的这一行27，我使用了我的list变量，它的名字比较好，
So at this line here, 27, I use my list variable, which just has a better name,
我将其设置为等于tmp，以便可以将其称为更大的列表。
and I make it equal to tmp so that I can just refer to it as a bigger list.
但是你说的很对。
But you are quite right.
那是我的疏忽。
That was an oversight on my part.
Valgrind不会喜欢的。
Valgrind would not have liked that.
在该程序结束时，我应该绝对自由列出。
At the very end of this program, I should absolutely free list.
但是，我本身不需要免费的tmp，
However, I don't need to free tmp, per se,
因为我只是通过该分配重用了变量名。
because I've simply reused the variable name through that assignment.
好问题，好捕获。
Good question and good catch.
意想不到的。
Unintended.
其他问题或意见，布莱恩？
Other questions or comments, Brian?
BRIAN：问题来了，为什么链表会改善
BRIAN: Question came in, why does the linked list improve
这种情况下，如果我们只能使用数组并重新分配和malloc做
this situation if we can just use arrays and realloc and malloc to do
所有这些东西？
all this stuff?
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
真的很好的问题。
Really good question.
那么，如果我们只能以这种方式使用数组，我们如何改善这种情况呢？
So how have we improved this situation if we can just use arrays in this way?
回想一下，这是一种回归。
Recall that this is kind of a regression.
我刚才所做的只是回归故事的起点，据此
What I just did is a regression to where we started the story, whereby
在我刚刚编写的任何版本的代码中，
in any of the versions of code I just wrote,
我为该数组重新分配了更多空间。
I reallocated more space for this array.
这意味着我手动使用该for循环，或使用自己的realloc
Which means that I, manually with that for loop, or realloc with its own
对于循环，必须将所有旧值复制到新值中。
for loop, had to copy all of the old values into the new.
因此，我们在该程序的所有三个版本中采用的方法
So the approach we've taken in all three versions of this program
到目前为止，我一直在写，他们都是n的大O。
that I've written thus far on the fly, they've all been Big O of n.
当涉及插入时，他们没有给我们链接列表的活力
When it comes to inserts, they have not given us the dynamism of a linked list
只需添加而无需重复。
to just add without that duplication.
而且我们还没有能力进行插入，例如，
And we haven't had the ability yet to just do an insert, for instance,
1的Big O中的结构开头。
at the beginning of the structure in Big O of 1 time.
再次，这是代码翻译，真的，
So, again, this is the code translation, really,
是我们开始时采用的较慢的方法。
of that slower approach from which we began.
因此，现在的最终目标是更改此代码
So the ultimate goal now is going to be to change this code
并给我们这种动力并实际上将事物实现为适当的链接
and give us that dynamism and actually implement things as a proper linked
列表，而不仅仅是一个整数数组。
list, not just as an array of integers.
但是我们大约一个小时。
But we're about an hour in.
让我们继续前进，在这里休息第一个五分钟。
Let's go ahead and take our first five minute break here.
当我们回来时，我们会将节点本身转换为完整的程序。
And when we come back, we'll translate the nodes themselves to a full program.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we are back.
回想一下，我们今天从回顾数组并指出
And recall that we began today by revisiting arrays and pointing out
如果您对它们进行排序，那么对数组的搜索非常有用。
that searching is great in arrays if you keep them sorted.
您从第0周起就得到了我们喜欢的log n的BigO。
You get the Big O of log n that we liked back from Week 0.
但是，一旦您要开始动态修改数组，
But as soon as you want to start dynamically modifying an array,
它很快变得非常昂贵。
it gets very expensive quickly.
复制可能需要您花费n步的大笔费用
It might take you Big O of n steps to copy
将旧的小型阵列的内容转换为新的较大阵列。
the contents of an old, small array into a new, bigger array.
老实说，随着时间的流逝，尤其是对于具有大量数据的真实世界的软件而言，
And honestly, over time, especially for real world software with lots of data,
即使n的大O也很昂贵。
even Big O of n is expensive.
就像，您不想一直复制和复制
Like, you don't want to be constantly copying and copying and copying
计算机内存附近的所有数据。
all of your data around the computer's memory.
因此，我们可以通过使用指针来避免这种情况，
So we can avoid that by using pointers and, in turn,
将这些称为“链表”的结构拼接在一起，
stitching together these structures called linked lists,
尽管付出了更多内存的代价。
albeit at a price of spending more memory.
但是有了额外的内存，就需要增加额外的动力。
But with that additional memory, that additional cost, comes dynamism.
这样，如果我们愿意，我们甚至可以实现恒定的时间
So that if we want we can even achieve constant time
当涉及到插入时。
when it comes to inserting.
但是，当然，我们必须牺牲诸如可分类性之类的东西。
But of course, then we have to sacrifice things like sortability.
因此，这需要权衡取舍。
So this came with trade offs.
我们刚刚看了一些实际C程序的例子
We've just seen a few examples of actual C programs
首先执行旧数组，每个第0周，
that implement first the old school array, per Week 0,
在这里我们只是硬编码数组的长度。
where we just hardcode the array's length.
不幸的是，我们把自己画在了一个角落，
And unfortunately, we painted ourselves into a corner,
单独使用括号符号。
using the bracket notation alone.
因此，我们改为部署了m，它是一种更具通用性的工具，
So we deployed instead m which is more versatile tool that
让我们获得尽可能多的内存。
lets us get as much memory as we want.
然后，我们用它来重新创建将列表实现为数组的想法。
And we used that to recreate the idea of a list implemented as arrays.
但是即使那样，我们仍然看到我必须使用for循环进行复制
But even then, we saw that I had to copy using a for loop
否则我们不得不使用旧的，间接的，重新分配的副本复制到新的副本中。
or we had to copy using, indirectly, realloc, old into new.
同样，对于这些小程序，您甚至都没有注意到它们之间的区别。
And, again, for these small programs, you don't even notice the difference.
程序像这样运行。
The programs run like that.
但是对于大型的，现实世界的软件来说，这是n次
But for large, real world software, all of that Big O of n time
将很快加起来。
is going to add up quickly.
因此，最好是我们完全避免它并实现动态。
So it's best if we can try to avoid it altogether and achieve dynamism.
因此，您可以通过其动态添加到链表的代码
So the code via which you can add to linked list dynamically
实际上，这是下周问题集5面临的挑战的一部分。
is actually part of the challenge for Problem Set 5 this coming week.
但是让我们看一些可以通过句法构建的构建块
But let's see some of the building blocks via which we can syntactically
开始分配节点并将它们拼接在一起
start to allocate nodes and stitch them together when
我们事先知道我们想要多少。
we know in advance how many we want.
问题集5不会出现这种情况
Which is not going to be the case for Problem Set 5,
但目前确实如此，因为我只想要其中三件事。
but for now is indeed the case, because I only want three of these things.
所以我将从以前回到我的程序。
So I'm going to go back to my program from before.
我将倒退并竞赛main内部的所有内容。
And I'm going to rewind and race everything inside of main.
我要继续声明自己
And I'm going to go ahead and declare myself
一个类型为struct节点的类型，该类型的开头带有一个数字，并带有一个struct节点
a type called struct node initially with a number inside of it and a struct node
*在里面叫下一个。
* called next inside of that.
然后，我将整个过程称为“节点”。
And then I'm going to call this whole thing quite simply node.
因此，这与我们对一个人所做的非常相似。
So that's quite similar to what we did with a person.
但是现在有点幻想，因为我提供的是结构本身
But now it's a little fancier in that I'm giving the structure itself
临时名称struct节点。
a temporary name, struct node.
我指的是结构内部的临时名称
I'm referring to that temporary name inside of the structure
这样我也可以在那里找到一个指针
so that I can have a pointer there, too.
然后，我将人重命名为现在的节点。
And then I'm renaming what was person to now node.
现在，让我们继续并在main内部实际使用此东西。
Now let's go ahead and actually use this thing inside of main.
因此，让我继续创建一个空的链表。
So let me go ahead and create an empty linked list.
翻译我们今天开始的简单区块的最简单方法就是
The simplest way to translate the simple block with which we began today is just
正在执行节点* list;。
doing node *list;.
不幸的是，任何时候您声明一个变量
Unfortunately, any time you declare a variable
没有分配的值，这是垃圾。
that does not have an assigned value, it's garbage.
在指针世界中，垃圾是不好的。
And garbage is bad in the world of pointers.
同样，要明确的是，如果您创建此名为list的变量
Again, to be clear, if you create this variable called list
并且您没有显式初始化其值
and you do not explicitly initialize its value
就像零点指向地面一样
to be something like null pointing at the ground,
而是将其保留为垃圾值，它是
but instead leave it as a garbage value, it's
该箭头指向的隐喻等效形式
the sort of metaphorical equivalent of this arrow pointing
这种方式这种方式
this way, this way, this other way.
也就是说，您可能会意外地使用自己的代码，
That is to say you might accidentally, in your own code,
跟随此箭头到一个完全伪造的地方。
follow this arrow to a completely bogus place.
这就是所谓的分段错误所在，
And that's the point at which you have what are called segmentation faults,
就像你们中的一些人在您完成问题集4时已经经历的那样
as some of you might have experienced already with Problem Set 4 when you
触摸不应该的记忆。
touch memory that you shouldn't.
因此，垃圾值在上下文中变得更加糟糕。
So garbage values are bad ever more so in the context
出于这个原因的指针。
of pointers for that reason.
因此，您很少想要这样做。
So you rarely want to do this.
您几乎总是想将指针初始化为某个已知值。
You almost always want to initialize the pointer to some known value.
在没有实际地址的情况下，我们
In the absence of an actual address, we're
将使用null来指示那里什么都没有。
going to use null to indicate that there's nothing there.
但这是我们故意的。
But that's deliberate on our part.
现在，假设我要插入，就像我在物理上所做的一样
Now, suppose I want to insert, just as I did physically
通过将第一个块放在舞台上，让我继续前进
by lugging the block number 1 onto stage before, let me go ahead
并分配一个节点-我们将其暂时称为n-
and allocate a node-- we'll call it n temporarily--
使用malloc，这一次要求一个节点的大小。
using malloc, this time asking for the size of a node.
因此，故事现在正在改变。
So the story is now changing.
我没有分配单个整数。
I'm not allocating individual ints.
我正在分配单个节点，其中的内部空间足以容纳一个整数
I'm allocating individual nodes inside of which is enough room for an integer
和另一个指向节点的指针。
and another pointer to a node.
运营商的规模可以从定义中得出
And this size of operator figures out, from the definition
上面这个结构的结构，有多少空间
of this structure up here above main, how much space
需要用于存储整数和指向结构节点的指针。
is needed to store an integer and a pointer to a struct node.
因此，一如既往，我将始终进行检查。
So as always now, I'm always going to check.
如果n等于null，我将退出该程序
If n equals equals null, I'm going to get out of this program
立即返回1。
immediately, and just return 1.
因为出了点问题，而且没有足够的内存。
Because something went wrong, and there's just not enough memory.
但是，如果一切顺利，我现在就继续进行，进入该节点n。
But if all went well, I'm going to go ahead now and go into that node n.
我将进入其数字字段并为其分配值1。
I'm going to go into its number field and assign it the value 1.
我将进入该节点n并进入其下一个字段，现在，
And I'm going to go into that node n and go into its next field and, for now,
给它分配空值。
assign it the value null.
好像我刚给木制积木分配了1
So this is as though I've just allocated the wooden block with a 1 in it
并且我已经将它的下一个指针初始化为null。
and I have initialized its next pointer to null.
现在，我将继续更新列表本身以指向该值。
Now I'm going to go ahead and update the list itself to point at that value.
所以，再次，我的变量叫做list是通过它的变量
So, again, my variable called list is the variable via which
我代表了整个清单。
I'm representing the whole list.
现在，我有一个实际的节点要指向，
And now that I have an actual node to point to,
我正在设置列表，它再次是一个指向节点的指针，等于
I'm setting list which, again, is a pointer, to a node, equal to whatever
n是实际节点的地址。
n is, the address of an actual node.
所以在故事的这一点上，我已经连接了一个小木块
So at this point in the story, I have the small wooden block connected
到包含1的较大块。
to the larger block containing 1.
为了讨论起见，让我们假设
Let's suppose, for the sake of discussion,
我现在想将数字2添加到此列表中，这次使用
I now want to add the number 2 to this list, this time using
一个节点，而不仅仅是一个整数。
a node as well, not just an integer.
我将继续使用malloc分配n，
I'm going to go ahead and allocate n, using malloc,
给我自己另一个节点的大小。
giving myself the size of another node.
我要再次检查那个东西是否相等
I'm going to again just going to check if that thing equals
null，让我继续并释放列表，以免泄漏内存。
null let me go ahead and free the list so I don't leak memory.
然后让我继续并返回1。
Then let me go ahead and return 1.
所以这只是一个快速的理智检查
So that's just a quick sanity check to make
确保我释放了之前已经分配的所有内存。
sure I free any memory I've already allocated before.
但是如果一切顺利，那是我所希望的，
But if all goes well, and that's what I'm hoping for,
我将继续进入该节点n并存储在其number字段中
I'm going to go ahead and go into this node n and store in its number field
从字面上看是2。
literally the number 2.
然后现在，因为这件事
And then now, because this thing--
我现在将其按排序顺序插入-
I'll insert it in sorted order for now--
我将继续进行下一步，并插入下一个= NULL。
I'm going to go ahead and insert this next = NULL.
如果我确实想将此2号节点放在1号节点之后，
And if I indeed want to put this number 2 node after the number 1 node,
我可以从列表的顶部开始，可以转到下一个节点。
I can start at the top of the list, I can go to the next node.
在其价值内，我可以说n。
And inside of its value, I can say n.
因此，这行代码从小块开始，跟随箭头，
So this line of code here starts at the little block, follows the arrow,
然后更新该第一个节点的下一个指针1节点，
and then updates the next pointer of that first node, the 1 node,
而是存储该新节点的地址n。
to instead store the address of this new node, n.
最后，让我们再做一个，所以n = malloc（sizeof（node））;
And then lastly, let's do one more of these so n = malloc(sizeof(node));
最后一次。
one last time.
让我继续进行一次理智检查。
Let me go ahead and do my sanity check one more time.
如果n = = NULL，那么会发生不好的情况。
If n = = NULL something bad happened.
因此，现在我将继续进行操作，不必担心语法。
So now I'm going to go ahead and don't worry about the syntax just yet.
但是，我将继续进行下一步，然后列出免费列表。
But I'm going to go ahead and free list next.
我将继续免费（列表）；
And I'm going to go ahead and free(list);
然后我将继续并返回1。
and then I'm going to go ahead and return 1.
但是在另一时间。
But more on that another time.
那只是在发生一些不好的情况的极端情况下。
That's just in the corner case where something bad happened.
但是，如果没有发生任何问题，我将把number字段更新为3。
But if nothing bad happened, I'm going to update the number field to be 3.
我将下一个字段更新为NULL。
I'm going to update the next field to be NULL.
现在我要更新下一个块的列表
And now I'm going to update the list next block
下一个等于该新n的块。
next block to equal this new one n.
然后，在此之后，如果需要，我可以继续打印所有这些东西。
And then here, after this, I can proceed to print all of these things if I want.
实际上，我将继续循环进行此操作。
And in fact, I'll go ahead and do this with a loop.
在这种情况下，循环看起来与以前有些不同。
The loop is going to look a little different from before in this case.
但是事实证明，我们在这里也可以非常强大地使用for循环。
But it turns out we can use for loops pretty powerfully here, too.
但是在故事的这一点上，我的列表指针
But at this point in the story, my list pointer
指向1节点，它指向2
is pointing at the 1 node, which is pointing at the 2
节点，它指向3节点。
node, which is pointing at the 3 node.
而且，正如之前有人观察到的那样，
And, again, as someone observed earlier, it's
在这种情况下，使用此双箭头符号并不常见。
not common to use this double arrow notation in this case.
我敢打赌，我实际上可以使用循环来遍历这些东西
I bet I could actually use a loop to iterate over these things
一次一个。
one at a time.
当需要打印时，我们可以在这里看到。
And we can see this here when it's time to print.
让我继续这样做。
Let me go ahead and do this for.
而不是使用i，因为实际上没有任何数字在讨论中。
And instead of using i, because there really aren't any numbers in question.
这不再是数组，所以我不能使用方括号符号或指针
This is no longer an array, so I can't use square bracket notation or pointer
算术。
arithmetic.
我需要使用指针。
I need to use pointers.
因此，一开始可能会觉得有些奇怪。
So this might feel a little weird at first.
但是，并没有阻止我使用for循环执行此操作。
But there's nothing stopping me with a for loop from doing this.
给我一个临时指针，指向名为tmp的节点
Give me a temporary pointer to a node called tmp
并将其初始化为列表开头的任何内容。
and initialize it to be whatever is at the beginning of the list.
只要tmp不等于NULL，就继续执行以下操作。
Keep doing the following so long as tmp does not equal NULL.
并且在此循环的每次迭代中，请勿执行类似i ++的操作，
And on each iteration of this loop, don't do something like i++ which,
同样，现在不相关了。
again, is not relevant now.
但是继续更新我的临时指针
But go ahead and update my temporary pointer
成为临时指针的下一个字段的值是什么。
to be whatever the value of the temporary pointer's next field is.
因此，这很可能看起来像是疯狂的神秘事物，尤其是
So this looks crazy cryptic most likely, especially
如果您像上周一样不熟悉指针，则与大多数人一样。
if you're new to pointers as of last week, as most of you are.
但是，相同的想法是典型的for循环。
But it's the same idea is a typical for loop.
您可以在分号之前初始化一些变量。
You initialize some variable before the semicolon.
您在第一个分号后检查一些条件。
You check some condition after the first semicolon.
然后在第二个分号之后执行该变量的更新。
And you perform an update of that variable after the second semicolon.
在这种情况下，它们不是整数。
In this case, they're not integers, though.
相反，我是说给自己一个暂时的起点
Instead, I'm saying give myself a temporary pointer to the beginning
列表中的手指，例如我的手指指着泡沫手指，或者，如果您愿意，
of the list, like my finger pointing at, or if you prefer, the foam finger
指向列表中的某个节点。
pointing at some node in the list.
继续并调用该临时变量tmp。
Go ahead and call that temporary variable tmp.
现在执行以下操作。
And now do the following.
只要tmp不为null，也就是说，只要它为
So long as tmp is not null, that is, so long as it's
指着一个实际的合法木块，我该怎么办？
pointing at an actual legitimate wooden block, what do I want to do?
让我继续使用printf和％i进行打印，
Let me go ahead and print out, using printf and %i as always,
那里那个节点的数字字段中的任何值。
whatever value is in the number field of that node there.
就是这样。
And that's it.
有了这个简单的for循环，相对简单的for循环，
With this simple for loop, relatively simple for loop,
我基本上可以指向列表中的第一个节点
I can essentially point at the very first node in my list
并继续将其更新到下一个字段，将其更新到下一个字段，
and keep updating it to the next field, updating it to the next field,
将其更新到下一个字段。
updating it to the next field.
我一直这样做，直到我的手指掉下来
And I keep doing this until my finger sort of walks off
木块列表的末尾，从而
the end of the list of wooden blocks, thereby
指向null，0x0，此时循环停止
pointing at null, 0x0, at which point the loop stops
没有更多可打印的内容了。
and there's nothing more to print.
因此，为了更早地回答该问题，我们
So in answer to that question earlier, do we
需要使用这个双箭头符号吗？
need to use this double arrow notation?
简短的回答，不，这是这里的秘密成分。
Short answer, no, this is kind of the secret ingredient here.
for循环中的这种语法可以接受您所指的任何内容，
This syntax inside of the for loop takes whatever you're pointing at,
跟随一个箭头，然后立即更新临时变量
follows one arrow, and then updates the temporary variable now
指向那个结构。
to point at that structure instead.
因此，这在指针和链接列表的世界中是等效的
So this is kind of the equivalent in the world of pointers and linked lists
做我++。
of doing i++.
但这并不像i ++那样简单。
But it's not as simple as i++.
您不能只向右或向左看一个字节。
You can't just look one byte to the right or to the left.
相反，您必须跟随箭头，然后跟随箭头。
Instead, you have to follow an arrow, follow an arrow.
但是通过将这个临时变量重新分配给您刚刚关注的任何地方，
But by reassigning this temporary variable to wherever you just followed,
这是跟随每个橙色箭头的方式
it's a way of following each of these orange arrows
就像我们刚才所做的一样。
as we did physically a moment ago.
在此之后，我应该采取充分的措施，继续释放整个清单。
After this, I should, for good measure, go ahead and free the whole list.
而且，让我提供释放链表的常用方法。
And let me just offer up a common way of freeing a linked list.
我实际上可以做这样的事情。
I can actually do something like this.
虽然list！= NULL，所以虽然整个列表本身不等于null，
While list != NULL, so while the whole list itself does not equal null,
继续，并获得一个指向下一个字段的临时指针，这样我
go ahead and get a temporary pointer like this to the next field so I
记住在列表的当前标题之后是什么。
remember what comes after the current head of the list.
释放列表节点本身。
Free the list node itself.
然后更新列表为tmp。
And then update list to be tmp.
因此，再次，这可能看起来是疯狂的神秘的，当然在未来
So, again, this probably looks crazy cryptic and certainly in the coming
天，尤其是问题集5，您将
days, especially with Problem Set 5, you'll
在逻辑上多一点地处理这种逻辑
work through this kind of logic a little more logically, a little more
也许是图片上的。
pictorially, perhaps.
但是我在这里做什么？
But what am I doing here?
首先，只要链接列表不为空，我就将执行以下操作。
First, I'm going to do the following, so long as my linked list is not null.
如果我有三个节点，按照定义
And if I've got three nodes in it, by definition
从一开始就不为空。
it's not null from the beginning.
但是我现在的目标是释放我分配的所有内存
But my goal now is to free all of the memory I have allocated
从左到右，可以这么说。
from left to right, so to speak.
那我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do that?
好吧，如果我面前有一个木块，
Well, if I've got a wooden block in front of me,
释放那个木块还不安全。
it's not safe to free that wooden block yet.
因为回想起那个木块，所以包含指向下一个节点的指针。
Because that wooden block, recall, contains the pointer to the next node.
因此，如果我过早地释放了内存，
So if I free this memory prematurely, I've
然后搁浅所有后续节点。
then stranded all subsequent nodes.
因为一旦我告诉计算机，就无法再访问它们
Because they are no longer accessible once I've told the computer
您可以为第一个节点取回这块内存。
you can take back this chunk of memory for the first node.
因此，这行代码（第52行）只是暂时说
So this line of code here, on line 52, is just saying temporarily
给我一个叫tmp的变量。
give me a variable call tmp.
并且不要将其指向列表本身（第一个节点），而是指向下一个节点。
And point it not at the list itself, the first node, point at the next node.
所以就像用我的右手指向当前节点，我的左手
So it's like using my right hand to point at the current node, my left hand
指向下一个节点，这样我就可以在第53行上释放列表本身，
to point at the next node, so that I can then, on line 53, free the list itself,
这不应该从字面上看。
which should not be taken literally.
列表表示链接列表中的第一个节点，而不是整个对象。
List represents the first node in the linked list, not the whole thing.
因此，当您说空闲列表时，就像仅释放当前节点一样。
So when you say free list, that's, like, freeing just the current node.
但是没关系。
But that's OK.
即使现在，这个记忆已经归还了，
Even now this memory has been given back,
我的左手仍然指向每个后续节点
I still have my left hand pointing at every subsequent node
通过下一个。
by way of the next one.
所以现在我可以将列表更新为等于该临时变量
So now I can update list to equal that temporary variable
并继续此循环。
and just continue this loop.
因此，这是一种Pacman风格的方式，例如，
So it's a way of sort of Pacman style, like,
从左侧吞噬整个链表
gobbling up the entire linked list from left
向右移动第一个节点，第二个节点，第三个节点，然后
to right by freeing the first node, the second node, the third node, and then
你完成了。
you're done.
但是通过使用临时变量来向前看一步，以确保
But by using a temporary variable to look one step ahead to make sure
你不吃力，过早释放内存
you don't chomp, free the memory too soon
因此，将失去对所有这些后续节点的访问权限。
and, therefore, lose access to all of those subsequent nodes.
好吧，
All right, phew.
那是一个很大的程序。
That was a big program.
但这本来应该是连续的，从数组开始，
But it was meant to be in succession, starting with an array,
过渡到动态分配的数组，最后是
transitioning into a dynamically allocated array, followed by, finally,
使用链表的实现，尽管是硬编码的
an implementation using linked list, albeit hardcoded
仅支持三个节点。
to support only three nodes.
但是在该示例中，您是否看到了一些示例语法，通过这些示例语法
But in that example, do you see some sample syntax via which you
可以操纵这些类型的节点？
can manipulate these kinds of nodes?
我可以帮助解决的问题或困惑？
Questions or confusion that I can help address?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yes.
有人问，就像您之前做过的一个例子一样，
Someone asked, similar to one of the examples you did before,
为什么我们不能刚刚完成三倍于节点大小的malloc
why could we not have just done malloc three times size of node
得到三个节点，并这样做吗？
to get three nodes and do it that way?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
我不能只使用malloc并一次分配所有三个吗？
Could I not just use malloc and allocate all three at once?
绝对地。
Absolutely.
是的。
Yes.
那完全是你的特权。
That is completely your prerogative.
我做得更勤快一点，一次一次。
I did it a little more pedantically, one at a time.
但是您绝对可以一次全部完成这三个操作。
But you could absolutely do it all three at once.
然后，您将需要使用一些指针算法，
You would then need to use some pointer arithmetic though,
否则您将需要使用方括号符号
or you would need to square bracket notation
将更大的内存块视为本质上是节点数组，
to treat that bigger chunk of memory as essentially an array of nodes,
然后将它们缝在一起。
and then stitch them together.
因此，我假设出于演示目的，
So I am assuming, for demonstration purposes,
即使我们有这些简单的例子来说明
that even though we have these little simple examples that demonstrate
语法，在现实世界的系统中，您不会插入1，
the syntax, in a real world system, you're not going to be inserting 1,
然后2，然后3。
then 2, then 3.
奇怪的是，您将要插入1。
Odds are you're going to be inserting 1.
一段时间过去了。
Some time passes.
然后，您想插入2，以便分配更多的内存。
Then you want to insert 2, so you allocate more memory.
然后再经过一些时间。
Then some more time passes.
然后您要插入3。
Then you want to insert 3.
因此，在现实世界中，这些代码块之间存在差距。
And so there's gaps in between these chunks of code in the real world.
还有其他疑问或困惑吗？
Other questions or confusion?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
另一个问题出现了。
Another question came in.
为什么malloc永远无法分配内存？
Why would malloc ever fail to allocate memory?
DAVID MALAN：为什么malloc会失败？
DAVID MALAN: Why would malloc ever fail?
它很少会失败，但是如果计算机内存不足。
It's rarely going to fail, but if the computer is out of memory.
所以本质上，如果您正在编写这样的内存需求大的程序
So essentially, if you're writing such a memory hungry program
具有如此多的变量，大型数组，大型结构，大量数据，
with so many variables, big arrays, big structures, lots of data,
您可能会耗尽内存。
you may very well run out of memory.
也许是2 GB，也许是4 GB或更多。
Maybe that's two gigabytes, maybe it's four gigabytes or more.
但是malloc可能很容易向您返回null。
But malloc may very well return null to you.
因此，您应该始终对其进行检查。
And so you should always check for it.
实际上，我敢说，在Mac和PC上，
In fact, I dare say, on Macs and PCs, one
直到今天，最常见的原因是程序被冻结，
of the most common reasons, to this day, for programs to freeze,
崩溃，您的家用计算机重新启动，
to crash, for your home computer to reboot,
确实是因为有人做了一些愚蠢的事情，例如我
is truly because someone did something stupid, like I've
现在已经在今天和上周进行了多次，
done multiple times now already today and last week,
触摸您不应该拥有的记忆。
by touching memory that you shouldn't have.
因此，在问题集4和现在的问题5中，
So in Problem Set 4 and now 5, any time you
经历那些细分错误之一
experience one of those segmentation faults
因此您的程序崩溃了，这就是问题所在
whereby your program just crashes, that is the problem set
整个Mac或PC崩溃的版本，
version of, like, your whole Mac or PC crashing,
因为有人比你经验丰富
because someone more experienced than you
在他们的代码中犯了同样的错误。
made that same mistake in their code.
为了加强这一点，让我们以一个快速的最终示例为例
Just to reinforce this, let's take a quick final example
涉及链表，这又是一维结构，
involving linked lists which, again, are this very one dimensional structure,
左到右。
left to right.
然后，我们将添加第二个维度，看看能为我们带来什么。
And then we'll add a second dimension and see what that buys us.
但是我们已经更改了此处的数字。
But we've changed the numbers around here.
现在我们仍然有清单。
Now we still have our list.
但这首先指向这里的第二位。
But it's first pointing at the number two here.
然后第二个指向其他的内存块
And then the number two is pointing to some other chunk of memory that's
被分配到这里。
been malloced way over here.
那么，这就是数字4。
And this, then, is the number 4.
那么，这就是数字5。
And this, then, is the number 5.
因此，我们有一个大小为3的链表。
So we have a linked list of size 3.
但是这次我故意将数字分配给2、4、5。
But I've deliberately spread the numbers out this time, 2, 4, 5.
因为假设我们确实希望在此列表中插入更多数字，
Because suppose that we do want to insert more numbers into this list,
但是按照排序的顺序，事实证明我们
but in sorted order, it turns out that we
当什么时候必须有所不同
have to think a little bit differently when
我们不是在节点的末尾添加节点，
we're adding nodes not to the end and not to the beginning,
但在中间。
but in the middle.
例如，当我们想在中间分配更多的节点时，
Like, when we want to allocate more nodes in the middle,
实际上还有更多工作要做。
there's a bit more work that actually has to happen.
那么我们该怎么做呢？
So how might we go about doing this?
假设我们要分配数字1。
Suppose that we want to allocate, for instance, the number 1.
我想添加数字1。
And I want to add the number 1.
好吧，我们可以使用这样的代码。
Well, we could use code like this.
这与我们之前使用的代码相同。
This is the same code as we used before.
我们分配一个节点的大小。
We allocate the size of a node.
我们检查它是否等于null，然后将其初始化
We check whether it equals null, we initialize it
具有我们关心的值，并且默认情况下，我们坐在下一个等于null的位置。
with a value we care about, and by default, we sit next equal to null.
从图片上看，它可能看起来像这样。
And pictorially, it might look like this.
有点像漂浮在计算机内存中的某个地方。
It's kind of floating somewhere in the computer's memory.
我有了这个临时变量n，不再显示了，
I have this temporary variable n, no longer pictured,
我在分配数字1时所指的就是
that I'm just pointing at when I allocate the number 1.
那么这是什么样的呢？
So what does this look like?
这就像可能在此处某处有数字1。
This is like having the number 1 maybe somewhere over here.
我将其放置到位。
And I'll just put it in place.
我们很幸运，那里有很多记忆。
We got lucky, and there was a chunk of memory right there.
那我现在想做什么？
So what do I want to now do?
好吧，我想继续进行连接。
Well, I want to go ahead and connect this.
所以我可以做的，只是凭直觉，如果1应该排在2之前
So what I could do, just intuitively, if 1 should go before 2,
我可以拔掉它。
I can unplug this.
我可以将其插入此处，这很有意义。
And I can plug this into here, which makes sense.
但是已经有问题了。
But there's already a problem.
如果到目前为止我什么也没做，
If I have done nothing else up until this point,
我只是孤立了三个节点2、4、5。
I have just orphaned three nodes, 2, 4, and 5.
孤立一个节点意味着忘记它在哪里。
To orphan a node means to forget where it is.
如果我的代码中没有其他变量，
And if I don't have another variable in my code,
或者如果我没有用一只手表演
or if I'm not acting out with one of my hands
指向列表的原始开头，
pointing at the original beginning of the list,
我实际上已经孤立了列表的其余部分。
I have literally orphaned the rest of the list.
而且，从技术上讲，每星期，
And the technical implication of that, per last week,
就是现在我有大量的内存泄漏。
is that now I have a massive memory leak.
您刚刚泄漏了三个节点的大小
You have just leaked the size of three nodes
在记忆中，你几乎永远都不会回来
in memory that you can literally never get back
例如，直到重新启动计算机，
until you reboot the computer, for instance,
否则程序将退出，操作系统将为您清除内容。
or the program quits and the operating system cleans things up for you.
所以你不想这样做。
So you don't want to do this.
操作顺序实际上很重要。
Order of operations actually matters.
所以我可能应该做的是。
So what I should probably do is this.
当我首先插入数字1时，我可能应该
When I insert the number 1 first, I should probably
认识到，那是从列表的开头开始的。
recognize that, well, the one begins at the beginning of the list.
因此，我真正应该做的就是将此箭头也指向同一节点。
So what I should really do is point this arrow also at the same node.
我们会像这样有点草率地做到这一点。
And we'll sort of do it a little sloppily like that.
但是让我规定它们都指向同一节点。
But let me stipulate those are both pointing at the same node.
现在，我的新节点AKA n和我显示的代码就是针对这个问题的，
Now that my new node, AKA n and the code I showed is pointing at this thing,
现在，我可以做一个switcheroo。
now I can do kind of a switcheroo.
因为我已经指向那里的最终目的地了。
Because I'm already pointing at the final destination there.
现在，我可以安全地删除它了，因为这是我的列表。
And now I can remove this safely, because this is my list.
这是n。
This is n.
因此，我有两个变量都指向
Therefore, I have variables pointing to both
我可以继续并正确插入。
and I can go ahead and insert that correctly.
长话短说，操作顺序很重要。
So long story short, order of operations matters.
因此，以图形方式，如果我像以前一样这样做，只需说list等于n，
So graphically, if I were to do this as before, just by saying list equals n,
如果这是n，这是列表，并且我先调整此箭头，
if this is n, and this is list, and I adjust this arrow first,
坏事将会发生。
bad things are going to happen.
确实，我们最终孤立了2、4和5，从而泄漏了大量
Indeed, we end up orphaning 2, 4, and 5, thereby leaking a significant amount
潜在的内存。
of memory potentially.
通常，泄漏任何内存都是不好的。
And leaking any memory, typically, is bad.
所以我不想那样做。
So I don't want to do that.
因此，让我们看一下正确的代码。
So let's look at the correct code.
正确的代码将从n开始
The correct code is going to be to start at n
并更新其下一个字段（这里的箭头）指向同一件事
and update its next field, this arrow here, to point at the same thing
就像列表最初指向的一样。
as the list was originally pointing at.
然后继续更新列表，这样他们两个
And then go ahead and update the list, such that both of them
当前指向重复。
are currently pointing in duplicate.
然后更新列表以指向新节点。
Then update the list to point to the new node.
因此，这次的代码与以前有些不同。
So, again, the code's a little different this time from before.
因为在我们将其添加到末尾之前，
Because before we kept adding it to the end,
或者我口头建议我们只是将其添加到开头。
or I proposed verbally that we just add it to the beginning.
实际上，我们确实在开始时就添加了它。
Here, we're adding it, indeed, at the beginning.
因此，实际步骤，实际代码略有不同。
And so the actual steps, the actual code, are a little bit different.
好吧，如果要分配3，让我们做一个最后的例子。
Well, let's do one final example, if we want to allocate 3.
好吧，我必须分配另一个节点3。
Well, I've got to malloc another node, the number 3.
假设最终出现在计算机内存中的某个位置。
Suppose that ends up somewhere in the computer's memory.
让我们继续前进，把这一个放在这里。
Let's go ahead and plop this one over here.
所以现在3就位了。
So now 3 is in place.
我现在该如何插入这个东西？
How do I now insert this thing?
好吧，类似于之前，我不想更新此指针
Well, similar to before, I'm not going to want to update this pointer
像这样去，然后把这个家伙插在这里。
and go like this and then plug this guy in over here.
因为现在我孤立了这两个节点。
Because now I've orphaned those two nodes.
因此，这又是错误的步骤。
So that, again is the wrong step.
当您位于链接列表的中间时，任何代码
When you're inside the middle of a linked list, any code
您写的要插入中间的内容，
that you write to insert into the middle,
如果您关心按排序顺序插入，则应首先进行更新。
if you care about inserting in sorted order, this should be updated first.
而且我应该作弊并指出同一件事，
And odds are I should kind of cheat and point this at the same thing,
即使目前只有一个物理插头。
even though there's only one physical plug at the moment.
因此，我们只是假装这是可行的。
So we'll just pretend that this is working.
好了
There we go.
现在我可以安全地说n和上一个节点
And now I can go ahead and safely say that n and the previous node
已经指出了他们应该去的地方。
are already pointing where they should be.
因此，现在我可以安全地拔下该插头了
So now it's safe for me to unplug this one
并继续更新此最终箭头以指向
and go ahead and update this final arrow to point
在正确位置的新节点上。
at the new node in the correct location.
因此，让我们再次在代码中看到它。
So let's see that in code again.
如果我去这里，我会以图形方式看到节点3在太空中的漂浮情况。
If I go here, I've got graphically the node 3 kind of floating in space.
我首先更新其下一个字段，使其也指向一式两份的4。
I first update its next field to point also at the 4 in duplicate.
然后，我将2更新为指向3。
Then, I update the 2 to point to the 3.
再次的目标是避免任何内存泄漏或孤立
The goal being, again, to avoid any leaking of memory or orphaning
的节点。
of nodes.
好吧，我们将把链表留在后面。
All right , we are about to leave linked lists behind.
因为你们当中有许多人已经注意到或可能想到过，
Because as multiple of you have noted or probably thought,
他们很好，但也许不是很好。
they're good, but maybe not great.
它们的优势在于它们是动态的，我可以添加到它们中，例如
They're good in that they are dynamic and I can add to them, as
如果我真的想在开头插入
by inserting at the beginning if I really want
并且不在乎排序顺序。
and don't care about sorted order.
但是他们仍然要做很多工作
But they're still a good amount of work to do
如果我想让它们保持排序并插入它们
if I want to keep them in sorted order and I insert them
在中间或最后。
in the middle or the end.
因为那就像，如果我保持n的大O
Because that's, like, Big O of n if I keep
遍历所有这些织补箭头。
traversing all of these darn arrows.
这样我们就具有了活力，但是我们不一定
So we get the dynamism, but we don't necessarily
获得性能提升。
get the performance increase.
但是我们从根本上为自己打开了一个全新的世界。
But we fundamentally have opened up a whole new world to ourselves.
现在，我们可以将这些数据结构拼接在一起
We can now stitch together these data structures
在内存中使用指针作为我们的线程（如果可以的话）。
in memory using pointers as our thread, if you will.
我们可以将内存用作画布，在其上绘制所需的任何值。
We can just use memory as a canvas, painting on it any values we want.
我们可以记住所有这些值在哪里。
And we can sort of remember where all of those values are.
但这确实是从左到右的非常单一的一维。
But this is indeed very single, one dimensional, left to right.
如果我们给自己第二个维度怎么办？
What if we give ourselves a second dimension?
如果我们开始思考不是从左到右，
What if we start thinking sort of not left to right,
而且从左到右，上，下。
but also left to right, up, down.
因此，这对计算机毫无意义。
So, again, this is meaningless to the computer.
计算机只是认为内存是字节0、1、2、3。
The computer just thinks of memory as being byte 0, 1, 2, 3.
但是我们人类可以想到这些数据结构
But we humans can kind of think of these data structures
更抽象一点，更简单一点。
a little more abstractly, a little more simply.
我们可以以熟悉的方式考虑它们，
And we can think about them in a way familiar,
也许对我们在现实世界中。
perhaps, to us in the real world.
树木，不是从地上生长的那么多的树木，
Trees, not the ones so much that grow from the ground,
但是如果您熟悉家谱。
but if you're familiar with family trees.
你可能有一个女家长或族长
Where you might have a matriarch or a patriarch
然后以图形方式将这些后代悬挂下来
and then sort of descendants hanging off of them graphically
在一张纸上，你可能在小学时做过的东西，
on a piece of paper, something you might have made in grade school,
例如。
for instance.
我们可以利用树形结构的想法
We can leverage this idea of a tree structure
根源是那种分支机构，分支机构和分支机构
that has a root that kind of branches and branches and branches
并从上到下生长。
and grows top to bottom.
因此，再一次，它更像是一棵家谱，而不是土壤中的一棵真实的树。
So, again, more like a family tree than an actual tree in the soil.
因此，对于树木，事实证明，关于树木的想法
So with trees, it turns out, this idea of a tree,
我们可以借鉴从链接列表中学到的一些经验教训。
we can take some of the lessons learned from linked lists.
但是我们可以重新获得数组的某些功能。
But we can gain back some of the features of arrays.
我们可以按照以下步骤进行操作。
And we can do that as follows.
考虑以下关于我们的定义
Consider the following definition of what we're
即将调用二叉搜索树。
about to call a binary search tree.
从第一周（第0周）开始，二进制搜索是一件非常好的事情。
Binary search being a very good thing from the first, Week 0.
现在，一棵树已成为新主意。
And a tree now being the new idea.
无论何时，这都是第0周，第1周，第2周的数组。
Here's an array from Week 0, Week 1, Week 2, whenever.
它的大小为7。
And it's of size 7.
并回想一下，如果已排序，我们可以对该数组应用二进制搜索。
And recall that if it's sorted, we can apply binary search to this array.
那太好了。
And that's great.
因为如果我们要搜索一个值，
Because if we want to search for a value,
我们可以开始在中间寻找。
we can start looking in the middle.
然后，我们可以在两者之间的中间位置向左或向右走。
Then we can go either left or right, halfway between each.
然后我们可以类似地向左或向右走。
And then we can similarly go left or right.
所以对排序数组进行二进制搜索是如此强大
So binary search on a sorted array was so powerful
因为它是log n的Big O，所以我们得出结论，
because it was Big O of log n, we've concluded,
一次又一次地遇到问题，
by just having and having and having the problem again and again,
一次又一次地将电话簿撕成两半。
tearing the phone book in half again and again and again.
但是二进制搜索的问题在于
But the problem with binary search is that it
要求您使用数组，以便您具有随机访问权限。
requires that you use an array so that you have random access.
您必须能够在恒定时间内索引数组
You have to be able to index into the array in constant time
使用简单的算术运算，例如括号0，括号n减1，括号n减1
using simple arithmetic, like bracket 0, bracket n minus 1, bracket n minus 1
除以2，得到中点。
divided by 2, to get the halfway point.
您必须能够对数据结构进行算术运算。
You have to be able to do arithmetic on the data structure.
我们只是建议摆脱这种随机访问
And we've just proposed getting rid of that random access
通过过渡到动态数据结构
by transitioning to a dynamic data structure
像是链表而不是数组。
like a linked list instead of an array.
但是，如果我们这样做呢？
But what if we do this?
如果您和我开始不在一个维度上思考，而是在两个维度上思考，该怎么办？
What if you and I start thinking not on one dimension, but on two dimensions?
如果我们改变思维方式像这样呢？
And what if we alter our thinking to be like this?
因此，可以将数组视为二维数组
So think of an array, perhaps, as being a two dimensional
不仅具有长度或长度，而且具有高度的结构。
structure that has not only with or length, but also height.
因此，我们似乎在视觉上保持了这种关系
And so we maintain, it seems, visually this relationship
所有这些值之间。
between all of these values.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
我们可以使用什么将所有这些值缝合在一起？
We can stitch all of these values together using what?
好吧，指针。
Well, pointers.
指针是我们可以使用的新的构建基块
Pointers are this new building block that we can use
将内存中的东西缝合在一起。
to stitch together things in memory.
如果内存中的内容是数字，那很好。
If the things in memory are numbers, that's fine.
它们是整数。
They're integers.
但是如果我们给它们多一点的内存，如果我们使用一个节点，
But if we throw a little more memory at them, if we use a node,
我们将整数包装在这样的节点中
and we kind of wrap the integer in a node such
该节点不仅包含数字，还包含指针，
that that node contains not only numbers but pointers,
我们可能会这样画一幅画，而不是
we could probably draw a picture like this, not
不像家谱，那里有根
unlike a family tree, where there's a root
可以这么说，在这种情况下，节点是最顶层，然后是子节点。
node, at the very top in this case, and then children, so to speak.
左孩子和右孩子，该定义一次又一次地重复。
Left child and right child, and that definition repeats again and again.
事实证明，计算机科学家确实按顺序使用了此数据结构
And it turns out the computer scientists do use this data structure in order
具有链接列表的动态性，其中
to have the dynamism of a linked list, where
您可以向树中添加越来越多的节点
you can add more and more nodes to the tree
只是增加越来越小的正方形
by just adding more and more squares even lower
比1、3、5和7。
than the 1, the 3, the 5, and the 7.
只需使用更多的指针就可以将它们缝合在一起，
And just use more pointers to kind of stitch them together, to sort of
如果可以的话，垂直，向下，向下，向下生长树。
grow the tree vertically, down, down, down, if you will.
但是优秀的计算机科学家会认识到，您不应该只是
But a good computer scientist would recognize that you shouldn't just
将这些数字放在随机的位置，否则，
put these numbers in random locations, otherwise,
你真的只是在浪费时间。
you're really just wasting your time.
您应该使用一些算法。
You should use some algorithm.
并注意。
And notice.
有人注意到这个树的图案吗？
Does anyone notice the pattern to this tree?
任何人都可以在聊天中进行口头表达或文字化吗
Can anyone verbalize or textualize in the chat
这棵树中的这七个节点显示了什么模式？
what pattern is manifest by these seven nodes in this tree?
它们不是随机排列的。
They're not randomly ordered.
他们是故意从左到右，从上到下订购的，
They're very deliberately ordered left to right, top to bottom,
以某种方式。
in a certain way.
任何人都可以指望这个东西的定义是什么？
Can anyone put their finger on what the definition of this thing is?
除此以外最重要的特征是什么
What is the most important characteristic besides it
像家谱一样被吸引？
just being drawn like a family tree?
[？格雷格？ ？]
[? Greg? ?]
听众：您把它们放在中间，
AUDIENCE: You have put in the middle of them,
在它们之上，您已经放置了中间数字。
on top of them you have put the middle number.
例如，在1到3之间，您放了2。
For example, between 1 and 3, you have put 2.
在5到7之间，您放置了6。
Between 5 and 7, you have put 6.
因此，在它们之上，您已放置了中间数字。
So on top of them, you have put the middle number.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
所有数字都有这种模式。
There's this pattern to all of the numbers.
在1和3之间是2。
Between 1 and 3 is 2.
在5到7之间是6。
Between 5 and 7 is 6.
2到6之间是4。
Between 2 and 6 is 4.
本质上，它甚至不必是中间数字。
And it doesn't even have to be the middle number, per se.
我可以概括一下并发表评论
I can generalize it a little bit and comment
也就是说，如果您在树中选择任何节点，可以这么说，
that, if you pick any node in this tree, so to speak,
它的左孩子将小于其价值，
its left child will be less than its value,
它的正确孩子的价值将大于其价值。
and its right child's will be greater than its value.
我们可以一次又一次地做到这一点。
And we can do that again and again.
所以这里是4。
So here's 4.
它的左孩子是2。
Its left child is 2.
小于。
That's less than.
这是4。
Here's 4.
对6岁的孩子来说是正确的。
It's right child to 6.
大于。
That's greater than.
我们可以再做一次。
We can do this again.
我们去2。
Let's go to 2.
它的左子项为1，该子项较小。
Its left child is 1, which is less.
它的正确孩子是3，甚至更多。
Its right child is 3, which is more.
6，其左子项为5，该子项更少。
6, its left child is 5, which is less.
6，它的正确的孩子是7，更多。
6, its right child is 7, which is more.
所以这实际上是，如果您不介意的话
And so this is actually, if you don't mind
上周的回顾性递归，这是一个递归定义。
the revisiting recursion from last week, this is a recursive definition.
这是一个递归数据结构。
This is a recursive data structure.
因此，不仅算法或函数
So it's not only algorithms or functions that
可以通过调用自己来递归。
can be recursive by calling themselves.
数据结构也可以是递归的。
A data structure can also be recursive.
毕竟这是什么东西？
After all, what is this thing?
这是一棵树，是的。
This is a tree, yes.
我会规定。
I'll stipulate.
但是从技术上讲，它是一棵有两棵树的树。
But it's technically a tree with two trees.
正确的？
Right?
这个第四个节点在技术上有两个孩子。
This node here, number four, technically has two children.
每个孩子本身就是一棵树。
And each of those children is itself a tree.
它是一棵较小的树。
It's a smaller tree.
但这是一次又一次的完全相同的定义。
But it's the same exact definition again and again.
每当我们看到递归数据结构时，
And any time we see a recursive data structure,
这实际上将是使用递归代码的机会，
it's actually going to be an opportunity to use recursive code,
我们待会儿会介绍。
which we'll take a look at in just a moment.
但是现在，请注意我们再次取得的成就，
But for now, notice what we've achieved again,
使用指针的动力，以便我们可以（如果需要），
the dynamism of using pointer so that we can, if we want,
向该树添加更多节点，例如通过将它们串起来
add more nodes to this tree, as by stringing them
沿着底部以正确的顺序排列。
along the bottom in the correct order.
但是，我们保留了二进制搜索的重要顺序，
And yet, we've preserved an important order for binary search,
也就是这种数据结构的正式名称，二进制搜索树，
AKA, the formal name of this data structure, binary search tree,
通过确保左孩子总是更少，右孩子总是更多。
by making sure that left child is always less, right child is always more.
因为现在，我们可以更有效地搜索此内容。
Because now, we can go about searching this thing more efficiently.
如何？
How?
好吧，如果我想搜索数字3，该怎么办？
Well, if I want to search for the number 3, what do I do?
好吧，我从树的开头开始。
Well, I start at the beginning of the tree.
就像链接列表一样，您从链接列表的开头开始。
Just like with a linked list, you start at the beginning of the linked list.
因此，从树的根部开始，树[[？总是。 ？]
So with the tree, you start with the root of the tree [? always. ?]
假设我要搜索3。
Suppose I want to search for 3.
好吧，我该怎么办？
Well, what do I do?
好吧，3明显小于4。
Well, 3 is obviously less than 4.
因此，就像在第0周将电话簿撕成两半一样，
So just like in Week 0 where I tore the phone book in half,
您现在可以将其砍倒一半。
you can now think of this as chopping down half of the tree.
因为您知道3（如果存在）绝对不是
Because you know 3, if it's present, is definitely not
将会在这里的任何地方，因此我们可以将注意力集中在这里。
going to be anywhere over here, so we can focus our attention down here.
这是数字2。
Here's the number 2.
这是另一棵树。
This is another tree.
如果愿意的话，它只是一个较小的子树。
It's just a smaller subtree, if you will.
我如何找到数字3？
How do I find the number 3?
好吧，我向右看，因为它大于。
Well, I look to the right because it's greater than.
繁荣，我找到了。
And boom, I found it.
但是相比之下，假设我正在搜索数字8。
But by contrast, suppose I were searching for the number 8.
我将从这里开始。
I would start here.
我会看这里。
I would look here.
然后得出结论，不，它不存在。
And then conclude, no, it's not there.
但是，每次我搜索那个8时，
But, again, every time I search for that 8,
我忽略了树的一半，子树的一半，依此类推。
I'm ignoring this half of the tree, this half of the subtree, and so forth.
这样看来，您将要实现，
So you're going to achieve, it would seem,
从第0周开始，我们便看到了同样的力量和表现。
the same kind of power, the same kind of performance as we saw from Week 0.
那么，我们如何将这个想法转化为代码呢？
So how do we translate this idea now into code?
我们已经有了所有的构建基块。
We have all the building blocks already.
让我继续提议，而不是节点
Let me go ahead and propose that, instead of the node
我们以前使用过的链表，看起来像这样，有一个数字和一个
we used before for a linked list, which looked like this, with a number and one
称为下一个的指针
pointer called next--
但是，同样，我们可以将这些东西称为“任何东西”-让我们继续
but, again, we could have called those things anything-- let's go ahead
不仅为数字腾出空间，而且为两个指针腾出空间，一个
and make room for not just a number, but also two pointers, one
我叫左，我叫右。
that I'll call left, one that I'll call right.
这些都仍然是指向结构节点的指针。
Both of those is still a pointer to a struct node.
和以前一样，但现在我有两个指针，而不是一个
So same terminology as before, but now I have two pointers instead of one
这样一来，您可以从概念上指向左侧并指向较小的
so that one can conceptually point to the left and point to a smaller
子树。
subtree.
可以指向右边并指向更大的子树。
One can point to the right and point to a larger subtree.
那么，我们如何实现类似于二进制搜索的东西呢？
So how do we go about implementing something like binary search?
好吧，让我们实际看一些代码。
Well, let's actually see some code.
这就是递归真正变得很酷的地方。
And this is where recursion really gets kind of cool.
我们在构建[时会强制使用它吗？ Maro的？]金字塔与递归。
We kind of forced it when building [? Maro's ?] pyramid with recursion.
就像，是的，您可以做到。
Like, yeah, you can do it.
是的，我声称金字塔是递归的物理结构
And yes, the pyramid was, I claimed, a recursive physical structure
或游戏中的虚拟结构。
or virtual structure in the game.
但是有了数据结构和指针，现在递归确实开始崭露头角了。
But with data structures and pointers, now recursion really starts to shine.
因此，让我们考虑一下。
So let's consider this.
如果我用C声明一个函数，其作用是生命
If I declare a function in C whose purpose in life
是在树上搜索数字，按照定义，
is to search a tree for a number, it's going to, by definition,
从根向下搜索。
search from the root on down.
我们如何实现呢？
How do we implement this?
好吧，我将建议的功能是返回布尔值。
Well, my function, I'll propose, is going to return a bool.
对或错，数字在树中，是或否。
True or false, the number is in the tree, yes or no.
它需要两个参数，一个指向节点的指针，即AKA树。
It's going to take two arguments, a pointer to a node, AKA tree.
我可以称其为root或其他名称。
I could call it root or anything else.
这将需要一个数字，这是
And it's going to take a number, which is
我关心的数字，无论是4还是6或8或其他任何数字。
the number I care about, whether it's four or six or eight or anything else.
那么，我的第一段代码将是什么？
So what's going to be my first chunk of code?
好吧，让我做我不断讲道的最佳实践。
Well, let me do the best practice that I keep preaching.
每当您处理指针时，请检查是否为空
Any time you're dealing with pointers, check for null
这样您的程序就不会冻结或崩溃，也不会发生坏事。
so that your program doesn't freeze or crash or bad thing happens.
因为谁知道？
Because who knows?
也许您会偶然或故意
Maybe you will accidentally or maybe intentionally
在空指针上传递此函数，因为没有树。
pass this function on null pointer, because there's no tree.
也许你会搞砸。
Maybe you'll screw up.
只要您的代码是自卫的，就可以了。
And that's OK, so long as your code is self-defensive.
因此，请务必检查指针是否为空。
So always check pointers for null.
如果是这样，如果树为空，即那里没有树，
If so, if the tree is null, that is, there is no tree there,
显然，这个数字不存在。
obviously, the number is not present.
因此，您只需返回false。
So you just return false.
可以这么说，这是我们的基本情况之一。
So that's one of our base cases, so to speak.
否则，如果您要查找的数字小于树的自身数字，
Else, if the number you're looking for is less than the tree's own number--
因此，同样，此箭头符号表示作为树的树，它是一个节点*，
so, again, this arrow notation means take tree, which is a node *,
所以拿这个指针。
so take this pointer.
转到实际节点。
Go there to the actual node.
并查看其自己的数字字段。
And look in its own number field.
如果您要从参数中寻找数字
If the number you're looking for from the argument
小于树自己的数字字段中的数字，
is less than the number in the tree's own number field,
好吧，这意味着您想离开。
well, that means that you want to go left.
而在电话簿中，我走到电话簿的左侧，
And whereas in the phone book, I went to the left of the phone book,
在这里，我们将转到左侧的子树。
here we're going to go to the left subtree.
但是，如何搜索子树？
But how do I search a subtree?
在这里，树是递归数据结构很重要。
Here's where it's important that a tree is a recursive data structure.
与以前一样，树是具有新根节点的两个子树。
A tree is two subtrees with a new root node, as before.
因此，我已经有了可以搜索较小树的代码。
So I already have code via which I can search a smaller tree.
所以我可以说搜索左侧的子树，
So I can just say search the left subtree,
如此处所示，这意味着从当前节点开始
as expressed here, which means start at the current node
并转到左孩子并传递相同的数字。
and go to the left child and pass in the same number.
人数没有变化。
The number is not changing.
但是树越来越小。
But the tree is getting smaller.
我已经用代码有效地将树切成了两半。
I've effectively, in code, chopped the tree in half.
我忽略了右边的那一半。
And I'm ignoring the right half.
我将返回任何答案。
And I'm returning whatever that answer is.
否则，如果我关心的数字更大
Otherwise, if the number I care about is greater
比当前节点中的数字多，请执行相反的操作。
than the number in the current node, do the opposite.
搜索正确的子树，并输入相同的数字。
Search the right subtree, passing in the same number.
因此，就像电话簿一样，
So, again, just like with the phone book,
它越来越小？
it kept getting smaller and smaller?
在这里，我继续搜索越来越小的子树。
Here I keep searching a smaller and smaller subtree.
因为我不断砍掉左或右的分支
Because I keep chopping off branches left or right as
我从上到下。
I go from top to bottom.
最后一种情况。
There's one final case.
让我把这个扔给小组。
And let me toss this out to the group.
还有第四种情况。
There's a fourth case.
无论是文字还是文字方式，在这里我还要检查什么？
Verbally or textually, what else should I be checking for and doing here?
我为最后一种情况留了余地。
I've left room for one final case.
布莱恩：有人建议树本身就是数字。
BRIAN: A few people are suggesting if the tree itself is the number.
DAVID MALAN：如果树本身包含数字，是的。
DAVID MALAN: If the tree itself contains the number, yeah.
因此，如果树中的数字等于
So if the number in the tree equals equals
我要查找的数字，继续，只有在这种情况下，才返回true。
the number I'm looking for, go ahead and, only in this case, return true.
这就是代码再次出现的地方-
And so this is where the code, again, gets kind of--
相反，递归会有点儿弯腰。
recursion, rather, gets a little mind-bending.
我在这里只有虚假的东西，在这里是真实的。
I only have false up here, true here.
但不要在这两个中间的两个分支中的任何一个中使用双关语（如果您愿意的话）。
But not in either of these middle two branches, no pun intended, if you will.
但是没关系。
But that's OK.
因为我的代码以这样的方式设计：如果我搜索左子树
Because my code is designed in such a way that if I search the left subtree
那里什么也没有，就像我在树的叶子上，
and there's nothing there, like, literally I'm at the leaf of the tree,
可以这么说，那么它将返回false。
so to speak, then it's going to return false.
这样很好
So that's fine.
就像，如果我搜索数字8。
That's, like, if I search for the number 8.
它甚至不在树上。
It's not even in the tree.
我只会意识到，一旦我跌落到树的尽头
I'm only going to realize that once I fall off the end of the tree
看看，哎呀，null
and see, oops, null.
我将返回false。
I'll just return false.
但是，如果我一路上看到数字，我将返回true。
But if I ever see the number along the way, I will return true.
还有这两个内部搜索请求，这两个递归搜索请求，
And these two inner calls to search, these two recursive calls to search,
就像在推卸责任。
are just kind of like passing the buck.
除了自己回答是非，
Instead of answering true or false themselves,
他们将返回较小问题的答案
they're returning whatever the answer to a smaller question
是分别搜索左或右树。
is by searching the left or right tree instead respectively.
所以，这又是递归开始的地方
So, again, this is where recursion starts
变得不是真正地被迫甚至不一定被迫地被迫，
to get not really forced or even necessarily really as forced,
但确实是适当的。
but really as appropriate.
当您的数据本身是递归的时，则将递归作为一种编码技术
When your data is itself recursive, then recursion in as a coding technique
真的很闪耀。
really rather shines.
所以，如果最终，我们有-哦[？ ？]次优化。
So if ultimately, we have-- oh, [? an ?] minor optimization.
正如我们可能在第0周注意到Scratch一样，
As we might have noted in Week 0 with Scratch,
当然，我们不需要显式检查数量是否相等。
we, of course, don't need to explicitly check if the number is equal.
我们可以摆脱最后一个条件，并假设它不为null
We can get rid of that last condition and just assume that if it's not null
它不在左边，也不在右边，
and it's not to the left and it's not to the right,
我们必须站在它上面。
we must be standing right on top of it.
因此，我们在那里才返回true。
And so we just return true there.
好吧，让我在这里总结一下图片。
Well, let me summarize the picture here.
现在这是一个二维数据结构。
This is now a two dimensional data structure.
它比二维链表更好，因为它现在是二维的。
And it's sort of better than a linked list in that now it's two dimensions.
我获得了二进制搜索，这非常了不起，所以
I gain back binary search, which is amazing, so
只要我按照此二叉搜索树定义将数据按排序顺序保留即可。
long as I keep my data in sorted order per this binary search tree definition.
但是我肯定已经付出了代价。
But I've surely paid a price.
正确的？
Right?
到目前为止，没有什么绝对比我们的故事中的其他任何事情更好。
Nothing is absolutely better than anything else in our story thus far.
那么，一棵树的缺点是什么？
So what is the downside of a tree?
我在这里秘密或不秘密地支付了什么价格，
What price have I secretly or not so secretly paid here,
在宣扬树木的优点时？
while preaching the upsides of trees?
而且，答案通常是在这种情况下的空间或时间，
And, again, the answer is often in this context sort of space, or time,
或开发人员的时间，金钱或个人或实物的某些资源，
or developer time, or money, or some resource, personal, or physical,
或真实世界。
or real world.
是的。
Yeah.
怎么过[听不清]？
How about over to [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：所以我认为插入不再是固定的时间。
AUDIENCE: So I think that inserting is no longer constant time.
而且我想我们需要更多的内存。
And I guess we need more memory.
您需要记忆来[？排序？]两个指针，而不是一次。
You need memory to [? sort ?] two pointers instead of one this time.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
似乎插入不再是固定时间。
It seems insertion is no longer constant time.
因为如果我需要保留排序的顺序，就不能仅将其放在最前面。
Because if I need to preserve sorted order, I can't just put it at the top.
我不能一直压低其他一切
I can't just keep pushing everything else down
因为事情可能会变得混乱。
because things might get out of order.
在这种情况下，它会[？似乎。 ？]或者，即使我维持订单，
In that case, it would [? seem. ?] Or rather, even if I maintain the order,
它可能会变得很长且很刺耳。
it might kind of get very long and stringy.
例如，如果我加上另一个数字，另一个数字，
If I add, for instance, another number, another number,
我一直把它塞在顶部
and I keep jamming it at the top, I probably
如果可以的话，需要保持平衡。
need to kind of keep things balanced, if you will.
是的，更重要的是，我立刻
And yeah, the bigger point, too, is that immediately I'm
使用两倍多的指针。
using twice as many pointers.
所以现在我的节点变得比这些东西还要大。
So now my node is getting even bigger than these things.
现在，我不仅有空间容纳数字和指针，
I now have room for not only a number and a pointer,
但是还有另一个指针，这当然会花费我更多的空间。
but another pointer, which is, of course, going to cost me more space.
同样，在那儿进行权衡。
Again, so a trade off there.
让我们继续问这里的小组，
And let's go ahead and ask the group here,
当涉及插入时，为什么我们暂时不考虑
when it comes to insertion, why don't we consider for a moment what
插入的运行时间可能是插入二进制搜索时的时间
the running time of insertion might be when inserting into a binary search
树。
tree.
如果您想像往常一样提取网址，请让我继续
If you'd like to pull up the URL as always, let me go ahead
并提出这一点。
and present this one.
插入二叉搜索树的运行时间是多少？
What's the running time of inserting into a binary search tree?
因此，如果您要将数字0插入该树，
So if you want to insert the number 0 into that tree,
如果您想插入数字8，或者介于两者之间或更大的数字
if you want to insert the number 8, or anything in between or bigger
或更小，这里的答案是什么？
or smaller, what are the answers here?
因此，获得最高酒吧的胜利并不算太大。
So not quite as big of a victory for the tallest bar.
大约60％的人认为log n。
About 60% of you think log n.
坦率地说，那里的良好本能是如此
And the good instincts there, frankly, are so
那将是正确的答案。
that is going to be the right answer.
这是正确的本能。
And that's kind of the right instinct.
每当您进行二分查找时，您说的都是对数的几率。
Anytime you have binary search, odds are you're talking something logarithmic.
但是我们也看到了用n log n进行分治和合并排序，
But we've also seen divide and conquer and merge sort with n log n,
因此约有10％的人也这么认为。
so not unreasonable that about 10% of you think that, too.
n平方实际上是不好的。
n squared would actually be bad.
因此，n平方是迄今为止我们所见过的最糟糕的时期。
So n squared is, like, the worst of the times we've seen thus far.
这表明一棵树比一个链表还要糟，
And that would suggest that a tree is even worse than a linked list,
比数组还差
is even worse than an array.
值得庆幸的是，我们还没有到那时。
And thankfully, we're not at that point.
但是根据某些假设，它的确是log n。
But it's indeed log n, based on certain assumptions.
那为什么呢？
So why is that?
因此，如果我们考虑一下刚才的那棵树，
So if we consider the tree from a moment ago,
看起来有点像这样。
it looked a little something like this.
插入树中涉及什么？
And what is involved in inserting into a tree?
好吧，假设我要插入数字8。
Well, suppose I want to insert the number 8.
好吧，我从这里开始。
Well, I start here.
它显然属于右图，因为8更大。
And it obviously belongs to the right because 8 is bigger.
我去这里
I go here.
它属于右边，因为8更大。
It belongs to the right because 8 is bigger.
我去这里
I go here.
它属于右边，因为8更大。
It belongs to the right, because 8 is bigger.
因此，将在此处某处创建一个新节点。
And so a new node is going to be created somewhere down here.
即使它不能显示在屏幕上，我也可以绝对调用malloc。
And even though it doesn't fit on the screen, I could absolutely call malloc.
我可以更新几个指针。
I could update a couple of pointers.
繁荣时期，我们在树上添加了第八个节点。
And boom, we've added an eighth node to the tree.
因此，如果我花了很多步骤，从根目录1、2、3开始，
So if it took me that many steps, starting at the root, 1, 2, 3,
如何将其概括为Big O表示法？
how do I generalize this into Big O notation?
好吧，二叉搜索树，如果您像这样很好地布置它们，
Well, a binary search tree, if you lay it out nice and prettily like this,
如果您愿意的话，该二叉搜索树的高度会很好并且平衡，
nice and balanced if you will, the height of that binary search tree,
事实证明，它将是n的对数。
it turns out, is going to be log of n.
如果n是故事中的总节点数（现在为7或8），则
If n is the number of total nodes, 7 or 8 now in the story, then
n的对数底数2将是树的高度。
log base 2 of n is going to be the height of the tree.
因此，如果采用n个节点，n个数字，并且
So if you take n nodes, n numbers, and you kind of
以一种很好的排序方式平衡它们，总高度将为log n。
balance them in this nice sorted way, the total height is going to be log n.
那么插入的运行时间是多少？
So what is the running time of insert?
好了，insert的运行时间等于多少
Well, the running time of insert is equivalent to how many
您是否需要执行以下步骤才能找到其中的位置
steps does it take you to find the location into which
新号码属于？
the new number belongs?
好吧，那是1,2,3。
Well, that's 1, 2, 3.
事实证明，以2为底的对数确实是3。
And as it turns out, log base 2 of 8 is indeed 3.
因此，在这种情况下，数学运算实际上是完美的。
So the math actually works out perfectly in this case.
有时，可能会有一些舍入错误。
Sometimes, there might be a little rounding error.
但总的来说，这确实将是log n的大O。
But in general it's going to indeed be Big O of log n.
但是，如果我们有点草率呢？
But what if we get a little sloppy?
如果我们有点草率并且开始
What if we get a little sloppy and we start
插入使我们有些倒霉的节点，如果愿意的话？
inserting nodes that are giving us a bit of bad luck, if you will?
举例来说，假设我继续进行-让
So for instance, suppose that I go ahead-- and let
我在这里忙着做一些事。
me do something on the fly here.
假设我继续插入数字1，数字2，
Suppose that I go ahead and insert the number 1, the number 2,
和数字3，这样逻辑上就会发生这种情况。
and the number 3 such that this is what logically happens.
这符合二叉搜索树的定义。
This adheres to the definition of a binary search tree.
如果这是根源，则为1。
If this is the roots, it's 1.
它没有左子树，这绝对不是问题，
It has no left subtree, and that's not strictly a problem,
因为这里没有什么违反搜索树的定义的。
because there's nothing violating the definition of a search tree here.
那里什么都没有。
There's just nothing there.
2在正确的位置。
2 is in the right place.
3在正确的位置。
3 is in the right place.
因此，从技术上讲，这也是二叉搜索树。
So this, too, technically is a binary search tree.
但这是一个极端的情况，一个反常的情况，如果您愿意的话，
But it's a bit of a corner case, a perverse case, if you will,
您插入事物的方式最终在二进制搜索树中最终到达的位置
where the way you inserted things ended up in the binary search tree actually
如果要在聊天中发出声音，您会说类似什么？
resembling more of a what, would you say, if you want to chime in the chat?
还有Brian，如果您想中继一下？
And Brian, if you might want to relay?
布莱恩：一些人说它看起来像一个链表。
BRIAN: A few people are saying it looks like a linked list.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
因此，即使我已将其自上而下绘制，
So even though I've drawn it sort of top down,
所以在第二维上，那就是
so in the sort of second dimension, that's
真的只是艺术家的表演。
really just an artist's rendition.
该树是二进制搜索树。
This tree is a binary search tree.
但这也是一种链表。
But it's kind of sort of also a linked list.
因此，即使是意图最明确的数据
And so even the most well-intentioned data
输入不幸的东西，运气不好或设计不好的结构，
structures, given unfortunate inputs or some bad luck or some bad design,
可能只是偶然地演变成不同的数据结构。
could devolve into a different data structure just by chance.
因此，即使有这些值，也有解决此问题的方法。
So there's a way to solve this though, even with these values.
当我插入1、2、3时，我可以考虑这种不正常的情况
When I insert 1, 2, 3, I could allow for this perverse situation
在这里它变得又长又弦，这时一切都是n的大O。
where it just gets long and stringy, at which point everything is Big O of n.
这只是一个链表。
It's just a linked list.
它恰好是对角绘制的，而不是左右绘制的。
It just happens to be drawn diagonally instead of left right.
但是，有人能直观地看到解决方案吗？
But does anyone see a solution intuitively?
没有代码，没有正式语言，
Not in terms of code, no formal language,
但是这里有一个解决方案，以确保该树具有1、2、3
but there is a solution here to make sure that this tree with 1, 2, 3
首先不会变得冗长而紧张。
does not get long and stringy in the first place.
您可以怎么做才能解决这个问题？
What might you do instead to solve this?
布莱恩：聊天中有几个人在暗示
BRIAN: A few people in the chat are suggesting
您应该在树的顶部将2设为新的根节点。
you should make 2 the new root node at the top of the tree.
DAVID MALAN：因此，如果我改为将2设为新的根节点，让我继续
DAVID MALAN: So if I instead make 2 the new root node, let me go ahead
并迅速进行模拟。
and mock this up real quickly.
一会儿，我会透露我认为你刚刚说过的话。
And in a moment, I'll reveal what I think you've just verbalized.
如果相反，我可以确保在插入这些节点时
What if instead, I make sure that when inserting these nodes
我不是天真地一直走到右边，右边，右边吗？
I don't naively just keep going to the right, to the right, to the right?
我行使一些判断力。
I exercise some judgment.
如果我注意到，也许是我的数据结构，我的树
And if I notice, maybe, that my data structure, my tree
变得有点长而刺鼻，也许我
is getting kind of long and stringy, maybe I
应该有点旋转，使用第二个维度
should kind of rotate it around, using that second dimension for real
这样我就改变了根源。
so that I change what the root is.
而且，我们不会遍历执行此操作的代码。
And we won't go through the code for doing this.
但是事实证明这是解决方案。
But it turns out this is the solution.
这是正确的直觉。
That is exactly the right intuition.
如果您在数据结构上参加更高级别的课程
If you take a higher level class on data structures
和专门用于计算机科学的算法，
and algorithms specifically in computer science,
您将学习诸如AVL树或红色，黑色树之类的树，
you'll study trees like AVL trees, or red, black trees,
这是不同类型的树数据结构。
which are different types of tree data structures.
他们在其中内置了用于转移事物的算法
They kind of have built into them the algorithms for kind of shifting things
根据需要确保在插入或删除时
as needed to make sure that as you insert, or maybe as you delete,
您会不断地重新平衡树。
you constantly rebalance the tree.
长话短说，这样做可能会花费您一些额外的时间。
And long story short, doing so might cost you a little extra time.
但是，如果您有很多数据，请保持平衡和对数
But if you've got a lot of data, keeping that thing balanced and logarithmic
可以这么说，在高度上线性不长而严格，
in height, so to speak, and not long and stringy in the linear in height,
根据您的应用程序，可能会节省您的时间
it's probably, depending on your application, going to save you
总的来说，时间很多。
quite a bit of time overall.
因此，我们可以说将其插入平衡的二进制搜索树中
So we might say that insert into a balanced binary search tree
确实是log n的BigO。
is indeed Big O of log n.
但这是确保您保持平衡的条件。
But that is conditional on you making sure that you keep it balanced.
这将是比我们今天要讨论的更多的代码，
And that's going to be more code than we'll go into today,
但确实是一个可能的设计决策。
but indeed, a possible design decision.
好吧，那么现在关于树和二进制搜索树的任何问题，
All right, any questions then on now trees and binary search trees,
特别是？
in particular?
几周前，我们开始使用阵列。
We started with arrays a few weeks ago.
现在，我们有了链表，这些链表很好，更好，但不是很好。
We've now got linked lists, which are good, better, but not great.
对于树木来说，这似乎很棒，但是，这始终是一个权衡。
To trees, which seemed maybe to be great but, again, it's always a trade off.
他们给我们增加了空间。
They're costing us more space.
但我敢打赌，我们可以继续缝合其中的一些想法
But I bet we can continue to stitch some of these ideas
一起用于其他结构。
together for other structures still.
布莱恩，什么出色的？
Brian, anything outstanding?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
一个问题来了，如果有的话为什么会成问题，
One question came in as to why it's a problem if you have,
像是1、2和3都在右侧按一个顺序排列？
like, the 1, and the 2, and the 3 all in just one sequence on the right side?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这是一个非常好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, a really good question.
为什么会出问题呢？
Why is it a problem?
也许不是。
Maybe it isn't.
如果您没有非常大的数据集，而您
If you don't have a very large data set and you
老实说，结构中没有太多价值，谁在乎？
don't have many values in the structure, honestly, who cares?
如果这是三个要素，那么绝对不在乎。
If it's three elements, definitely don't care.
如果是10个元素，如果是1000个元素，那么，如果您的计算机足够快，
If it's 10 elements, if it's 1,000, heck, if your computer is fast enough,
可能有上百万个元素，但这没什么大不了的。
there might be a million elements, and it's not a big deal.
但是如果是200万或10亿个元素，
But if it's two million elements or a billion elements,
那么这完全取决于您正在建立的业务是什么？
then it totally depends, again, on what is the business you're building?
您正在编写什么应用程序？
What is the application you're writing?
您的数据有多大？
How big is your data?
您的计算机有多快或多慢？
How fast or how slow is your computer?
最终可能很重要。
It might very well matter ultimately.
确实，当我们几个星期看到一些算法时
And indeed, when we've seen some of our algorithms a couple of weeks
以前，当我们比较气泡排序和选择排序以及合并排序时，
ago, when we compared bubble sort and selection sort and merge sort,
即使这些时间属于不同的运行时间类别，
even though those were in a different category of running times,
n记录n和n的平方，只需回想一下明显的差异即可。
n log n and n squared, just recall the appreciable difference.
在搜索上下文中，n的对数比n更好。
Log of n in the context of searching is way better than n.
因此，如果您的数据结构演变成冗长而冗长的内容，
So if your data structure is devolving into something long and stringy,
回想一下，就像搜索一本电话簿共一千页。
recall that's, like, searching a phone book a thousand total pages.
但是二进制搜索并不让它变得冗长而冗长
But binary search and not letting it get long and stringy
给您10个步骤，而不是1,000个步骤
gives you, like, 10 steps instead of 1,000
步骤以搜索相同的页面。
steps in order to search those same pages.
因此，即使在第0周，我们也看到了明显的差异
So, again, even in Week 0 we saw the appreciable difference
在这些不同类别的运行时间之间。
between these different categories of running times.
好吧，让我们看看我们是否可能
All right, well, let's see if we can't maybe
兼顾两全其美。
take some of the best of both worlds.
到目前为止，我们再次看到了数组。
Thus far, again, we've seen arrays.
我们已经看到了链表。
We've seen linked lists.
我们看过树木。
We've seen trees.
如果我们在这里有点弗兰肯斯坦，把东西捣碎怎么办
What if we kind of get a little Frankenstein here and mash things
在一起，并采取这些东西的最好的功能
together and take sort of the best features of these things
并建立更大的东西。
and build up something grander.
实际上，我感觉像是数据结构的圣杯
In fact, I feel like the Holy Grail of a data structure
证明和插入不是n，n的Big O的东西，
would be something for which cert and insertion aren't n, Big O of n,
不是log n的BigO。
aren't Big O of log n.
但是，如果有数据结构，那会不会令人惊讶
But wouldn't it be amazing if there's a data structure
那里的运行时间就像恒定时间，Big O为1。
out there where the running time is like constant time, Big O of 1.
那是圣杯。
That's the Holy Grail.
如果您可以通过这种方式巧妙地布置计算机的内存
If you can cleverly lay out your computer's memory in such a way
如果您要搜索或插入一个值，繁荣，就可以了。
that if you want to search for or insert a value, boom, you're done.
动臂，您已完成，并且没有任何线性或对数运行时间。
Boom, you're done, and none of this linear or logarithmic running time.
因此，让我们看看我们是否无法实现这一目标。
So let's see if we can't pursue that goal.
让我建议我们介绍一个称为哈希表的主题。
Let me propose that we introduce this topic called hash tables.
哈希表是另一种数据结构
Hash table is another data structure that's
本质上是链表的数组。
essentially an array of linked lists.
再说一次，这是科学怪人怪物
So, again, it's this Frankenstein monster,
从而我们最终将数组与链表结合在一起。
whereby we've combined arrays ultimately with linked list.
让我们看看这是如何完成的。
Let's see how this is done.
让我建议我们首先从大小为26的数组开始。
Let me propose that we first start with an array of size 26.
我将开始垂直绘制数组，只是因为它
And I'm going to start drawing my arrays vertically, just because it
可以通过图片更好地完成工作。
sort of works out better pictorially.
但是，无论如何，这些都是艺术家的作品。
But, again, these are all artist's renditions, anyway.
即使我们总是从左到右绘制数组，这完全是任意的。
Even though we always draw arrays left to right, that's completely arbitrary.
因此，现在我要开始，将我的数组从上到下绘制。
So I'm going to start, for now, drawing my array top to bottom.
并假设我现在关心的数据结构
And suppose that the data structure I care about now
这些数字将变得更加有趣。
is going to be even more interesting the numbers.
假设我要存储诸如名称之类的东西，如字典或名称
Suppose I want to store things like names, like dictionaries, or names
就像手机中的联系人一样。
like contacts in your phone.
如果您想跟踪所有认识的人，
If you want to keep track of all the people you know,
如果它不需要线性时间或对数时间，那将很棒
it would be great if it doesn't take linear time or logarithmic time
找人。
to find people.
相反，恒定的时间似乎会更好。
Instead, constant time would seem to be even better.
因此，这是一个数组，例如，大小为26。
So here's an array, for instance, size 26.
我是故意提出的。
And I proposed that deliberately.
在英语中，有26个字母，从A到Z。
In English, there's 26 letters, A through Z. So
让我们考虑位置0是A。位置25是Z。
let's consider location 0 is A. Location 25 is Z.
如果我现在开始将所有朋友插入新手机，
And if I now go and start inserting all of my friends into my new phone,
放入通讯录应用程序中，我可以将它们放在哪里？
into the contacts application, where might I put them?
好吧，让我继续执行此操作。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续考虑一下这些元素，分别是0到25，
Let me go ahead and think of each of these elements as, again, 0 through 25,
或实际上是A到Z。
or really A through Z.
然后，在我将新朋友或联系人插入手机后，
And let me, upon inserting a new friend or contact into my phone,
让我将其放置在与名称本身有一定关系的位置。
let me put them into a location that has some relationship with the name itself.
我们不仅要一开始就把它们放在首位。
Let's not just start putting them at the very beginning.
我们不必将它们本身按字母顺序排列。
Let's not necessarily put them alphabetically per se.
我们实际上将它们放置在此数组中的特定位置，而不仅仅是顶部
Let's actually put them at a specific location in this array, not just top
到底部，但在特定条目处。
to bottom, but at a specific entry.
因此，假设我要添加到我的联系人中的第一个人是Albus。
So suppose the first person I want to add to my contacts is Albus.
好吧，我提议，因为阿不思以A开头，
Well, I'm going to propose that because Albus starts with an A,
他将要进入A位置，因此是该数组中的第一个条目。
he is going to go into the A location, so the very first entry in this array.
假设我接下来要添加Zacharias。
Suppose I next want to add Zacharias.
好吧，他的名字以Z开头。所以他要去的最后一个位置。
Well, his name starts with Z. So he's going to go in the very last location.
所以，我再次跳来跳去。
So, again, I'm jumping around.
我从0降到25。
I went from 0 to 25.
但这是一个数组，我可以在恒定时间内做到这一点。
But it's an array, and I can do that in constant time.
您可以使用方括号随机索引到任何元素。
You can randomly index to any element using square brackets.
所以这都是恒定的时间。
So this is both constant time.
我不必只是把他放在阿不思之后。
I don't have to just put him right after Albus.
我可以把他放在我想要的任何地方。
I can put him wherever I want.
假设第三人称赫敏。
Suppose the third person is Hermione.
好吧，我要把她放在位置H。为什么？
Well, I'm going to put her at location H. Why?
因为我可以进行数学运算，并且可以算出H。好吧，
Because I can do the math, and I can figure out H. OK,
我可以立即跳到那个字母。
I can just jump immediately to that letter of the alphabet.
反过来，多亏了ASCII并做了一些算术运算，
And in turn, thanks to ASCII and doing a bit of arithmetic,
我也将其转换为数字。
I convert that to a number as well.
所以她以0、1、2、3、4、5、6、7结束
So she ends up at 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
因为H最终映射到第八个字符或位置7。
because H ends up mapping to the eighth character, or location 7.
好的。
All right.
还有谁？
Who else?
所有这些其他人最终都出现在我的通讯录中。
All these other people end up in my address book.
因此，它们都散布了。
And so they're all spread out.
我没有多达26个朋友。
I don't have as many as 26 friends.
因此，那里的数据存在一些差距。
So there's some gaps in the data there.
但是我适合所有人。
But I fit everyone here.
但是可能有问题。
But there might be a problem.
您也许可以看到这种情况的到来。
And you can perhaps see this coming.
到目前为止，我有点幸运。
Thus far, I've kind of gotten lucky.
而且我只知道名字以唯一的字母开头的人。
And I've only know people whose names are-- uniquely start with a letter.
但是当我在学校遇到一个人并将他们添加到我的联系人中后，
But as soon as I meet someone at school and I add them to my contacts,
好吧，例如，现在哈利必须去同一地点。
well, now Harry, for instance, has to go in the same location.
如果我要同时存储赫敏和哈利，那么这是一个问题，
Now this is a problem if I want to store both Hermione and Harry,
因为它们的名称都以H开头。
because their names both start with H.
但是，再说一次，如果它是一个数组，那绝对是一个破坏交易的事情。
But, again if it's an array, it's absolutely a deal breaker.
到那时，一切都崩溃了。
At that point, all things break down.
因为可以，所以我可以增加阵列。
Because I could, yes, grow the array.
但是，如果我增加数组，那么它的大小为27。
But if I grow the array, then it's size 27.
然后，就像，我怎么知道那时候什么字母是什么数字？
And then it's, like, how do I know what number is what letter at that point?
它只是变成了一个烂摊子。
It just devolves into a complete mess.
但是如果我借用链表的想法，如果我
But if I borrow the idea of a linked list, what if I
使我的数组为链接列表的数组？
make my array an array of linked lists?
所以是的，即使有碰撞
So yes, even though there's this collision
赫敏和哈利都在阵列中的同一位置，
where both Hermione and Harry belong at the same location in the array,
没关系。
that's fine.
万一发生这种情况，我只是将它们缝合在一起
In the event this happens, I'm just going to kind of stitch them together
从左到右进入一个链表。
into a linked list from left to right.
所以这不是理想的。
So it's not ideal.
因为现在我要走两步才能到达哈利，而不是1，
Because now it takes me two steps to get to Harry instead of 1,
使用简单的算术和方括号表示法。
using simple arithmetic and square bracket notation.
但是，至少我仍然可以将他放入我的通讯录中。
But heck, at least I can still fit him in my address book.
因此，需要权衡取舍，但感觉是合理的。
So a bit of a trade off, but feels reasonable.
好吧，其他人，海格-
Well, someone else, Hagrid--
好吧，现在需要我是不理想的
all right, it's not ideal that now it takes me
在我的地址簿中到达海格的三个步骤。
three steps to get to Hagrid in my address book.
但是三个总比根本不让他在那里更好。
But three is way better than not having him in there at all.
因此，我们再次在这里看到了折衷的体现。
So, again, we see a manifestation of a trade off here, too.
但是我们已经解决了这个问题。
But we've solved the problem.
哈希表确实就是这种数据结构。
And a hash table is, indeed, exactly this data structure.
它是一个链表的数组，至少可以这样实现。
It is an array of linked lists, at least it can be implemented as such.
它基于引入哈希函数的概念。
And it is predicated on introducing the notion of a hash function.
这实际上是我们不久之后将在其他环境中看到的东西。
This is actually something we'll see in other contexts before long.
但是散列函数将使我们不仅可以映射Hermione，Harry，
But a hash function is going to allow us to map not only Hermione, Harry,
和海格，还有罗恩和雷穆斯，西弗勒斯和小天狼星
and Hagrid, but also Ron and Remus, Severus and Sirius
确定地移动到其各自的位置。
to their respective locations deterministically.
也就是说，这里不涉及随机性。
That is, there's no randomness involved here.
每当我看到这些人的名字时，
Every time I look at these people's names,
我要弄清楚它们所属的位置
I'm going to figure out the location at which they belong
而且位置永远不会改变。
and that location is never going to change.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do this?
好吧，事实证明我们可以回想一下自己解决问题的方法
Well, it turns out we can think back to problem solving itself
以及什么功能。
and what functions are.
因此，这就是我们定义的问题解决方法。
So this is problem solving as we defined it.
这也是使用输入和输出的任何语言的功能。
This is also a function in any language that takes inputs and outputs.
哈希函数将是一种秘密
A hash function is going to be sort of a secret sauce
现在在此黑匣子内部。
inside of this black box for now.
那么什么是哈希函数？
And so what is a hash function?
嗯，哈希函数实际上是一个函数，无论从数学上还是
Well, a hash function is literally a function, either mathematically
或在编程中以某种字符串作为输入，在这种情况下，
or in programming, that takes as input some string, in this case,
例如Hermione或Harry，它会返回一些输出。
like Hermione or Harry, and it returns some output.
哈希函数的输出通常是一个数字。
And the output of a hash function is usually a number.
在这种情况下，我想要的数字将在0到25之间。
In this case, the number I want is going to be between 0 and 25.
因此，为了实现哈希表的这一概念，
So in order to implement this notion of a hash table,
不仅以图形方式显示在屏幕上，而且以实际代码显示，
not just pictorially on the screen, but in actual code,
实际上，我将不得不编写一个需要字符串的函数，
I'm literally going to have to write a function that takes a string,
或者，如果愿意，可以将char *作为输入，并返回一个介于0到25之间的int，以便
or if you will, char*, as input and returns an int between 0 and 25 so that
在这种情况下，我知道如何将Hermione或Harry或Hagrid转换为7。
I know how to convert Hermione or Harry or Hagrid to the number 7 in this case.
那么这个散列函数做什么呢？
So what does this hash function do?
它采用像Albus这样的输入作为输入，并且输出0。
It takes as input something like Albus and it outputs 0.
它需要像Zacharias这样的人，并且输出25。
It takes someone like Zacharias, and it outputs 25.
您可能会在这里看到该模式。
And you can probably see the pattern here.
我将编写以实现此类代码的代码是
The code I would write in order to implement something like this is
可能要看用户的输入，即char *。
probably going to look at the user's input, that char*.
然后要看第一个字符
And it's going to look at the first character, which
这两个分别为A或Z。
is A or Z, respectively, for these two.
然后要做一点数学
And it's then going to do a little bit of math
然后减去65之类的
and subtract off, like, 65 or whatnot.
这将使我得到一个介于0到25之间的数字，
And it's going to get me a number between 0 and 25,
就像凯撒（Caesar）或我们过去对字符串的某些处理一样。
just like with Caesar or some of our past manipulations of strings.
因此，从这里开始，我们现在可以采用此构建块，也许
So from here, we can now take this building block, though, and perhaps
更有效地解决我们的问题。
solve our problems a little more effectively.
就像，我不喜欢这样的事实，即使是的，我已经
Like, I don't love the fact that even though, yes, I've
为哈利，赫敏和海格腾出了空间，
made room for Harry, and Hermione, and Hagrid,
现在是Luna，Lily，Lucius和Lavender，其中一些链接列表
and now Luna, and Lily, and Lucius, and Lavender, some of these linked lists
越来越长了。
are getting a little long.
您可以在这里使用另一个术语。
And there's another term you can use here.
这些有点像链子，如果您愿意的话，
These are kind of like chains, if you will,
因为它们看起来像链节围栏或链条中的小链接。
because they look like chain link fences or little links in a chain.
这些是链或链表。
These are chains or linked lists.
但是其中一些已经开始变长了。
But some of them are starting to get long.
我试图达到恒定的时间有点愚蠢，Big O为1
And it's a little stupid that I'm trying to achieve constant time, Big O of 1,
但是从技术上讲，即使其中一些名称从字面上迈出了一步，
but technically, even though some of the names literally take one step,
他们中的一些人正在采取两个或三个或四个步骤。
some of them are taking two or three or four steps.
因此，它开始发展。
So it's starting to devolve.
那么，这里的优化是什么？
So what would be an optimization here?
如果因为如此受欢迎而开始感到不适
If you start to get uncomfortable because you're so popular
并且您的联系人中有很多名字，以至于
and you've got so many names in your contacts that looking up
H，查找L比其他花费更多的时间，
the H's, looking up the L's is taking more time than the others,
我们可以做些什么来改善这种情况，并且仍然使用哈希表，
what could we do to improve the situation and still use a hash table,
还在使用哈希函数吗？
still use a hash function?
但是，合理的解决方案可能是什么
But what would maybe the logical solution
当你有太多的碰撞时，你
be when you have too many collisions, you
有太多的名字彼此冲突？
have too many names colliding with one another?
我们又如何才能提高绩效并到达目标位置，
How could we improve our performance and get at locations, again,
接近一步，不是两个，不是三个，不是四个？
closer to one step, not two, not three, not four?
所以实际上是一步，因为这是我们这里的圣杯。
So literally one step, because that's our Holy Grail here.
布莱恩：一些人建议您不仅仅应该看
BRIAN: A few people have suggested you should look at more than just
第一个字母。
the first letter.
例如，您可以查看第二个字母。
Like, you could look at the second letter, for example.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
好的。
Nice.
因此，如果看一个人名字的字母
So if looking at one letter of the person's name
显然是不够的。
is obviously insufficient.
因为我们所有人的名字都以H或A开头
Because a whole bunch of us have names that start with H or A
或Z之类的东西，那么，为什么我们不看两个字母
or Z or the like, well, why don't we look at two letters
因此降低了我们
and therefore decrease the probability that we're
会发生这些碰撞？
going to have these collisions?
因此，让我继续进行重组。
So let me go ahead and restructure this.
并着眼于赫敏，哈里和海格的问题，
And focusing on the Hermione, Harry, and Hagrid problem,
我们为什么不继续将我们的数组放在哈希表中，垂直的东西
why don't we go ahead and take our array in the hash table, the vertical thing
在这里，让我们想一想，可能不只是在那个位置是H。
here, and let's think of it as maybe not just being H at that location.
但是，如果我们特别想到那个位置呢？
But what if we think of that location specifically
首先是HA，然后是HB，HC，HD，HE，HF，直到HZ。
as being HA, and then HB, HC, HD, HE, HF, all the way down to HZ.
然后是IA，IB，IC等，所以我们现在
And then IA, IB, IC, and so forth, so we now
枚举从AA到ZZ的所有可能的字母对？
enumerate all possible pairs of letters from AA to ZZ?
但这似乎使事情散布开了，对吗？
But this would seem to spread things out, right?
因为现在赫敏进入阵列中的HE位置。
Because now Hermione goes in the HE location in the array.
现在，哈利进入房委会。
Now Harry goes in the HA.
现在，哈格-噢，该死。
And now Hag-- oh, dammit.
就像，海格仍在同一地点。
Like, Hagrid still goes in the same location.
那么，什么会是更好的解决方法呢？
So what would maybe be a better fix?
再说一次，这并不可怕，就像两个步骤没什么大不了的，
Again, this isn't horrible, like two steps is not a big deal,
特别是在快速计算机上。
especially on fast computers.
但是，同样，如果有足够大的数据集，
But, again, with large enough data sets, and if we're
不再谈论您联系人中的人，但也许
no longer talking about people in your contacts, but maybe
世界上所有拥有Google帐户或Twitter帐户的人，
all the people in the world who have Google accounts, or Twitter accounts,
等等，您想在其中快速搜索此信息，
and the like, where you want to search this information quickly,
您将有很多人的名字以H和A开头
you're going to have a lot of people whose names start with H and A
和Z以及其他所有内容。
and Z and everything else.
最好将它们进一步传播出去。
It would be nice to spread them out further.
那我们该怎么办？
So what could we do?
好吧，与其使用前两个字母，
Well, instead of using the first two letters,
坦率地说，我认为这的逻辑扩展是使用前三个字母。
frankly I think the logical extension of this is to use the first three letters.
因此，也许这就是HAA存储桶。
So maybe this is the HAA bucket.
这就是HAB，HAC，HAD，HAE，点，点，点，一直到HZZ，
This is the HAB, HAC, HAD, HAE, dot, dot, dot, all the way down to HZZ,
然后是IAA。
and then IAA.
但是现在当我们哈希我们的三个朋友时，赫敏
But now when we hash our three friends, Hermione
可以说是数组的元素。
goes in the HER bucket so to speak, the elements of the array.
哈利，哈利，进了那个水桶。
Harry, HAR, goes in that bucket.
现在，海格和其他所有人一样，都拥有自己的水桶HAG。
And Hagrid now gets his own bucket, HAG, as would everyone else.
这样看来已经解决了这个特定问题。
So it seems to have solved this specific problem.
您仍然可以想象，而我不得不更加努力地思考，也许是谷歌
You could still imagine, and I have to think harder and probably Google
看看是否还有其他以HAG或HAR开头的哈利波特名称
to see if there's other Harry Potter names that start with HAG or HAR
或HER寻找另一个碰撞。
or HER to find another collision.
因为您可以想象使用四个字母来代替。
Because you could imagine using four letters instead.
但是我们要付出什么代价呢？
But what price are we paying?
就像，我一次又一次地解决这个问题。
Like, I'm solving this problem again and again.
而且我正在使自己的查字时间更快，
And I'm getting myself literally faster look up time,
因为它给了我一步。
because it's giving me one step.
我可以从数学上算出
I can mathematically figure out by just doing
一点点的ASCII数学，索引的数量是多少
a bit of ASCII math, what the number of the index
是我应该跳入这个越来越大的阵营。
is that I should jump to in this bigger and bigger array.
但是我要付出什么代价？
But what price am I paying?
Brian，您有什么想传达的想法吗？
Brian, any thoughts you'd like to relay?
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
少数人说这将占用大量内存。
A few people are saying it's going to take a lot of memory.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
就像我的上帝，这现在需要大量的记忆。
My God, like, this is taking a huge amount of memory now.
以前，它需要多少内存？
Previously, how much memory did it take?
好吧，让我在这里拉起一个小计算器，然后做一些快速数学运算。
Well, let me pull up a little calculator here and do some quick math.
因此，如果我们最初有26个存储桶（可以说是数组中的元素），
So if we had originally 26 buckets, so to speak, elements in the array, that,
当然，还不错。
of course, isn't that bad.
感觉很合理，有26个插槽。
That feels pretty reasonable, 26 slots.
但不利的一面是，连锁店可能
But the downside was that the chains might
得到一种长名称，三个名称，四个名称，甚至更多。
get kind of long, three names, four names, maybe even more.
但是，如果我们有AA到ZZ，而不是A到Z，那就是26乘以26，
But if we have AA through ZZ, instead of A through Z, that's 26 times 26,
那是676个桶
that's 676 buckets.
听起来不算什么，尽管这比大多数事情都大
Doesn't sound like a huge deal, though that's bigger than most things
到目前为止，我们已经在内存中完成了很多任务。
we've done in memory thus far, not a huge deal.
但是如果我们有三个，那就是26种可能性乘以26乘以26，
But if we have three, that's 26 possibilities times 26 times 26,
通过ZZZ的AAA。
for AAA through ZZZ.
现在，我的阵列中有17,576个存储桶。
Now we have 17,576 buckets in my array.
问题不仅仅在于我们正在使用该内存。
And the problem isn't so much that we're using that memory.
老实说，如果您需要内存，请使用它。
Because honestly, if you need the memory, use it.
没关系。
That's fine.
只是把硬件扔在问题上。
Just throw hardware at the problem.
购买并升级更多内存。
Buy and upgrade more memory.
但问题是我可能不知道
But the problem is that I probably don't know
有很多名字以HAA或AZZ开头的人
that many people whose names start with HAA or AZZ
或字母的这些组合中的任何数量。
or any number of these combinations of letters of the alphabet.
这些水桶很多都将是空的。
A lot of those buckets are going to be empty.
但是，它们是否为空并不重要。
But it doesn't matter if they're empty.
如果您想要一个数组并且想要随机访问，则必须存在它们
If you want an array and you want random access, they have to be present
这样您的算术就可以每个星期2进行一次计算
so that your arithmetic works out, per Week 2,
您只使用方括号表示法的地方
where you just use square bracket notation
并跳转到您关心的内存中的任何位置。
and jump to any of the locations in memory that you care about.
因此，需要权衡利弊，或者找到与这些交易有关的拐点
So finding that trade off, or finding the inflection point with those trade
是一种艺术和/或科学，
offs, is kind of an art and/or a science, figuring out
对于您的特定数据，您的特定应用程序，
for your particular data, your particular application, which
更重要的是两者之间的时间或空间或某种快乐的媒介。
is more important, time or space or some happy medium in between the two.
正如问题5所示，您将
And with Problem Set 5, as you'll see, you'll
实际上必须部分弄清这种平衡
actually have to figure out this balance in part
通过尝试最终减少您自己的内存使用量
by trying to minimize, ultimately, your own use of memory
和您自己使用计算机的时间。
and your own use of computers' time.
但是，实际上，让我指出一点。
But let me point something out, actually.
直到现在，哈希表的概念
This notion of hash table, which up until now,
绝对是我们研究过的最复杂的数据结构，
definitely the most sophisticated data structure that we've looked at,
在某种程度上您已经很熟悉了。
it's kind of familiar to you in some way already.
这些可能比您在家中拥有的扑克牌还要大。
These are probably larger than the playing cards you have at home.
但是，如果您曾经玩过一副纸牌，
But if you've ever played with a deck of cards,
纸牌随机开始，在某些时候您很有可能，
and the cards start out randomly, odds are you've, at some point,
需要将它们分类以进行一场或另一场比赛。
needed to sort them for one game or another.
有时您需要彻底洗牌。
Sometimes you need to shuffle them entirely.
如果您想变得整洁一些，可以对它们进行排序，
If you want to be a little neat, you might sort them,
不仅是数量，而且是西装。
not just by number, but also by suit.
因此，心，黑桃，球杆和钻石分为不同的类别。
So hearts and spades and clubs and diamonds into separate categories.
坦白说，我只是为了隐喻而在此使用此字词。
So honestly, I have this literally here just for the sake of the metaphor.
我们这里有四个水桶。
We have four buckets here.
我们已经继续前进，并在那儿预先用铁锹标记它们。
And we've gone ahead and labeled them in advance with spade there.
这就是一个桶。
So that's one bucket.
在这里，我们有菱形。
Here we have diamond shape here.
在这里，我们有-
And here we have--
[咕RUN]
[GRUNTING]
-在这里我们有心，然后在这里有俱乐部。
--here we have hearts here and then clubs here.
因此，如果您曾经整理过一副纸牌，
So if you've ever sorted a deck of cards,
很有可能您还没有真正考虑过这个问题。
odds are you haven't really thought about this very hard.
因为它没那么有趣。
Because it's not that interesting.
您可能会无意识地开始对它们进行布局和排序
You probably mindlessly start laying them out and sorting them
穿西装，然后按数字。
by suits and then maybe by number.
但是，如果您这样做了，那么您之前就有了哈希值。
But if you've done that, you have hashed values before.
如果您看第一张卡片，就会发现，
If you take a look at the first card and you see,
哦，那是钻石的王牌。
that, oh, it's the ace of diamonds.
您知道，是的，您最终可能会关心它是钻石，是王牌。
You know, yes, you might care ultimately that it's a diamond, that it's an ace.
但是现在，我只是将其放入钻石桶中。
But for now, I'm just going to put it, for instance, into the diamond bucket.
这是这里的两颗钻石。
Here's the two of diamonds here.
我将其放入钻石桶中。
I'm going to put that into the diamond bucket.
这是俱乐部的王牌。
Here's the ace of clubs.
所以我要把它放在这里。
So I'm going to put that over here.
您可以逐步将一张卡散列在另一张卡上。
And you can just progressively hash one card after the other.
而且，实际上，散列实际上只是意味着要看一些输入和产生，
And, indeed, hashing really just means to look at some input and produce,
在这种情况下，一些数字输出会输出类似存储桶0、1、2
in this case, some numeric output that outputs the like bucket 0, 1, 2,
或3根据该输入的某些特征，
or 3 based on some characteristic of that input,
像我在这里一样，实际上是否是西装上的西装，
whether it's actually the suit on the card like I'm doing here,
还是基于这里的字母。
or maybe it's based on the letter of the alphabet here.
我为什么要这样做呢？
And why am I doing this?
正确的？
Right?
我不会做整个事情。
I'm not going to do the whole thing.
因为52个步骤需要一段时间并且很快就会变得无聊
Because 52 steps is going to take a while and get boring quickly, if not
已经。
already.
但是我为什么要这样做呢？
But why am I doing this?
因为很可能您已经做到了。
Because odds are you've probably done this.
与实际水桶的戏剧性不同，您可能只是将它们铺好了
Not with the drama of actual buckets, you've probably just kind of laid them
在你面前
out in front of you.
但是，如果您确实做到了，那您为什么要这样做呢？
But why have you done that, if that's indeed something you have done?
是的。
Yeah.
到索菲亚？
Over to Sophia?
听众：实际上，我们可能会更快地处理问题，
AUDIENCE: There's a possibility that we could actually get to things faster,
就像，如果我们知道它是什么桶。
like, if we know what bucket it is.
我们甚至可以搜索0、1或更少的东西。
We might be able to even search things for, like, 0, 1, or less.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
听众：类似的东西。
AUDIENCE: Something like that.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
您开始获得这些优化，对吗？
You start to gain these optimizations, right?
至少，作为一个人类，老实说，我可以处理四个较小的问题
At least, as a human, honestly, I can process four smaller problems
比一个更大的问题（即52号问题）容易得多。
just much easier than one bigger problem, that's size 52.
我可以更快地解决四个13卡问题
I can solve four 13 card problems a little faster, especially
如果我正在寻找特定的卡片。
if I'm looking for a particular card.
现在我可以在13张牌中找到它，而不是52张。
Now I can find it among 13 cards instead of 52.
因此，这里只是一种优化。
So there's just kind of an optimization here.
因此，您可以将这些卡作为输入，将它们散列到特定的存储桶中，
So you might take as input these cards, hash them into a particular bucket,
然后继续解决较小的问题。
and then proceed to solve the smaller problem.
现在，这不是哈希表本身的全部内容。
Now that's not what a hash table itself is all about.
哈希表是关于存储信息，但存储信息
A hash table is about storing information, but storing information
以便更快地到达它。
so as to get to it more quickly.
因此，索菲亚（Sophia）的观点是，如果确实她只是想像钻石般地寻找自己，
So to Sophia's point, if indeed she just wants to find like the ace of diamonds,
她现在只需要查看一个13大小的问题，
she now only has to look through a 13 sized problem, a linked
大小为13的列表，而不是数组或大小为52的链表。
list of size 13, if you will, instead of an array or a linked list of size 52.
因此，哈希表允许您对输入进行存储，如果可以的话，
So a hash table allows you to bucketize your inputs, if you will,
口语化，并更快地访问数据。
colloquially, and get access to data more quickly.
不一定要一次完成，一步就可以是两个。
Not necessarily in time one, in one step, it might be two.
可能是四个。
It might be four.
这可能是13个步骤。
It might be 13 steps.
但是通常比您减少步骤
But it's generally fewer steps than if you
纯粹是线性地，甚至是对数地做某事。
were doing something purely linearly, or even logarithmically.
理想情况下，您尝试以这种方式选择哈希函数
Ideally, you're trying to pick your hash function in such a way
通过不使用A到Z来最大程度地减少发生碰撞的元素的数量，
that you minimize the number of elements that collide by using not A through Z,
但是AA到ZZ等。
but AA through ZZ and so forth.
因此，让我继续在这里提出一个问题。
So let me go ahead here and ask a question.
那么，什么是运行时间
What, then, is the running time when it comes
哈希表的这种数据结构？
to this data structure of a hash table?
如果要继续在哈希表中搜索，则所有数据
If you want to go ahead and search in a hash table, once all of the data
在那里，一旦我所有的联系人都在那里，
is in there, once all of my contacts are there,
给定手机中的n个联系人，您的手机必须执行多少步骤，
how many steps does your phone have to take, given n contacts in your phone,
找到赫敏，海格或其他人？
to find Hermione or Hagrid or anyone else?
因此，我再次看到，你们80％的人说的是固定时间，即1的大O。
So I see, again, 80% of you are saying constant time, Big O of 1.
同样，恒定时间可能意味着一个步骤，两个步骤，四个步骤，
And, again, constant time might mean one step, two steps, four steps,
但是一些固定的数字，不依赖于n。
but some fixed number, not dependent on n.
大约有18％的人说线性时间。
18% of you or so are saying linear time.
我必须承认，你们中的20％
And I have to admit, the 20% of you or so that
所说的线性时间在技术上，渐近上，数学上都是正确的。
said linear time are technically, asymptotically, mathematically correct.
在这里，我们开始看到现实世界之间的某种区别
And here we begin to see sort of a distinction between the real world
和学术界。
and academia.
所以这里的学者，或者这里的真实世界，真实的程序员
So the academic here, or rather the real world here, the real world programmer
会说，就像索菲亚所做的那样，很明显，里面有13张卡的水桶
would say, just like Sophia did, obviously, a bucket with 13 cards in it
绝对比拥有52张卡的更大水桶更好。
is strictly better than one bigger bucket with 52 cards.
那只是更快。
That is just faster.
实际上，查找或翻转的速度是它的四倍
It's literally four times as fast to find or to flip
通过这13张牌，而不是52张。
through those 13 cards instead of 52.
从客观上讲，这是更快的。
That is objectively faster.
但是学者会说是的，但是渐近地-渐近地
But the academic would say yes, but asymptotically-- and asymptotically
这只是一种幻想的说法，因为n变得非常大，
is just a fancy way of saying as n gets really large,
我不断描述的手形，渐近地
the sort of wave of the hand that I keep describing, asymptotically taking
13个步骤在技术上是n的大O。
13 steps is technically big O of n.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，对于这里的卡片，从技术上来说，它是n除以4。
Well, in the case of the cards here, it's technically n divided by 4.
是的，那是13岁。
Yes, it's 13.
但是，如果总共有n张牌，从技术上讲，这个存储桶的大小
But if there's n cards total, technically, the size of this bucket
最终将被m除以4。
is going to end up being m divided by 4.
当我们谈论大O和欧米茄时，我们谈论了什么？
And what did we talk about when we talked about Big O and omega?
好吧，您放弃了低阶条款。
Well, you throw away the lower order terms.
您摆脱了常数，例如除以4，
You get rid of the constants, like the divide by 4,
或其他优点。
or the plus something else.
因此，我们摆脱了这一点。
So we get rid of that.
从技术上讲，这是一个哈希表搜索。
And it's technically a hash table searching.
它仍在n的Big O中。
It is still in Big O of n.
但是在这里，我们再次看到了现实世界之间的对比
But here, again, we see a contrast between the real world
和理论世界。
and the theoretical world.
就像，是的，如果您想参加学术辩论，
Like, yes, if you want to get into an academic debate,
是的，它在技术上仍然与链接相同
yes, it's still technically the same as a linked
列表或数组，此时您最好只搜索
list or an array, at which point you might as well just search
从左到右线性变化的东西，无论是数组还是链表。
the thing left to right linearly, whether it's an array or a linked list.
但是，来吧。
But come on.
例如，如果您实际上预先对这些值进行哈希处理，
Like, if you actually hash these values in advance,
并将它们分散到4或26或576个桶中，
and spread them out into 4, or 26, or 576 buckets,
实际上，挂钟时间会更快。
that is actually going to be faster when it comes to wall clock time.
因此，当您从字面上看墙上的时钟时，
So when you literally look at the clock on the wall,
采取索菲娅的方法所花的时间少于采取的时间
less time will pass taking Sophia's approach than taking
数组或链表方法。
an array or linked list approach.
所以在这里，那些说n大O的人是正确的。
So here, those of you who said Big O of n are correct.
但是当涉及到现实世界的编程时，
But when it comes to the real world programming,
老实说，如果它比实际的n步快，
honestly, if it's faster than actual n steps,
这很可能是一个净积极的方面。
that may very well be a net positive.
因此，也许我们应该将重点更多地放在实践上，而有时却要少一些，
And so perhaps we should be focusing more on practice and less, sometimes,
这些东西的理论。
on the theory of these things.
确实，这将是挑战。
And indeed that's going to be the challenge.
我不断提到的问题集5
The Problem Set 5 to which I keep alluding
会挑战你去实现一个
is going to challenge you to implement one
这些数据结构中的一个哈希表，包含100,000个英文单词。
of these data structures, a hash table, with 100,000 plus English words.
简而言之，我们将为您提供一个大文本文件，其中包含
We're going to, in a nutshell, give you a big text file containing
每行一个英文单词。
one English word per line.
您的目标之一就是将所有这140,000多个单词加载
And among your goals is going to be to load all of those 140,000 plus words
使用哈希表进入计算机的内存。
into your computer's memory using a hash table.
现在，如果您对此简单化，并且您
Now if you are simplistic about it, and you
使用具有26个存储区（从A到Z）的哈希表，
use a hash table with 26 buckets, A through Z,
您将发生很多碰撞。
you're going to have a lot of collisions.
如果有140,000多个英文单词，那么里面有很多单词
If there's 140,000 plus English words, there's a lot of words in there
以A或B或Z或介于两者之间的任何内容开头。
that start with A, or B, or Z, or anything in between.
如果您可能随后通过ZZ选择AA，那也许更好，
If you maybe then go with AA through ZZ, maybe that's better,
或通过ZZZ AAA认证，也许更好。
or AAA through ZZZ, maybe that's better.
但是到某个时候，您将开始使用
But at some point, you're going to start to use
太多的内存对您自己没有好处。
too much memory for your own good.
问题5的挑战之一（可选）
And one of the challenges, optionally, of Problem Set 5,
将会是一个好玩的挑战您的同学的方式，
is going to be to playfully challenge your classmates whereby,
如果您选择这样做，则可以运行一个命令，该命令将使您
if you opt into this, you can run a command that will put you
在大板上，这将在课程的网站上确切显示多少
on the big board which will show on the course's website exactly how much
或您正在使用多少RAM或内存，以及
or how little RAM or memory you're using, and how little
或您的代码需要花费多少时间才能运行。
or how much time your code is taking to run.
因此，我们只是搁置了一些学术上的挥霍之手，说：
And so we just put aside the sort of academic waves of the hand saying,
好吧，是的，您所有的代码都是n的BigO。
well, yes, all of your code is Big O of n.
但是n除以4，Sophia的方法在实践中要比n好得多
But n divided by 4, Sophia's approach, is way better in practice than n
本身。
itself.
我们将开始梳理二分法
And we'll begin to tease apart the dichotomy
在这里理论与实践之间。
between theory here and practice.
但是，这些并不是在内存中分配内容的唯一方法。
But these aren't the only ways to lay things out in memory.
我们只想向您展示一些其他想法
And we wanted to show you just a few other ideas that come out now
我们拥有所有这些构件。
that we have all of these building blocks.
其中之一就是我们要称为特里的数据结构。
One of which is the data structure that we're going to call a trie.
Trie实际上是单词检索的缩写，
Trie is actually short for the word retrieval,
即使发音不尽相同。
even though it's not quite pronounced the same.
也称为前缀树。
It's also known as a prefix tree.
这是另一种类型的树，通常
And it's a different type of tree that is typically
用于存储单词或其他更复杂的数据
used to store words, or other more sophisticated pieces of data
而不只是数字。
instead of just numbers alone.
因此，特里树实际上是由数组组成的树。
So a trie is actually a tree made up of arrays.
因此，您可以在此处看到某种模式。
So you can kind of see a pattern here.
哈希表是链接列表的数组。
A hash table was an array of linked lists.
特里是一棵树，其每个节点都是一个数组。
A trie is a tree, each of whose nodes is an array.
因此，在某个时候，计算机科学家开始变得有点创意
So at some point, computer scientists started getting a little creative
并开始像砸碎一样
and started just, like, literally smashing together
似乎可以看到不同的数据结构。
different data structures to see what they could come up with, it seems.
因此，特里开始看起来像这样。
And so a trie begins to look like this.
但是它具有这种惊人的特性，比理论上的任何东西都要好
But it has this amazing property that's better than anything in theory
我们以前见过。
we've seen before.
这是一个尝试中的节点。
Here is one node in a try.
从某种意义上来说，这是一个节点，就像矩形或正方形一样。
And it's a node in the sense that this would be like a rectangle or square.
但是在这种情况下，该节点的内部实际上是一个大小为26的数组。
But inside of that node is literally an array of size 26 in this case.
如果您要表示A到Z，则表示这些位置或存储桶中的每一个。
And each of those locations or buckets, if you will represent A through Z.
而且我们要做的就是每当我们插入一个单词（例如名称）时，
And what we're going to do is any time we insert a word, like a name,
像哈利（Harry）或海格（Hagrid）或赫敏（Hermione）或其他任何人，
like Harry, or Hagrid, or Hermione, or anyone else,
我们将逐步浏览其名称的字母，例如HAGRID，
we are going to walk through the letters of their name, like, H-A-G-R-I-D,
我们将遵循一系列从一个节点到另一个节点的指针
and we are going to follow a series of pointers from one node to another
如下。
as follows.
因此，例如，如果这是A到Z或0到25，则这里是位置H。
So for instance, if this is A through Z, or 0 through 25, here is location H.
因此，如果目前的目标是插入我们的第一个联系人，
So if the goal at the moment is to insert the first of our contacts,
例如，哈里，我将首先看
for instance, Harry, I'm going to start by looking
在第一个节点（树的根）处，查找H位置。
at the first node, the root of the tree, looking up the H location.
我会想起哈利从这里开始的想法，
And I'm going to kind of make mental note that Harry starts there,
哈里的H从那里开始。
the H in Harry starts there.
然后，如果我想在哈里插入A，我是
Then if I want to insert the A in Harry, I'm
接下来，添加一个代表26个字母的新节点。
going to go ahead and add a new node, representing 26 letters.
但我要跟踪一个事实，好的，A在这里。
But I'm going to keep track of the fact that, OK, A is here.
所以现在我将有另一个指针-
So now I'm going to have another pointer--
哦，很抱歉-不是哈里，首先是海格，是海格。那我刚刚做了什么？
oh, I'm sorry-- not Harry, Hagrid first, H-A-G-R-I-D. So what have I just done?
特里树又是一棵树，每个树的节点都是一个数组。
A trie, again, is a tree, each of whose nodes is an array.
这些数组中的每一个都是指向其他节点的指针的数组。
And each of those arrays is an array of pointers to other nodes.
因此，再次，我们实际上只是在这里将所有内容融合在一起。
So, again, we're really just mashing up everything together here.
但这是和以前一样的构建基块。
But it's the same building blocks as before.
该树中的每个节点（从上到下）都是指向其他节点的指针的数组。
Each node in this tree, top to bottom, is an array of pointers to other nodes.
因此，如果我想检查海格是否在我的联系人中，
And so, if I wanted to check if Hagrid is in my contacts,
我实际上从第一个节点开始，然后跟随H指针。
I literally start at the first node, and I follow the H pointer.
然后，我跟随A指针。
I then follow the A pointer.
然后，我跟随G指针，R指针，I指针。
I then follow the G pointer, the R pointer, the I pointer.
然后我检查D指针。
And then I check at the D pointer.
该结构内部是否存在布尔值-下次再说一次，
Is there a Boolean value inside of that structure-- more on that another time,
可能 -
perhaps--
只是说，是或否，有人叫HAGRID
that just says, yes or no, there is someone named H-A-G-R-I-D
在我的联系人中。
in my contacts.
请注意，目前没有其他字母要注意。
Notice there's no other letters noted at the moment.
而且没有其他绿色盒子了。
And there's no other green boxes.
就我们的目的而言，绿色仅表示布尔值。
Green just denotes a Boolean value for our purposes now.
因此，这意味着没有人叫HAGRIA，RIB或RIC。
So that means there's no one whose name is H-A-G-R-I-A, or R-I-B, or R-I-C.
我的联系人中只有HAGRID。
It's only H-A-G-R-I-D that exists in my contacts.
但是请注意接下来会发生什么。
But notice what happens next.
现在，如果我继续插入哈利，请注意
Now if I go ahead and insert Harry, notice
哈里和海格里德共享H，A，然后是第三个节点。
that Harry and Hagrid share the H, the A, and then this third node.
但随后哈利需要遵循不同的指针
But then Harry needs to follow a different pointer
存放R和Y。注意那里的绿色。
to store the R and the Y. And notice the green there.
这是数据结构中的一个复选标记，一个布尔值，即
It's sort of a checkmark in the data structure, a Boolean value, that's
说是。
saying yes.
在我的上下文中，我有一个叫HARRY的人。
I have someone in my context named H-A-R-R-Y.
然后，如果我们添加Hermione，则她共享H，然后共享第二个节点。
And then, if we add Hermione, she shares the H, and then also the second node.
但是Hermione一起需要一些新节点。
But Hermione requires some new nodes all together.
但是请注意这个关键属性，这种复杂性的原因，
But notice this key property, the reason for this sort of complexity,
因为这可能是迄今为止我们所见过的最奇怪的结构，
because this is probably the weirdest structure we've seen thus far,
即使我的电话簿中有十亿个名字，
is that even if I have a billion names in my phone book,
从根本上讲，我找到海格要走几步？
how many steps literally does it take me to find Hagrid?
有人吗
Someone?
随意发短信，如果您喜欢聊天窗口？
Feel free to chime in the text, the chat window if you like?
即使我的联系人中有十亿个名字，
Even if I have a billion names in my contacts,
我要检查并检查多少个步骤
how many steps does it take for me to look up and check
海格在其中吗？
if Hagrid is among them?
布莱恩：人们说的是六个。
BRIAN: People are saying six.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：六，哈格里德（HAGRID）。如果我有20亿个名字，40亿个名字，
DAVID MALAN: Six, H-A-G-R-I-D. If I have 2 billion names, 4 billion names,
它需要执行几个步骤？
how many steps does it take?
6，这就是我们所说的恒定时间，至少恒定时间
6, and this is what we mean by constant time, constant time at least
数据结构中人类名字的长度。
in the length of the humans' names in the data structure.
那么这是什么意思？
So what does this mean?
无论您将多少个名称塞入一个trie数据
No matter how many names you cram into a trie data
结构，其他名称的数量不
structure, the number of other names does not
影响我找到Harry，Hagrid或Hermione所需的步骤
impact how many steps it takes for me to find Harry or Hagrid or Hermione
或其他任何人。
or anyone else.
它仅取决于其名称的长度。
It is only dependent on the length of their name.
这是我们可以学到一点的地方。
And here's where we can get a little academic.
如果您假设字符数有限
If you assume that there's a finite number of characters
以任何人类，真实或虚构的名字命名，可能是20或100，或者其他。
in any human, real or imaginary's name, maybe it's 20, or 100, or whatever.
它大于6，但可能少于数百。
It's more than 6, but it's probably fewer than hundreds.
然后您可以假设那是恒定的。
And then you can assume that that's constant.
大概是200个字符
So it might be Big O of, like, 200 characters
对于拥有超长名字的人。
for someone with a super long name.
但这是不变的。
But that's constant.
因此，从技术上来说，尝试可以使您获得圣杯
And so technically a try gives you that Holy Grail
1的Big O的查找时间和插入时间
of look up times and insertion times of Big O of 1.
因为它不依赖于n，即n
Because it is not dependent on n, which is the number
数据结构中其他名称的名称。
of other names in the data structure.
它仅取决于您输入的名称的长度。
It is dependent only on the length of the name you're inputting.
而且，如果您假设世界上的所有名称都有合理的联系，
And if you assume that all names in the world are reasonably linked,
小于某个有限值，例如6或200，或任何其他值
less than some finite value, like 6, or 200, or whatever
是的，那么你可以打电话给它。
it is, then you can call that.
从技术上讲，它是1的大O。
And it technically is Big O of 1.
那是恒定的时间。
That is constant time.
因此，这就是整天的目标，例如，努力达到固定的时间。
So here is the goal of this whole day, like, trying to get to constant time.
因为固定时间比固定时间好，所以
Because constant time is better than, it would
似乎是线性时间，还是对数时间，或者我们看到的其他任何时间。
seem, linear time, or logarithmic time, or anything else we've seen.
但是，但是，但是，再次，总会有一个权衡。
But-- but-- but-- again, there's always a trade off.
如果您看到了，我们刚刚支付了什么价格？
What price have we just paid if you see it?
为什么尝试不一定全部如此？
Why are tries not necessarily all that?
还有一个陷阱。
There's still a catch.
丹尼尔？
Daniel?
听众：例如，假设您的联系人列表中有两个人。
AUDIENCE: For example, if let's say you have two people in your contact list.
一个人叫丹尼尔，一个人叫丹妮尔。
One person was named Daniel and one person was named Danielle.
而且您知道Daniel在您的清单中。
And you know that Daniel is in your list.
因此，L的布尔运算符为true。
So the L would have this Boolean operator of true.
但是，如果您的L是运算符，您将如何前往Danielle
But then, how would you get to Danielle, if your L was an operator
而且它并没有指向Danielle的另一个L？
and it didn't point to another L for Danielle?
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：真的很好的问题，如果可以的话，可以提供一个特例。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question, a corner case, if you will.
如果某人的名字是另一人的名字的子串怎么办？
What if someone's name is a substring of another person's name?
Daniel，DANIEL，我想你是说Danielle，
So Daniel, D-A-N-I-E-L, and I think you're saying Danielle,
丹妮尔所以第二个名字要长一些。
D-A-N-I-E-L-L-E. So the second name is a little longer.
让我规定我们可以解决这个问题。
Let me stipulate that we can solve that.
我没有显示代表此树中每个节点的代码。
I have not shown code that represents each of the nodes in this tree.
让我建议，我们甚至可以在下面继续使用箭头。
Let me propose that we could continue having arrows even below.
所以如果我们要把丹尼尔放在这棵树上，
So if we were to have Daniel in this tree,
我们也可以拥有丹妮尔
we could also have Danielle by just having
Daniel下方还有几个节点，并且还有另一个绿色对勾。
a couple of more nodes below Daniel and just having another green checkmark.
因此它在代码中是可解决的，即使它不是
So it is solvable in code, even though it's not
从图形表示中显而易见，但绝对
obvious from the graphical representation, but absolutely
拐角处的情况。
a corner case.
但值得庆幸的是，它可以通过尝试解决。
But thankfully, it is solvable in tries.
但是，另一个缺点是什么呢？
What might another downside be, though, of a trie?
就像，您确实获得1次BigO。
Like, you do get Big O of 1 time.
您可以解决Daniel-Danielle问题。
You can solve the Daniel-Danielle problem.
但是仍然有代价。
But there's still a price being paid.
有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts?
是的。
Yeah.
如果我说对了，那到Ethan怎么样？
How about over to Ethan, if I'm saying it right?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
我是伊桑
I'm Ethan.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：伊桑。
DAVID MALAN: Ethan.
听众：我认为这是因为这只会占用大量内存
AUDIENCE: I think it's because it would just take a lot of memory
容纳所有这些。
to house all of that.
这可能会花费很多时间。
And that could take a lot of time.
这可能会减慢系统速度。
It could slow down the system.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
是的。
Yeah.
您可以单从我的照片中看到它。
You can kind of see it from my picture alone.
我们仅在此数据结构中添加了三个名称。
We only added three names to this data structure.
但是我的上帝，就像有几十个，也许有一百多个指针
But my God, like, there's dozens, maybe 100 plus pointers
如图所示，即使它们都可能为null。
pictured here, even though they might all be null.
正确的？
Right?
如果此处没有箭头表明它们为空，则为0x0，但即使
If the absence of an arrow here suggests that they're null, 0x0, but even
存储空值0x0是8 0位。
storing null, 0x0, is 8 0 bits.
因此，实际的内存使用情况并不缺乏，
So this is not lacking for actual memory usage,
我们只是没有非常有效地使用它。
we're just not using it very efficiently.
我们花费了大量的位或字节，
We have spent a huge number of bits, or bytes,
还是您要测量它。
or however you want to measure it.
因为看起来，即使使用H，我也使用26中的一个指针。
Because look, even with the H's, I'm using one pointer out of 26.
25个指针可能已初始化为null，
25 pointers are probably initialized to null,
这意味着我在浪费25个指针。
which means I'm wasting 25 pointers.
您可以想像您在这棵树中得到的越低，
And you can imagine the lower and lower you get in this tree,
甚至以HAGRID开头的名称的可能性也较小。
the less likely there is to be a name that even starts with H-A-G-R-I-D.
丹尼尔为丹妮尔提出了一个很好的榜样。
Daniel came up with a good example with Danielle.
但这很少发生。
But that's not going to often happen.
当然，您在这棵树中的排名较低。
Certainly, the lower you get in this tree.
因此，正如Ethan所说，您正在浪费大量内存。
So as Ethan says, you're wasting a huge amount of memory.
所以，是的，您的时间不断增加，但天哪，以什么价格？
So yes, you're gaining constant time look ups, but my God, at what price?
您可能正在使用兆字节，千兆字节的存储空间。
You might be using megabytes, gigabytes of storage space.
同样，因为数组最重要的属性
Because, again, the most important property of an array
都是连续的。
is that it's all contiguous.
因此，您具有随机访问权限。
And therefore, you have random access.
但是如果您必须让每个节点都包含
But if you have to have every node containing
大小为26或其他任何值的数组，您
an array of size 26 or anything else, you
必须一遍又一遍地花费内存。
have to spend the memory over and over again.
因此，这也是一个折衷方案。
So there, too, is a trade off.
虽然这在理论上可能是理想的，但理论上
While this might be theoretically ideal, theory
不一定意味着练习。
does not necessarily mean practice.
有时，设计一些效率较低的教科书，
And sometimes, designing something that is textbook less efficient,
在现实世界中可能实际上更有效。
might actually be more efficient in the real world.
在问题集5中，在您自己的拼写检查器中，
And in Problem Set 5, in your own spellchecker,
当您建立这本字典时，我们
when you build up this dictionary that we then
用于对非常大的文本语料进行拼写检查，
use to spell check very large corpuses of text,
您将开始自己体验一些现实世界中的权衡吗？
will you begin to experience some of those real world trade offs yourself.
好吧，我们今天想结束于其他内容
Well, we wanted to end today with a look at what else
您可以使用这类数据结构
you can do with these kinds of data structures,
只是让您了解可以在其他地方使用
just to give you a taste of where else you can go with this
以及您可以解决什么其他类型的问题。
and what other kinds of problems you can solve.
再一次，到目前为止，我们已经研究了数组，这些数组实际上是
Again, thus far, we've looked at arrays, which are really
最简单的数据结构。
the simplest of data structures.
它们本身甚至都不是结构。
And they're not even structures per se.
这只是连续的内存块。
It's just contiguous blocks of memory.
然后，我们引入了链表，当然，
We then introduced linked lists, of course,
你有一个一维数据结构
where you have this one dimensional data structure that
使您可以将节点和内存拼接在一起，从而实现动态分配。
allows you to stitch together nodes and memory, giving you dynamic allocation.
如果要取消分配，可以根据需要插入和删除节点，
And if you want deallocation, inserting and deleting nodes if you want,
然后我们有了树木，这让我们两全其美，
then we had trees, which kind of gives us the best of both worlds,
数组和链表。
arrays and linked lists.
但是我们必须花费更多的空间并使用更多的指针。
But we have to spend more space and use more pointers.
然后，当然，哈希表会合并在一起
Then, of course, hash tables kind of merged together
其中两个想法，数组和链表。
two of those ideas, arrays and the linked lists.
那开始运作良好。
And that starts to work well.
确实，这就是您将使用自己的拼写检查器进行实验的地方。
And indeed, that's what you'll experiment with your own spellchecker.
但是，当然，这里有尝试，乍一看
But then, of course, there's tries, which at first glance
似乎比Ethan更好，但并非没有高昂的代价。
seem better, but not without great cost, as Ethan says.
事实证明，所有这些构建基块都可供您使用，
So it turns out, with all of those building blocks at your disposal,
您实际上可以将它们用作较低级别的实施细节
you can actually use them as lower level implementation details
解决更高层次的问题。
to solve higher level problems.
这就是所谓的抽象数据结构或抽象数据
And this is what are known as abstract data structures, or abstract data
类型。
types.
抽象数据结构是一种心理结构
An abstract data structure is kind of a mental structure
您可以想象，实现一些现实世界中的问题，
that you can imagine, implementing some real world problem,
通常，这是通过其他一些数据结构实现的。
typically, that's implemented with some other data structure.
因此，您有点像在此级别上编写代码。
So you're sort of writing code at this level.
但是您正在考虑最终在此级别上构建的内容。
But you're thinking about what you've built ultimately at this level.
那是抽象，需要较低级别的实现
And that's abstraction, taking lower level implementation
细节，为了讨论或问题而简化它们
details, simplifying them for the sake of discussion or problem
解决更高。
solving higher up.
那么，这样的数据结构是一种什么呢？
So what's one such data structure?
队列是一种非常常见的抽象数据结构。
A queue is a very common abstract data structure.
什么是队列？
What is a queue?
好吧，那些在英国长大的人
Well, those of you who grew up, say, in Britain
在存储区外将一条线称为队列。
call a line outside of a store a queue.
实际上，它就是它得名的地方。
And that's, indeed, where it gets its name.
队列是具有某些属性的数据结构。
A queue is a data structure that has certain properties.
因此，如果您站在商店或餐厅外面，
So if you're standing outside of a store or a restaurant,
在更健康的时期，等待进入的时间通常会排在队列中。
in healthier times, waiting to get in, you're generally in a queue.
但是队列有一个重要的属性。
But there's an important property of a queue.
至少，如果您生活在一个公平的社会中，
At least, if you live in a fair society, you'd
想想如果您是第一个排队的人，
like to think that if you are the first one in line,
您是第一个脱颖而出的人。
you are the first one to get out of line.
先进先出。
First in, first out.
如果您排在第一位，那将有点令人讨厌
It would be kind of obnoxious if you're first in line
然后他们开始让那些在您后面的人进入您的队列。
and then they start letting people in who are behind you in that queue.
因此，如果队列实施正确，
So a queue, if it's implemented correctly,
具有称为先进先出的先进先出属性。
has a property known as FIFO, first in, first out.
我们人类会认为这只是一个公平的财产。
And we humans would think of that as just a fair property.
队列通常至少具有两个与之关联的操作，
And a queue generally has two operations associated with it at least,
入队和出队。
enqueue and dequeue.
这些只是约定。
Those are just conventions.
您可以将其称为添加和删除，或插入，删除任何内容。
You could call it add and remove, or insert, delete, whatever.
但是入队和出队是比较常见的说法。
But enqueue and dequeue are sort of the more common ones to say.
因此排队意味着您可以走到商店
So enqueuing means you walk up to the store
然后排队，因为您必须等待。
and you get in line, because you have to wait.
出队意味着他们已经准备好为您服务或拥有您。
Dequeue means they're ready to serve you or have you.
这样您就脱颖而出了。
And so you get out of line.
那是出队。
That's dequeue.
再说一次，FIFO只是一个花哨的缩写，
And again, FIFO is just a fancy acronym that
描述了它的关键属性，即先进先出。
describes a key property of that, which is that it's first in, first out.
那么，您如何实现队列呢？
So how could you implement a queue then?
好吧，关于该数据结构的有趣之处在于它是抽象的。
Well, what's interesting about that data structure is that it's abstract.
正确的？
Right?
它比代码中的实际更多的是想法。
It's more of an idea than an actual thing in code.
您想实现某种公平的排队系统。
You want to implement some kind of fair queuing system.
因此，您将其视为一个队列。
And so you think of it as a queue.
但坦率地说，如果我们要将该示例转换为代码，
But frankly, if we're going to translate that example to code,
您可以想象使用一系列人员。
you could imagine using an array of persons.
那可以实现一个队列。
That could implement a queue.
您可以使用个人的链接列表。
You could use a linked list of persons.
坦白说，这些方法中的任何一个都将有效。
Frankly, either of those would actually work.
底层是较低层的实现细节。
Underneath the hood is the lower level implementation details.
但是，如果我们翻译这个现实世界，那将会是一个问题
But what would be a problem, if we translate this real world
类比就像在商店外排队进入代码
analogy like queuing up outside of a store to get in, into code
而您使用了数组？
and you used an array?
使用数组的缺点是什么
What would a downside be of using an array
通常来说，代表一个队列，即使我们做出了一些飞跃
to represent a queue, in general, even though we're making a bit of a leap
从现实世界突然变成代码？
from real world to code suddenly?
但是可能还有一个缺点。
But there's probably a downside.
使用数组来实现队列的不利之处是什么，Ryan？
What might a downside be of using an array to implement a queue, Ryan?
听众：如果您使用数组，则不能
AUDIENCE: If you're using an array, you can't really
只是拿出现有的价值。
just take out the existing values.
因为如果您正在考虑这样做，
Because if you were thinking about doing this in a line,
您将必须取出第一个人，取出第二个人。
you would have to take out the first person, take out the second person.
但是之后，您将无法真正动态地更改内存。
But you can't really dynamically sort of change the memory after that.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
是的。
Yeah.
这是一个很好的观点。
That's a really good point.
考虑一条线。
Think about a line.
假设有一条线可以容纳10位苹果商店外的人。
Suppose that there's a line that can fit 10 people outside the Apple store.
因为苹果现在在健康危机中的表现相当不错
Because Apple's pretty good right now during the health crisis of letting
一次只能有很多人。
people in only so many at a time.
因此，假设他们可以容纳10个人，相距六英尺。
So suppose they have room for 10 people, six feet apart.
这实际上是一个非常恰当的比喻，今年比以往任何时候都多。
That's actually a pretty apt analogy, this year more than ever.
但正如瑞安（Ryan）所说，如果您想让某人出队，那么第一个排队的人
But as Ryan says, if you want to dequeue someone, then the first person in line
要去商店。
is going to go into the store.
然后第二个人，您将使他们出队。
And then the second person, you're going to dequeue them.
他们走进商店。
They go into the store.
数组的问题似乎
The problem with an array, it would seem,
就是说，您现在在行首处基本上有空白。
is that now you have essentially empty spaces at the beginning of the line.
但是您仍然没有机会在新朋友的行列中腾出空间。
But you still don't have room at the end of the line for new people.
现在那里有一个显而易见的现实世界解决方案。
Now there's an obvious real world solution there.
您只是说，嘿，大家，您介意向前迈出几步吗？
You just say, hey, everyone, would you mind taking a few steps forward?
但这效率低下。
But that's inefficient.
在人类世界中没有那么多，您必须进入商店。
Not so much in the human world, you've got to get into the store.
但是在代码中，这就是价值的复制。
But in code, that's copying of values.
如果两个人只是，您必须将八个值移动两个位置
You have to move, like, eight values two places over if two people were just
让它进入商店。
let into the store.
因此，现在您的出队操作为n的BigO。
So now your dequeue operation is Big O of n.
这并不十分理想。
And that doesn't feel quite ideal.
如果我们有一点点，我们可以做得更好
And we can do better than that if we're a little
巧妙地使用一些局部变量等。
clever with some local variables and such.
但这将是队列的挑战，
But that would be one challenge of a queue,
当然，这是我们可以使用数组实现的程度。
certainly, is just how well we could implement it using an array.
因此，您可能也想像到数组也是有限的。
So you might imagine, too, an array is limited, too.
因为如果您去Apple Store商店，那会有点令人讨厌。
Because it would kind of be obnoxious if you get to the Apple store.
已经有10个人在排队。
There's already 10 people in line.
而且他们不允许您排队。
And they don't let you get in line.
他们说，对不起，我们今天很忙，而显然他们没有。
They say, sorry, we're all full for today, when they're obviously not.
因为最终队列中会有更多空间。
Because eventually there'll be more room in the queue.
链接列表将使您能够继续添加越来越多的人。
A linked list would allow you to keep appending more and more people.
即使店外的电话线变得疯狂了很长时间，
And even if the line outside the store gets crazy long,
至少链表允许您服务
at least the linked list allows you to service
随着时间的流逝出现的所有客户。
all of the customers who are showing up over time.
固定大小的数组将使处理起来更加困难。
An array of fixed size would make that harder.
同样，您可以分配更大的数组。
And, again, you could allocate a bigger array.
但是然后您将不得不问所有的顾客，嘿，
But then you're going to have to ask all the customers, hey,
大家可以过来吗？
could everyone come over here?
不。
No.
回到那边。
Go back over there.
我的意思是，您正在不断地来回移动人类或价值观和记忆。
I mean, you're constantly moving humans, or values and memory, back and forth.
所以这只是说要实现这个现实世界
So that is only to say that to implement this real world
队列的概念，即使在计算机中也很常用
notion of a queue, which is very commonly used even in the computer
代表某些想法的世界，例如打印机队列，当您
world to represent certain ideas, for instance, the printer queue, when you
向打印机发送一些东西，尤其是在校园或公司中，
send something to the printer, especially on a campus or in a company,
有一个队列。
there's a queue.
理想情况下，第一个人
And ideally, the first person who printed
是第一个获得打印输出的人。
is the first one who gets their printouts thereafter.
队列也用于软件中。
Queues are also used in software.
但是除了队列之外，还有其他抽象数据类型。
But there's other abstract data types out there besides queues.
其中之一称为堆栈。
One of them is called a stack.
因此，堆栈是一种数据结构，它也可以
So a stack is a data structure that can also
可以在内部使用数组或链表实现，或者
be implemented underneath the hood using arrays or linked lists or,
哎呀，也许还有别的。
heck, maybe something else.
但是堆栈具有不同的属性。
But stacks have a different property.
它是后进先出。
It's last in, first out.
后进先出。
Last in, first out.
因此，如果您考虑自助餐厅中的托盘，
So if you think about the trays in the cafeteria,
在更健康的时代，每个人都在校园里使用自助餐厅的托盘，
in healthier times when everyone was on campus using trays from a cafeteria,
您当然会记得，托盘通常会像这样堆叠。
you'll recall, of course, that trays tend to get stacked like this.
最后一个放在纸叠顶部的纸盘是第一个出来的纸盘。
And the last tray to go on top of the stack is the first one to come out.
如果你去服装店，你自己的壁橱，
If you go to a clothing store, your own closet,
如果您不将东西挂在衣架上或放在抽屉里，
if you don't hang things on hangers or put them in drawers,
但是有点像在这里像所有这些毛衣一样堆放它们，
but kind of stack them, like here, like all of these sweaters,
这是一堆毛衣。
this is a stack of sweaters.
我该如何获得一件想要的毛衣？
And how do I get at a sweater I want?
好吧，最简单的方法是先入先出。
Well, the easiest way to do it is with last in, first out.
所以我不断拿黑色毛衣，黑色毛衣。
So I constantly take the black sweater, the black sweater.
但是，如果我将所有毛衣都存储在此堆栈中，
But if I've stored all of my sweaters in this stack,
您可能永远也不会接触到较低级别的产品，
you may never get to the sort of lower level ones,
就像红色或蓝色的毛衣一样，这又是因为这种数据结构。
like the red or the blue sweater because, again, of this data structure.
所以后进先出实际上是财产
So LIFO, last in, first out, is in fact, the property
用于表征堆栈。
used to characterize stacks.
根据实际环境，堆栈是有用的还是无效的。
And stacks are useful or not useful, depending on the real world context.
但是，即使在计算领域，随着时间的流逝，我们也会看到应用程序
But even within computing, we'll see applications over time
堆栈确实发挥作用的地方。
where stacks indeed come into play.
这些东西支持的那两个操作通常称为
And those two operations that those things support are generally called
推和弹出。
push and pop.
与添加或删除或插入或删除相同，但是使用条款
It's the same thing as add or remove or insert or delete, but the terms of art
通常是推入和弹出，这是我从堆栈中弹出一个值。
are generally push and pop, where this is me popping a value off of the stack.
这是我将一个值压入堆栈。
This is me pushing a value onto the stack.
但是，它又是后进先出，也就是后进先出。
But, again, it's last in, first out, otherwise known as LIFO.
还有另一种数据结构
And then there's this other data structure
实际上有一个非常真实的类比，称为字典。
that actually has a very real world analog, known as a dictionary.
字典是一种抽象的数据类型，
A dictionary is an abstract data type, which
意味着您可以使用数组，链接列表或哈希表来实现它，
means you can implement it with arrays, or linked lists, or hash tables,
或尝试，或任何其他方式，抽象数据类型
or tries, or whatever else, an abstract data type
使您可以将键与值相关联。
that allows you to associate keys with values.
最好的模拟确实是在现实世界中。
And the best analog here is indeed in the real world.
什么是字典，就像旧式字典一样
What is a dictionary, like an old school dictionary
那实际上是以书本形式印在纸上的？
that's actually printed on paper in book form?
那本书里面有什么？
What is inside that book?
一堆钥匙，一堆黑体字，例如苹果和香蕉
A whole bunch of keys, a whole bunch of boldfaced words, like apple and banana
等等，每个都有定义，也称为值。
and so forth, each of which have definitions, otherwise known as values.
而且通常将它们按字母顺序排列以使其更容易
And they're often alphabetized to make it easier
为您找到事物，以便您可以更快地查找事物。
for you to find things so that you can look things up more quickly.
但是字典是将键与值相关联的抽象数据类型。
But a dictionary is an abstract data type that associates keys with values.
然后，您可以通过它们的键来查找值，
And you look up the values by way of their keys,
就像您通过单词本身查询单词的定义一样。
just like you look up a word's definition by way of the word itself.
词典实际上也属于我们所有人。
And dictionaries are actually kind of all around us, too.
您可能不会在这些方面考虑它们。
You don't think of them in these terms, probably.
但是，如果您去过例如New Haven的Sweet Green，
But if you've ever been to Sweet Green, for instance, in New Haven
或在剑桥或其他地方，这是一个沙拉的地方
or in Cambridge or elsewhere, this is a salad place
尤其是在如今的地方，您可以在线或通过应用程序提前订购
where nowadays, especially, you can order in advance online or on an app
然后进入商店，从架子上拿起食物。
and then go into the store and pick up your food from a shelf.
但是架子，他们在剑桥和其他城市在这里做的方式，
But the shelf, the way they do it here in Cambridge and in other cities,
他们实际上在架子上有字母A，B，C，D，E，
is they actually have letters of the alphabet on the shelves, A, B, C, D, E,
F，一直到Z。想法是，如果我进去拿沙拉，
F, all the way through Z. The idea being that if I go in to pick up my salad,
如果布莱恩进去接他，那可能是在D部分
it's probably on the D section, if Brian goes in to pick up his,
在B部分，依此类推。
it's in the B section, and so forth.
现在在这里，您也可以想象异常的拐角案例
Now here, too, you can imagine perverse corner cases
这个数据结构在哪里，这个字典在哪里
where this data structure, this dictionary whereby
字母映射到值，即人们的沙拉，
letters of the alphabet map to values, which are people's salad,
不一定是失败的证明。
is not necessarily fail proof.
你能想到一个反常的情况吗
Can you think of a perverse corner case where
Sweet Green的极好的，系统的系统实际上崩溃了吗？
Sweet Green's very wonderful, methodical system actually breaks down?
即使您从未去过Sweet Green，您能想到这里的限制吗？
Can you think of a limitation here, even if you've never been to Sweet Green
或从未吃过沙拉，这个系统可能会分解
or never eaten a salad, what could break down with this system
是否要去商店根据您的名字取东西？
if going into a store and picking something up based on your name?
有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts?
布莱恩：有人说可能有问题
BRIAN: A few people say there might be a problem
如果两个人的名字相同。
if two people have the same name.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
如果两个人的名字相同，那么您就开始堆叠东西。
If two people have the same names, you start to stack things up.
因此，从字面上看，Sweet Green将开始在另一种沙拉上堆叠另一种沙拉。
So literally, Sweet Green will start stacking one salad on top of the other.
所以实际上有一个有趣的化身
So there is actually an interesting incarnation
一种数据类型构建在另一种数据类型之上。
of one data type being built on top of yet another data type.
因此，所有这些都有点像自定义的Scratch作品，如果您愿意的话，
So, again, all of these are sort of like custom Scratch pieces, if you will,
我们不断地重组到更多
that we're constantly sort of reassembling into more
有趣而有力的想法。
interesting and powerful ideas.
但是在某个时候，如果有很多B名或D名，
But at some point, if there's a lot of B names, or D names,
或任何字母，我肯定会在这个架子上看到一个有限的高度。
or any letter of the alphabet, I surely see a finite height to this shelf.
因此，就好像Sweet Green已实施了他们的字典
So it's kind of as though Sweet Green has implemented their dictionary
使用带有数组的堆栈。
using stacks with arrays.
因为数组是固定大小的。
Because arrays are fixed size.
因此，垂直方向肯定只有这么多英寸的空间。
So there's surely only so many inches of space here vertically.
因此，您可以看到现实世界中的限制。
So you can see a real world limitation.
那么，如果发生这种情况，Sweet Green会做什么？
So what does Sweet Green do if that happens?
他们可能只是作弊，将D放在C部分，
They probably just kind of cheat and put the D's in the C section,
或E部分中的D。
or the D's in the E section.
像，谁真的在乎现实世界？
Like, who really cares in the real world?
您的眼睛可能左右左右掠过。
Your eyes are probably going to skim left and right.
但是从算法上讲，这会使事情变慢。
But algorithmically, that is slowing things down.
在最坏的情况下，如果您真的迟到拿起沙拉，
And in the worst case, if you're really late to pick up your salad,
或者，如果Sweet Green真的很受欢迎，并且有
or if Sweet Green is really popular and there's
架子上有很多沙拉，你的名字叫阿不思，
a huge number of salads on the shelf, your name might be Albus,
但是您的沙拉可能会在Z部分结束
but your salad might end up way over here in the Z section
如果他们刚好不在房间里。
if they're just out of room.
因此，这也是有效的算法决策，
And so that, too, is a valid algorithmic decision,
在其他地方腾出空间。
to just make room somewhere else.
但是，同样，在时间和空间之间进行权衡。
But, again, trade offs between time and space.
因此，由于我们的一些朋友，我们认为我们将以一个音符结尾
And so we thought we'd end on a note, thanks to some friends of ours
在另一个机构进行了出色的可视化
at another institution who made a wonderful visualization that
区分了堆栈和队列的这些概念。
distinguished these notions of stacks versus queues.
这些抽象数据类型（包括堆栈和队列）
Stack and, again, a queue are these abstract data types that
可以以不同的方式实现。
can be implemented in different ways.
它们具有不同的属性，每个属性分别为FIFO或LIFO。
They have different properties, each of them respectively FIFO or LIFO.
例如，这是我们最后时刻的最后一眼
And here, for instance, is a final look in our final moments
今天在这里一起讨论这些想法如何体现出来，也许
together here today about how these ideas manifest themselves, perhaps
在现实世界中，与这里的这堆毛衣没什么两样。
in the real world, not unlike this stack of sweaters here.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
-从前，有个叫杰克的家伙。
- Once upon a time, there was a guy named Jack.
当结交朋友时，杰克没有诀窍。
When it came to making friends, Jack did not have the knack.
于是杰克去和他认识的最受欢迎的人交谈。
So Jack went to talk to the most popular guy he knew.
他走到楼，问：“我该怎么办？”
He went up to Lou and asked, "What do I do?"
楼看到他的朋友真的很沮丧。
Lou saw that his friend was really distressed.
“好吧，”娄开始道，“只要看看你的衣着如何。
"Well," Lou began, "just look how you're dressed.
难道你没有别样的衣服吗？”
Don't you have any clothes with a different look?"
“是的。”杰克说。
"Yes," said Jack.
“我肯定会的。
"I sure do.
到我家来，我给你看。”
Come to my house, and I'll show them to you."
所以他们去了杰克的。
So they went off to Jack's.
杰克把盒子放到娄的盒子里。
And Jack showed Lou the box where he kept all his shirts
还有他的裤子和袜子。
and his pants and his socks.
楼说：“我看你一堆衣服都放了。
Lou said, "I see you have all your clothes in a pile.
您为什么不偶尔穿一些其他衣服？”
Why don't you wear some others once in a While?"
杰克说：“好吧，当我脱下衣服和袜子时，
Jack said, "Well, when I remove clothes and socks,
我洗净并将它们放在盒子里。
I wash them and put them away in the box.
然后第二天早晨来了，我跳了起来。
Then comes the next morning, and up I hop.
我去箱子把衣服脱掉。”
I go to the box and get my clothes off the top."
娄很快意识到杰克的问题。
Lou quickly realized the problem with Jack.
他把衣服，CDS和书堆放在一堆中。
He kept clothes, CDS, and books in the stack.
当他伸手去读书或穿衣服时，
When he reached for something to read or to wear,
他选择了高级书籍或内衣。
he chose top book or underwear.
然后，当他完成后，他会把它放回原处。
Then, when he was done, he would put it right back.
它将返回，位于堆栈的顶部。
Back it would go, on top of the stack.
“我知道解决方法！”娄凯旋说。
"I know the solution!" said a triumphant Lou.
“您需要学习开始使用队列。”
"You need to learn to start using a queue."
娄拿起杰克的衣服，把它们挂在壁橱里。
Lou took Jack's clothes and hung them in a closet.
当他清空箱子时，他就把它扔了。
And when he had emptied the box, he just tossed it.
然后他说：“现在，杰克，在一天结束时，把衣服放在左边
Then he said, "Now, Jack, at the end of the day, put your clothes on the left
当你把它们收起来的时候
when you put them away.
然后明天早晨看到阳光时，
Then tomorrow morning when you see the sunshine, get
您的衣服从右边开始，从行尾开始。
your clothes from the right, from the end of the line.
你看不到吗？”楼说，“那太好了。
Don't you see?" said Lou, "it will be so nice.
在穿两次之前，你会穿一次。”
You'll wear everything once before you wear something twice."
一切都在他的壁橱和架子上，
And with everything in queues in his closet and shelf,
杰克开始对自己很确定，谢谢
Jack started to feel quite sure of himself, all thanks
到娄和他美妙的队列。
to Lou and his wonderful queue.
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
CS50就是这样。
That's it for CS50.
下次见。
We will see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]